<Table>
<Row><Cell>dlc0_bruncvik_s0100</Cell><Cell>Set out on the trail of the legend of Prince Brunswick, who won the heraldic lion for Bohemia. With the help of a series of clues, embark on a journey across the Trosky Region to track down Brunswick's armour. But beware! Only a true knight is worthy of it.</Cell><Cell>布伦瑞克王子为波希米亚赢得了雄狮纹章，而你将重新踏上他的传奇之路。在一系列线索的指引下，穿越特罗斯基地区，探寻布伦瑞克的盔甲。要当心！只有真正的骑士才能配上这副盔甲！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dlc0_bruncvik_s0500</Cell><Cell>&lt;strong&gt;Forging instructions for Brunswick's poleaxe&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;strong&gt;布伦瑞克长柄斧的锻造方法&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dlc0_bruncvik_s0700</Cell><Cell>&lt;strong&gt;Brunswick's caparison bearing the crest of Bohemia&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;strong&gt;带有波希米亚纹章的布伦瑞克马衣&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dlc0_bruncvik_s0800</Cell><Cell>&lt;strong&gt;Brunswick's knightly armour set, including leg plates, brigandine, plate sleeves, gauntlets, chainmail coif and bascinet&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;strong&gt;布伦瑞克的全套骑士盔甲，包括板甲护腿、板甲衣、板甲臂铠、护手、链甲头巾和桶盔。&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_cant_save_potion</Cell><Cell>You have no Saviour Schnapps!</Cell><Cell>你没有救世烈酒！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_castles</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Early Gothic buildings in Bohemia were inspired by France and the Rhineland. Among the earliest were the monastery in Předklášteří near Tišnov, South Moravia, the chapter house in Osek, North Bohemia, the monastery of St Agnes in Prague and many parish churches and monasteries such as those in Kolin and Kouřim in Central Bohemia.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;At the turn of the 13th and 14th centuries, Czech architecture diverged from its western counterparts. There was a burgeoning of Cistercian monasteries, e.g. in Zlatá Koruna and Vyšší Brod in South Bohemia, and churches and castles, e.g. Bezděz, North Bohemia. The &lt;accent&gt;High Gothic&lt;/accent&gt; period was ushered in during the time of Charles IV and Wenceslas IV, with its rectangular windows and portals, rayonnant traceries and quadripartite, sexpartite, or cross-ribbed vaulting.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The most significant buildings of that time include Charles University, St Vitus Cathedral, Charles Bridge, Prague Old Town Hall and New Town Hall, stone houses in Prague and the castles of Karlštejn, Kost and Kašperk.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Records of construction work fellowships first appear during this time: the most famous are those of Master Peter Parler and his family, and Matthias of Arras, who also worked on the reconstruction of Sasau Monastery.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;New castles no longer served just a defensive function, but were also intended to serve as royal residences. They were therefore more spacious and elaborate and had extensive gardens.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;波希米亚早期的哥特式建筑的灵感来源于法国和莱茵兰。其中最早的建筑，是南摩拉维亚的提什诺夫（Tišnov）附近的普莱德克拉斯特里（Předklášteří）修道院、北波希米亚的奥赛克的牧师会礼堂、布拉格的圣阿格尼丝修道院，以及很多位于中波希米亚的教区教堂和修道院，例如那些的科林和库日姆（Kouřim）等地的建筑。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;在13世纪至14世纪之交，捷克的建筑风格开始与西方分野。在南波希米亚的泽拉塔克鲁纳（Zlatá Koruna）和维希布罗德（Vyšší Brod）等地区，熙笃会修道院如雨后春笋般崛起，北波希米亚的贝兹德兹（Bezděz）等地区的教堂和城堡亦是如此。查理四世和瓦茨拉夫四世在位期间迎来&lt;accent&gt;哥特盛期&lt;/accent&gt;，该时期典型建筑设有矩形的窗户和立面、辐射式的窗花格，以及四分、六分或交叉式的拱顶。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;此时期极具意义的建筑有查理大学、圣维特大教堂、查理大桥、布拉格老市政厅和新市政厅及其他石质建筑、卡尔施泰因城堡（Karlštejn）、科斯特城堡（Kost）、卡斯佩克城堡（Kašperk）等。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;关于建筑工团体的最早记录中，最著名的是彼得·帕勒大师及其家族，还有阿拉斯的马蒂亚斯，后者也曾参与过莎邵修道院的重建工作。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;新城堡不仅被用作防御工事，还是皇室居所，因此被修建得更加宽敞和精美，还配有大型花园。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_cesky_raj</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;An area, also known as &lt;accent&gt;Bohemian Paradise&lt;/accent&gt;, about 90 km north-east of Prague with a great number of natural and cultural monuments. The main landmarks of the region are Kozákov Mountain and &lt;accent&gt;Trosky Castle&lt;/accent&gt;, while other important sites include, for example, the Prachov and Klokoči rock formations, the castles Kost, Waldstein and Sychrov, and a number of ponds.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Its picturesque landscape is mainly underscored by the ubiquitous sandstone rocks, characterised by their steep and rugged reliefs and towers.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;It is an important protected landscape area and a popular destination for climbers. Nowadays the area is crisscrossed with a dense network of tourist trails, making it a haven for nature lovers and enthusiasts of historical landmarks.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In the medieval period the region was quite bustling, particularly due to the numerous castles, fortresses and fortifications, which are located almost literally on every hilltop.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;位于布拉格东北约90公里的地方，有一个被称为&lt;accent&gt;波希米亚伊甸园&lt;/accent&gt;的地区，那里拥有大量自然和文化古迹。该地区的主要地标就有科扎科夫山（Kozákov Mountain）和&lt;accent&gt;特罗斯基城堡&lt;/accent&gt;，其他著名景点还包括普拉霍夫和克洛科奇岩石群（Prachov and Klokoči rock formations）、科斯特城堡、瓦尔德斯坦城堡、西赫罗夫城堡以及多处池塘。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;那里风景如画，砂岩随处可见，以其崎岖、峻峭、塔状林立为特色。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;这里是一处重要的景观保护区，也吸引着大批攀岩爱好者。如今，这处自然和古迹爱好者的天堂，纵横交织着密集的游览线路。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;中世纪时期，这片地区格外繁华，尤其是数不胜数的城堡、堡垒以及防御工事，几乎每座山丘上都能看到它们耸立的身影。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_fashion</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Clothing for villagers and common folk had to be comfortable, durable and practical. It consisted of a simple shirt and a tunic. Men also wore &lt;italic&gt;braies&lt;/italic&gt; (knee-length linen drawers). In winter they wore hooded cloaks, furs and hats. All typically in natural colours without embellishments. The exception was &lt;accent&gt;festive attire&lt;/accent&gt; for special occasions and religious holidays.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In the city, clothing reflected status, wealth, but also affiliation to a particular group, such as craftsmen, soldiers or apprentices. Belts, bags, gloves, hats and other headgear were used as accessories.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;Hairstyles&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;accent&gt;Unwed young women&lt;/accent&gt; had long hair, which they wore down or in braids. Women in towns adorned their hair with ribbons, pearls, wreaths and vines. Older &lt;accent&gt;married women&lt;/accent&gt; wore pearled nets on their heads, white or coloured veils or hats. Fashionable &lt;accent&gt;men&lt;/accent&gt; had long, coiffured hair, they liked to shave their chins and wear various headwear.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;Jewellery&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Jewellery was fashioned from gems, wood, leather and metals. The most common types of jewellery were &lt;accent&gt;earrings&lt;/accent&gt;, various types of crosses and, in the High Middle Ages, &lt;accent&gt;rings&lt;/accent&gt;, which were both representative and symbolic. Floral and animal themes as well as figural motifs inspired by religious themes predominated in decoration.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;Footwear&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Shoes were made of leather, but also of grass, straw, bast, wood, cloth or felt. In the countryside, people often went barefoot in summertime. &lt;accent&gt;Soles&lt;/accent&gt; (left and right) on shoes first appeared in the mid 14th century while heels were added in the 15th century.The most common type of footwear consisted of sandals and slippers made of wood or cork. Stitched shoes were called either &lt;italic&gt;škrpály&lt;/italic&gt; (low shoes) or &lt;italic&gt;škorně&lt;/italic&gt; (above the ankle).&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;对村民和其他平民来说，服装最首要的是舒适、结实和实用，通常多是些简单的衬衫和短袍。男人也会穿着及膝的&lt;italic&gt;亚麻裤&lt;/italic&gt;，冬天时还会穿兜帽斗篷、皮外套和帽子。大部分服装都是自然朴素的颜色，没有装饰。为了宗教假日和特殊庆祝场合准备的&lt;accent&gt;节庆服装&lt;/accent&gt;则是例外。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;在镇上，服装能够反映穿着者的社会地位、财富状况，当然还反映了特有的身份，例如工匠、士兵或学徒。配饰包含腰带、袋子、手套、帽子和其他头罩等。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;发型&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;accent&gt;未婚女子&lt;/accent&gt;留披肩长发或是编成辫子。镇上的女人会用丝带、珍珠、花环和藤蔓装饰头发。年长的&lt;accent&gt;已婚女子&lt;/accent&gt;会在头上戴珍珠网，白色或彩色的面纱，或者帽子。时髦的&lt;accent&gt;男人&lt;/accent&gt;会留长发并做成发型，他们还会剃须，穿戴各式各样的头饰。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;珠宝&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;珠宝首饰由宝石、木头、皮革和金属制成。最常见的首饰为&lt;accent&gt;耳环&lt;/accent&gt;、各种各样的十字架，以及在中世纪兴盛时期流行的&lt;accent&gt;戒指&lt;/accent&gt;，当时的戒指既可以代表身份，又具有象征意义。首饰上的装饰图案主要是花朵和动物，以及受宗教主题启发的人物形象。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;鞋子&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;当时的鞋子由皮革制成，也有些用青草、稻草、树皮、木头、布或者毛毡制成。每到夏天，乡下人经常光脚出行。区分左右脚的&lt;accent&gt;鞋底&lt;/accent&gt;首次出现于14世纪中期，而鞋跟则出现于15世纪时。最常见的鞋子有木质或软木的凉鞋和拖鞋。缝制的鞋子包括&lt;italic&gt;škrpály&lt;/italic&gt;（低帮）和&lt;italic&gt;škorně&lt;/italic&gt;（高帮）两种。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_gunpowder</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Black powder is the oldest known explosive, discovered around the 9th century in China. Initially, it was used in medicine and widely experimented with by alchemists. However, when it failed to yield the anticipated elixir of immortality, its powerful explosive properties began to be used for ammunition production. It likely arrived in Europe as early as the 13th century, although some experts believe that Europeans discovered black powder independently of China.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The European inventor of gunpowder is typically attributed to either the German alchemist Berthold "The Black" Schwarz, or, according to other sources, the German friar Albertus Magnus, who was familiar with the recipe for gunpowder as early as 1275. Another mention can be found in the work of the alchemist Marcus Graecus, who included a black powder recipe in his writings around 1300. However, at this time, gunpowder was not yet commonly used in combat.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Originally, a fine particle mixture known as “meal powder,” produced by grinding the individual components, was used for shooting. Later, methods were developed to produce larger grains, which significantly improved the consistency of ballistic properties and accuracy in shooting.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;黑火药是目前已知最古老的炸药，大约在9世纪由中国人发明。黑火药最初被用于医疗领域，且广泛地用于炼丹师的实验当中。显然，黑火药并没能如同预期般地成为长生不老药，但那之后人们利用它的爆炸特性将其用于弹药生产中。黑火药可能早在13世纪便已传入欧洲，也有一些专家声称欧洲人是独立发现黑火药的。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;欧洲火药的发明者通常被认为是德国炼金术士贝索德·施瓦茨。也有一些其他的说法，比如德国修士阿尔伯特·麦格努斯，据说他早在1275年就掌握了火药配方。也有关于炼金术师马库斯·格拉厄库斯的记载，他在大约1300年的著作之中收录了一份黑火药的配方。不过，在那段时间，火药还并未广泛用于战争之中。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;最初人们使用的火药是一种研磨而成的，称为“粉末火药”的细颗粒混合物，通常用于射击。之后人们研发出了生产较大颗粒火药的方法，大大提高了其弹道性能、射击精度和稳定性。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_jan_sokol</Cell><Cell>&lt;years&gt;cca. 1355 – 28 September 1410&lt;/years&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Jan Sokol of Lamberg was a military leader, provincial governor, son of Jaroslav of Kninice, and a friend of Radzig Kobyla.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;He actively participated in the internal disputes of the Luxembourg dynasty, siding with Wenceslas IV. For his loyalty, the king rewarded him with the village of Horky and the castle of Skalitz near Kostelec in Bohemia.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In 1404, Jan fought against Sigismund of Luxembourg at Znojmo. As a member of Wenceslas's retinue, he met Jan Zizka in 1409 and went into battle against the Rosenbergs with him. He fought in the Battle of Grunwald, where he sided with the Polish-Lithuanian coalition. After the battle, he was likely poisoned at a feast at the court of Polish King Władysław Jagiełło.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;years&gt;约1355年 – 1410年9月28日&lt;/years&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;兰伯格的约翰·索科尔，是金尼斯的雅罗斯洛夫之子， 拉德季·科比拉之友，也是摩拉维亚的督军。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;他是卢森堡王朝内乱中的关键人物，也是支持瓦茨拉夫的一员。得救后的国王为表彰其忠诚，当即将波希米亚境内的霍基村，以及科思泰莱茨附近的斯卡利茨城堡赏给了索科尔。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;1404年，扬与卢森堡的西格斯蒙德在兹诺伊莫交战。作为瓦茨拉夫的盟友，他于1409年联合扬·杰式卡抗击罗森堡。他加入波兰与立陶宛联军，参加了格伦瓦尔德战役。战役之后，波兰国王弗拉迪斯拉夫·雅盖隆，疑似在一场宴会上对约翰下了毒。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_loupeze</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Thievery and banditry were 'dishonourable professions', whose practitioners were often known in the wider area - that is, if they could evade justice long enough.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Petty theft most often happened in villages, town markets or taverns. In short, where thieves could hide in the crowd. But people were in greater danger in the open countryside, outside their settlements, or in remote villages, where victims could rarely call for help. Bandits therefore often threatened merchants and travellers on the road, especially around the richer towns, where they flocked to do business.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Some &lt;accent&gt;bands of robbers&lt;/accent&gt; were organised and operated under the auspices of rebelious nobles who profited from their actions. At times they even resorted to raiding entire villages or towns. They would then sell off their loot in markets or taverns.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The execution books give us evidence of the fate of those, who became involved with bandits. In one of them, we read about Jan Zizka, that: &lt;italic&gt;'He steals herrings and killed a hired hand of the Rosenberg's.'&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;偷盗是一种“不光彩”的职业，精通此道的人也会臭名远扬——如果他们还未落入法网的话。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;偷盗常发生在村中、市场或是酒馆内，简单地说，人群中可能随时藏着小偷。但是，在旷野荒山或是偏远村庄这种人烟罕至的地方，人们可能所面临的境况更为险恶。这种地方的强盗们常常会胁迫路过的商人或旅客，在繁华且有活跃市场的城镇周边这种现象尤为突出。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;一些&lt;accent&gt;强盗团伙&lt;/accent&gt;接受着反叛贵族们的资助，并在他们的组织与运作下，通过恶行为他们谋利。有时候，他们还会洗劫整座村庄或城镇，事后再到市场或酒馆内进行销赃。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;与处决有关的记录向我们揭露了那些与强盗有染之人的命运，在其中，我们还读到了与扬·杰式卡有关的信息：&lt;italic&gt;“他偷走鲱鱼，并杀死了罗森堡的一位雇工。”&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_opatovice</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;As the name suggests, the village probably owes its foundation to the abbots (opati) of the nearby Sedletz Monastery, who from the 13th century tried to colonise this inhospitable and sparsely populated region. The first written mention of the village dates back to the latter half of the 14th century, when it belonged to the Kuttenberg burgher Jan Glenc.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The farmstead of Opatowitz was founded sometime during the 14th century by the monastery, which subsequently supported it until it was sold to another wealthy Kuttenberg burgher, Wenceslas Bartosch (Václav Bartoš), in 1379.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;正如其名所示，这座村庄的建立或许得归功于附近塞德莱茨修道院的院长们（opati），自13世纪以来，他们曾试图在这荒无人烟的不毛之地上殖民。该村庄首次于书中有所提及可追溯至14世纪下半叶，当时它属于名为扬·格伦茨的库滕堡市民。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;14世纪期间，修道院还建造了奥帕托维茨农庄，并对其经营发展施以支持，一直到农庄于1379年专卖给了一位富有的库滕堡市民，此人名叫瓦茨拉夫·巴托什（Václav Bartoš）。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_polsko</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;In Poland at the turn of the 14th and 15th centuries, similar to the Czech lands, wars over governance, territory, and faith were occurring. The country's prosperity and its cultural and economic growth were particularly hampered by the relentless attacks of the Teutonic Knights from the so-called Crusader states on northern Polish territories, justified by the need for Christianization and the suppression of the still dominant paganism in the Baltic region.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Unfortunately, Poland was not unified for long, because after the death of Casimir III the Great, the Piast dynasty, which had long unified and ruled the country, ended in the male line. The crown was taken by Casimir's cousin, Ludwig I of Anjou, the King of Hungary, but he struggled to gain the obedience of the Polish nobility, and his rule and ability to unite a larger coalition against the Crusader invasion were thus very limited.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The most suitable solution eventually was the marriage of Ludwig's daughter Hedwig to Jagell, the Grand Duke of Lithuania. He took the name Vladislav, was accepted as the King of Poland, and, along with the rest of Lithuania, was baptized. This created the Polish-Lithuanian coalition, which significantly weakened the Teutonic Order.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;However, the Crusaders did not want to give up so easily, and the war continued for many more years. A turning point in this conflict was the Battle of Grunwald in 1410, in which the Teutonic forces were decisively defeated by the Polish-Lithuanian army. Many Czech fighters fought on the side of the Poles at that time, including Jan Zizka and Jan Sokol of Lamberg.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;在14至15世纪之交的波兰领土上，与捷克大陆类似，人们为了争夺控制权、领土和信仰而四处引发战火。尤其是波兰北部受到所谓的十字军国家派出的条顿骑士团的不断侵扰，战争冲突阻碍了该国的繁荣以及文化和经济的发展。这些战争被认为是为了对当地进行基督教化，扼杀波罗的海地区主流的异教信仰。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;遗憾的是，波兰未能保持长久的统一。卡西米尔三世驾崩以后，统治多年的一统王朝皮亚斯特于战争中覆灭。后来，卡西米尔的堂兄、匈牙利国王安茹·路易一世登基，但波兰贵族却不愿向其俯首称臣，因此他在统筹联军抵抗十字军侵略的过程中备受阻碍。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;最好的解决办法就是让路易的女儿海德薇与立陶宛大公雅盖沃联姻。雅盖沃后取名弗拉迪斯拉夫，登上波兰王位，与立陶宛众人一同受洗，波兰-立陶宛联盟因此结成，进而削弱了条顿骑士团的影响力。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;然而，十字军并不会轻易投降，战争也因此持续多年。战争的转折点是发生于1410年的格伦瓦尔德战役，波兰-立陶宛联军在这场战役中迎头击败了十字军。当时许多捷克战士也为波兰出战，其中就包括扬·杰式卡和扬·索科尔。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_ratbor_tvrz</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;The first written mention of Raborsch appears in 1362. At that time, the adjacent village belonged to Mikuláš Velkuš, a townsman from Kuttenberg, who sold it to Mikuláš Wonderbute between 1386-1389.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The rapid change of owners is characteristic of the fortress, even to this day: after his death it passed to King Wenceslas IV, from whom it was acquired by another Kuttenberg burgher, Martin Oderin.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In 1402, the fortress and the village were burnt down by King Sigismund of Hungary during the siege of Kuttenberg. The remains of the fortress continued to change hands during the 15th century until they came under the administration of King George of Podiebrad and from there to the captain of Kolin, Jan Hrabaň, at Přerubnice. The list of subsequent owners is extensive.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Today the fortress (rebuilt into a castle) is privately owned. Only part of the masonry of the south-east corner and one room with a ribbed vaulting have been preserved from the original Gothic building.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;与拉博施有关的记录首次出现于1362年。当时，附近的村庄属于库滕堡市民米库拉什·韦尔库什（Mikuláš Velkuš），后在1386年至1389年期间，他将村庄卖给了米库拉什·温德布特（Mikuláš Wonderbute）。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;频繁易主贯穿着这座堡垒的一生，即便时至今日仍然如此：温德布特死后，堡垒便由瓦茨拉夫四世国王接管，而后又一位库滕堡市民，马丁·奥德林，从国王手中取得了这座城堡。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;1402年，在库滕堡遭受袭击期间，匈牙利国王西格斯蒙德将村庄焚毁殆尽。村庄的残余部分在15世纪时期再次易主，直至波杰布拉迪的乔治国王将其收至麾下进行管辖，而后又交给了治理普热鲁布尼采（Přerubnice）的科林长官扬·赫拉班（Jan Hrabaň）。后续该堡垒的持有者仍不断更换。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;如今，这座堡垒（已被改建成一座城堡）归私人所有。该建筑仅有东南角的一部分砖墙和一间带有肋拱的房间仍保持着原有的哥特式风格。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_semin</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Semín (Semine) is a small village lying to the west of Troskowitz. In earlier times, it included a fortress that no longer exists today, which, according to surviving records, belonged to Jan and Oldřich of Semín in the year 1365. These two brothers, and later their children, owned the fortress until 1416, but did not reside there much because they chose other places for their seats. In 1375, Oldřich’s son Jan therefore assumed administration of Semín, and after him it passed to his sons Petr and Přibík.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Whether these Semín men were ancestors or relatives of the Semín of Semín line – an old Bohemian minor noble family – unfortunately can no longer be definitively proven or disproven. So far, the only discovery is that the first to bear that name was Jakub the Younger Semín of Semín, as late as 1422.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Even so, we decided to present the owner of the Semín fortress in our game as a representative example of impoverished nobility dwelling in pleasant countryside.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;As for the place where the fortress is situated, the terrain bordered by steep rocky slopes, lakes, marshes and fishponds became an ideal settlement area as early as the middle of the first century BC. Remains of massive ramparts can be found here, the most prominent part being a ten-metre-high frontal rampart with a moat, which archaeological research indicates was built by the Celts.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In Kingdom Come: Deliverance 2, one also finds the Semín mill, which belonged to the lords of Semín for centuries, and it remains an important part of the picturesque landscape to this day.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;这座村庄于1339年首次在文献中被提及，当时它还由塞米的赫尔曼（Heřman）统治。然而，从古墓遗址以及古凯尔特城堡城墙的发现表明，村庄附近的定居迹象可追溯至公元前一千年中叶。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;1379年，塞米的米库拉什·塔特卡（Mikuláš Tatka）统治着塞米堡垒，还赞助着当地的教堂。其他堡垒所有者包括塞米的扬·西罗泰克（Jan Sirotek）和斯拉特金的安娜，后来则是安娜的儿子，斯拉蒂纳的扬接管。胡斯战争之后，哈尼凯尔（Hanykéř）家族成为了堡垒的所有者，但很可能在那时，因为战争的缘故，堡垒早已遭到掠夺并且最终空无一人。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;如今，该遗址上只有几座农舍，以及一座按照堡垒原型打造的城堡，该城堡也作为展览馆和画廊使用。时至今日，该地区仍然有大量的城墙遗迹，且建于16世纪上半叶的下塞米磨坊也保存至今。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_stribskalice</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;The area where Skalitz (Skalice), the birthplace of our hero Henry, is situated today, was probably settled in the 13th century. The development of the town was prompted by silver mining in the area as well as the existence of the nearby parish of Rovná.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The owners of the castle included Ješek of Skalitz (from 1384) and Bohdal of Drahonice (1402-1403). In 1403, Wenceslas IV took possession of it and placed it under the governance of the knight Sir Radzig Kobyla. However, in the same year, he had to leave the castle in order to save the inhabitants of Skalitz from Sigismund's army, who torched the castle and the adjoining village; the estate was never rebuilt.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In December of 1403, Wenceslas IV granted the remains of the village to Jan Sokol of Lamberg. The ruins of the medieval castle and its fortifications was scavenged for building material for the Church of St. John of Nepomuk. Today, only a small part of the masonry of the gate, the bailey and the walls remain.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;斯卡里茨，即亨利的家乡，可能在13世纪便有人在此定居。银矿业和附近罗维那（Rovná）教区推动了该地区的城镇发展。 &lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;城堡的故主包括斯卡里茨的耶舍克（自1384年起）和达荷尼采的波达尔（1402 - 1403）。瓦茨拉夫四世于1403年将其接管，并交由骑士拉德季·科比拉治理。同年，科比拉被迫离开城堡，保护斯卡利茨人民免遭国王西格斯蒙德的军队屠戮。随后，侵略者将城堡及周围的村庄付之一炬，自此城堡再也没有重建。 &lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;1403年12月，瓦茨拉夫四世将村庄余部让渡给兰贝格的扬·索科尔。这座中世纪城堡的遗迹及其防御工事于1730年被拆除，所得材料用于建造尼波姆克的圣约翰大教堂，只有门楼、瓮城和城墙的一小部分留存至今。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_trosecke_rybniky</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Today, there is a system of several ponds around the Trosky Castle. Although they were built in the 16th century, we decided to leave them in place because of the amazing views that their surroundings offer.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The largest of the ponds is the Rocktower Pond, which covers an area of 9 hectares, the others are Vidlák, Rokytňák, Kerchak, Hrudka and Lower Pond. In the Middle Ages, Nebakov Fortress stood near Nebakov Pond.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The area is now a nature reserve, called Podtrosecká Valley. It is the largest complex of wetland habitats in the Bohemian Paradise region and is home to many species of strictly protected organisms. If you ever decide to visit Trosky Castle, we recommend you stop by this nearby locality as well.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;现如今，特罗斯基城堡周边有一系列的池塘。虽然它们修建于16世纪，但我们还是决定将其保留，只因它们周边的景色极为宜人。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;其中最大的池塘就是石塔池塘，占地面积达9公顷，余下的则有维德拉克池塘，罗基特纳池塘，科尔察克池塘，赫鲁德卡池塘以及下池塘。中世纪时期，内巴科夫城堡就坐落在内巴科夫池塘附近。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;那片区域现如今已成为了一处名叫波德特罗谢茨卡河谷的自然保护区，它是“波希米亚伊甸园”地区最大的一片湿地栖息地群，也是许多受到严格保护的物种的家园。如果你有机会游览特罗斯基城堡，我们建议你也拜访一下位于其附近的该自然保护区。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_troskovice</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;Troskowitz&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The first mention is found in 1388 in connection with the nearby castle, but the village probably existed long before that. The village got its name from the rock on which the castle was later built, as the rock resembled the ruins of a castle from a distance.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;Tachov&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;A small village 1.5 km north of Troskowitz, first mentioned in sources in 1388. A nameless stream flows through it, emptying into the Krčák pond, forming cascades along the way and a waterfall about 10 metres high.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Today, the village is part of a protected area and the &lt;italic&gt;'Golden Trail of the Bohemian Paradise'&lt;/italic&gt; passes through it.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;Zhelejov&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;There are only a few mentions of Zhelejov. Notably, in 1558, the three sons of Lord Semine sold the fortress and the village to the 'Skalské panství'. The fortress was abandoned during the wars with the Swedes.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;特罗斯科维茨&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;与此村庄有关的记载最早可追溯到1388年，它与附近的城堡有所关联，但是村庄似乎很早之前就已存在。这座村庄的名字源自日后拔地而起的城堡身下的岩石，因为从远处望去，那些岩石看似如同一座城堡废墟。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;塔霍夫&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;这是一座位于特罗斯科维茨北边1.5公里处的小村落，于1388年首次出现于史料之中。一条无名河流途经村庄，最终注入克尔恰克（Krčák）池塘，沿途还形成了诸多小型瀑布和一个约10米高的大瀑布。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;如今，该村庄被纳入了保护区的管辖当中，&lt;italic&gt;“波希米亚伊甸园黄金小径”（Golden Trail of the Bohemian Paradise）&lt;/italic&gt;便经过那里。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;heading&gt;哲勒约夫&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;与哲勒约夫相关的记录并不多，主要发现在1558年。当时塞米领主的三个儿子将堡垒和村庄出售给了“岩石领地”（Skalské panství），而后在与瑞典人的战争期间，该堡垒遭到了遗弃。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_vojenske_lezeni</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;European medieval armies were based on the feudal obligation of nobles to serve their liege lord. This system, which originated from late Roman traditions, primarily applied to defensive warfare where there was no opportunity for plunder. If a ruler wanted to lead an offensive campaign, he had to not only promise his knights the prospect of loot but also pay them.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In France and Italy, where wars were relatively frequent, mercenary armed bands (&lt;italic&gt;rutta&lt;/italic&gt;, &lt;italic&gt;routes&lt;/italic&gt;) known as &lt;accent&gt;free companies&lt;/accent&gt; began to emerge. These companies fought for wages during wars but extorted protection money from peasants and robbed travellers during peacetime.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In the 14th century, mercenary service became a profession for thousands of impoverished nobles. Among the largest groups were the French &lt;italic&gt;Bandes blanches&lt;/italic&gt;, the English &lt;italic&gt;White Company&lt;/italic&gt;, and the Italian &lt;italic&gt;Compagnia di San Giorgio&lt;/italic&gt;. In Bohemia, there was the retinue surrounding Jan Sokol of Lamberk and Hynek I of Kunstadt.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;欧洲中世纪的军队建立在贵族对其封主的封建义务之上。这一制度源自于罗马帝国末期的传统，主要适用于无法进行劫掠的防御性战争。倘若统治者想要发动进攻性战役，他不仅要向骑士们允诺战利品，还得给他们支付报酬。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;在法国和意大利，战争相对频繁，以&lt;accent&gt;自由联队&lt;/accent&gt;著称的雇佣兵团体（&lt;italic&gt;rutta&lt;/italic&gt;，&lt;italic&gt;routes&lt;/italic&gt;）开始涌现。这些团体会在战乱期间为报酬参与到战争当中，而在和平时期又会向农民勒索保护费，或是抢劫过往旅者。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;在14世纪，数千名穷困潦倒的贵族走上了成为职业雇佣兵的道路。其中最大的兵团有：法国的&lt;italic&gt;白衣团&lt;/italic&gt;（Bandes blanches），英国的&lt;italic&gt;白公司&lt;/italic&gt;（White Company），以及意大利的&lt;italic&gt;圣乔治公司&lt;/italic&gt;（Compagnia di San Giorgio）。在波希米亚，就曾有围绕在扬·索科尔和海尼克一世身边的随从。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_cont_zlata_doba_karla</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;When Charles, the young son of John of Luxembourg, inherited the title Margrave of Moravia and subsequently the Bohemian throne, the kingdom began to flourish not only economically but also culturally. This period is now known as &lt;italic&gt;"the Golden Age"&lt;/italic&gt;.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;During his reign, many cities, towns and castles received new fortifications, new bridges and better infrastructure, as well as new churches. Many famous buildings are named after Charles because he initiated their construction, such as Charles Bridge, Karlstejn Castle and one of the oldest universities in Europe, Charles University in Prague, which he founded in 1348.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;He also emphasised the role of faith in society. He was instrumental in the renewal of the cults of Saints Wenceslas, Sigismund and Vitus, to whom he dedicated sacred buildings, including the cathedral at Prague Castle.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;He used marriage policy to strengthen his position in Europe, linking his family with prominent houses in neighbouring countries. He influenced the appointment of ecclesiastical offices. Thanks to his firm rule and a policy based on alliances, he was able to maintain peace in Europe.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;King Charles was an educated ruler with an interest in the arts, which was reflected in the architecture of the cities, especially Prague, which he chose as the seat of his court and which went through a considerable transformation during his reign.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;当卢森堡的约翰的年轻儿子，查理，继承摩拉维亚侯爵的爵位，随后又继承了波希米亚王位，国家的经济和文化开始繁荣发展，这个时期便是至今都为人熟知的&lt;italic&gt;“黄金时期”&lt;/italic&gt;。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;在查理统治期间，许多城镇与城堡建起崭新的防御工事、桥梁、基础设施以及教堂。查理本人乃建设的发起者，因此很多著名建筑均以其名命名，比如查理大桥、卡尔施泰因城堡（Karlstejn Castle），以及欧洲最古老的大学之一，也就是位于布拉格、建于1348年的查理大学。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;查理还热衷于强调信仰在社会中的重要地位，致力于重燃人们对圣瓦茨拉夫、圣西格斯蒙德以及圣维特的崇拜。他为这几位圣人兴建圣所，其中就包括建于布拉格城堡的大教堂。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;为了巩固他在欧洲的地位，他利用政治联姻，促使自己和邻国的显赫家族建立了同盟关系。他对教会官职的委任颇具影响，且得益于坚决的执政风格和为联盟颁布的政策，他才得以维护欧洲的和平。 &lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;查理是个受过良好教育的君主，对艺术兴趣颇深， 这些特点也反映在了城市的建筑之上，尤其是布拉格，他将那里选作王都，布拉格在他的统治期间经历了翻天覆地的变化。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_katerina</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;The brave and determined helper of Jan Zizka of Trotznov is mostly just a fictional character, although women bearing this name played important roles in Zizka's life.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The first Katherine was probably his mother, although this is not certain, as other sources name her Johanna. We know more about the second Katherine. In the provincial land-registry books we learn that Jan Zizka married her and acquired a farm in Čerejov as a dowry. They even had a daughter, although her name is unknown.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;After Katherine's death, Zizka married… yet another Katherine. Again, we do not know anything about her, except that Zizka inherited her property after her death.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In view of the importance of this name in the life of this great figure of Czech history, we decided to interpret the character of Katherine in our own way.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;扬·杰式卡手下那位英勇决绝的女性助手很大程度上不过是个虚构角色。不过，拥有该名字的女性在杰式卡的一生中扮演着极为重要的角色。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;我们所了解的第一位名为“凯瑟琳”的女士可能是杰式卡的母亲，但仍难以考证，因为其它资料所显示其母之名又为“约翰娜”。对于第二位名为“凯瑟琳”的女士，我们了解到的信息更多。通过翻阅省级土地登记簿，我们了解到，扬·杰式卡与这位女士缔结联姻，因此得到了一份嫁妆，即切雷约夫（Čerejov）的一间农场。两人甚至育有一女，但其名不详。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;在凯瑟琳过世后，再婚的杰式卡……又一次迎娶了一位名为“凯瑟琳”的女士。同样，我们对这位女士所知甚少，只知道杰式卡在她离世后继承了她的财产。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;对于杰式卡这位在捷克历史中颇具地位的伟人而言，如此姓名举足轻重，因此，我们决定以我们自己的方式塑造“凯瑟琳”这名角色。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_oldrich_vavak</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Twice during his life, he was appointed Royal Mint Master, and after the outbreak of the Hussite uprising, he was one of the few representatives of the higher Czech nobility to join the rebels.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;We know nothing about his life before the outbreak of the uprising, except that in the years 1402-1403 (or 1404), during King Wenceslas's absence from Bohemia, he held the office of Mint Master.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;His later life is documented, during which he supported Jan Hus and complained to King Sigismund about his burning. He initiated the negotiations of the Four Articles of Prague (which defined the direction and demands of the uprising) and was elected as a representative of the nobility to the provisional government at the Congress of Tschaslau. He marched into battle alongside Jan Zizka, and in 1421, he became the Mint Master of Kuttenberg for the second time.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;他一生两次被任命为皇家铸币官，在胡斯起义爆发后，他是少数几个加入叛乱者的捷克高级贵族。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;我们对他在起义爆发前的经历知之甚少，只知道在1402年至1403年（或1404年）期间，在瓦茨拉夫国王未掌管波希米亚之时，他担任过铸币官。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;但他的晚年经历却有详细记载。当时的他支持扬·胡斯，并向国王西格斯蒙德揭露了扬·胡斯被烧死一事。他曾发起对《布拉格四项条款》（the Four Articles of Prague）的商讨（该条款决定了起义的方向和要求），并在查斯劳大会（the Congress of Tschaslau）上被选为贵族代表，加入了临时政府。他曾与扬·杰式卡并肩作战，并于1421年在库滕堡第二次担任铸币官。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_codex_suchy_cert</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;Originally named Hynek Jevišovský of Kunstadt, he was a fierce and fearless soldier who became famous as a robber knight during the Moravian Margraviate Wars, in which he repeatedly raided Austria in 1401 and 1402, continuing even after the first capture of the Bohemian king in Vienna.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Only after the escape of King Wenceslas IV did the Austrian Duke Albrecht lose patience and so in 1404 he marched on Znojmo with 12,000 soldiers supported by another 12,000 soldiers of Sigismund of Luxembourg. However, the Dry Devil knew about the campaign. When the enemy troops stood in front of the town, it was already fortified and with substantial help from his friend Jan Sokol of Lamberg he repelled the attack. It should be noted that a dysentery epidemic, which had spread among the enemy to such an extent that both enemy nobles were infected, also contributed greatly to this. Albrecht IV of Austria even died of the disease.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;And so the Dry Devil continued to pillage and plunder.
Eventually, however, even Wenceslas IV ran out of patience and had Hynek imprisoned in 1407. He was soon released, but did not enjoy his freedom very long, for he died in 1408.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;此人原名海尼克·耶维绍夫斯基·库斯塔特（Hynek Jevišovský of Kunstadt），他是一位勇猛无畏的战士，在摩拉维亚的边疆侯爵战争期间变成了一个臭名昭著的强盗骑士，并于1401与1402年频繁袭击奥地利，在波希米亚国王受囚禁于维也纳期间，他仍未罢休。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;瓦茨拉夫四世国王逃脱后，奥地利公爵阿尔布雷希特才失去了耐心。1404年，他带领12000名战士，协同卢森堡的西格斯蒙德手下的12000兵力进军兹诺伊莫。但是，“酒鬼”提前得知了此消息。当敌军兵临城下，此时的城镇早已严加设防，且在盟友兰贝格的扬·索科尔的帮助下击退袭击。但值得注意的是，这场胜利很大程度上也得归功于在敌军阵营中传播蔓延的疾病痢疾，敌方贵族同样受到感染，奥德利的阿尔布雷希特四世还因此命丧黄泉。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;于是，“酒鬼”继续干着劫掠的勾当。
但是最后，就连瓦茨拉夫四世都失去了耐心，并于1407年将海尼克囚禁了起来。而后他很快又得到了释放，只是还未能享受足够的自由便于1408年离世。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_costs_save_potion</Cell><Cell>This will cost you one Saviour Schnapps!</Cell><Cell>这会消耗一份救世烈酒！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_deposit_item</Cell><Cell>Put down the sack</Cell><Cell>放好袋子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_deposit_jug</Cell><Cell>Put down the carafe</Cell><Cell>放下酒瓶</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_dialog_sequnce_badge_bet</Cell><Cell>and a badge</Cell><Cell>和一枚徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_dice_reroll_not_same_value</Cell><Cell>All dice should have the same value</Cell><Cell>所有骰子应具有相同的点数</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_extra_in_wh_bascinet</Cell><Cell>A bascinet adorned with the colours of the Lords of Warhorse. The only one of its kind.</Cell><Cell>一件饰有战马领主配色的中头盔，且此物世间绝无仅有。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_extra_nm_wh_bascinet</Cell><Cell>Warhorse bascinet</Cell><Cell>战马中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_extra_nm_wh_brigandine_leg</Cell><Cell>Warhorse plate leg armour</Cell><Cell>战马板甲护腿</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_help_modded_saveui_help_loadgame</Cell><Cell>This save contains the mods:</Cell><Cell>你可以按下$menu_accept;加载存档，或按下$menu_reset;删除存档。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice0_s0200</Cell><Cell>&lt;accent&gt;Held dice from previous throws&lt;/accent&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;accent&gt;保留前一次掷骰的骰子&lt;/accent&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice0_s0900</Cell><Cell>You start the game by rolling all six dice. Select the scoring dice you want keep (put them to the side and gain points for them at the end of your turn), then roll the rest again. You can keep rolling until you run out of dice. &lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;However, if you don't roll a single scoring die, you lose all points gained this turn.&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;The art of dice is to finish your turn and score your points before you run the risk of not rolling a single scoring die. &lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;The first player to reach the score goal is the victor. You can see all point information for the current game in the bottom left corner.</Cell><Cell>游戏开始时，你将掷骰全部六颗骰子。然后标记你想要的获分骰子，接着可再次掷骰剩余的骰子。只要你还有至少一颗骰子留存在对局内，你就可以继续掷骰。&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;然而，如果你在某次掷骰中没有掷出任何获分骰子，那么你将失去那一轮得到的所有分数，并且轮到你的对手进行他的回合。&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;掷骰的诀窍在于在合适的时间结束你的回合，以免失去已经获得的分数。&lt;br/&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br/&gt;最先获得规定分数的玩家获胜。你可以在左下角查看所有与对局有关的信息。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice3_s0200</Cell><Cell>Doubles the points of you last throw. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，将你所选骰子的分数翻倍。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice3_s0800</Cell><Cell>Allows you to roll one die again. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，重掷一颗骰子。每局游戏可使用两次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice3_s1000</Cell><Cell>Allows you to add one extra die to your throw. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，可在掷骰时额外增加一颗骰子。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice3_s1200</Cell><Cell>After your throw, change a die of your choosing to a 3. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>掷骰后使用，选择任意一颗骰子，将其点数更改为3。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice3_s1600</Cell><Cell>You gain 25% more points for this turn. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，该回合获得的分数提升25%。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice3_s1800</Cell><Cell>After an unlucky throw, allows you to throw again. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>若对掷骰不满意，你可以使用该徽章进行重掷。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s0200</Cell><Cell>Doubles the points of your last throw. Can be used twice per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，将你所选骰子的分数翻倍。每局游戏可使用两次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s0800</Cell><Cell>After your throw, you can roll a die of your choosing again. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>掷骰后使用，可指定一颗骰子重掷。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s1000</Cell><Cell>You can roll up to two dice again. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，重掷最多两颗骰子。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s1200</Cell><Cell>Allows you to add an extra die to your throw. Can be used twice per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，可在指定掷骰时额外增加一颗骰子。每局游戏可使用两次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s1400</Cell><Cell>After your throw, change a die of your choosing to a 5. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>掷骰后使用，选择任意一颗骰子，将其点数更改为5。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s1800</Cell><Cell>Gain 50% more points this turn. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，该回合获得的分数提升50%。每局游戏可使用一次</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s2000</Cell><Cell>After an unlucky throw, allows you to throw again. Can be used twice per game.</Cell><Cell>如果对掷骰不满意，你可以使用该徽章进行重掷。每局游戏可使用两次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice4_s2200</Cell><Cell>The badge of the rightful king of the birds allows you to add an extra die to your throw. Can be used twice per game.</Cell><Cell>正统鸟王的徽章。使用后，可在掷骰时额外增加一颗骰子，每局游戏可使用两次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s0200</Cell><Cell>Doubles the points scored from your last throw. Can be used thrice per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，将你所选骰子的分数翻倍。每局游戏可使用三次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s0800</Cell><Cell>After your throw, you can throw two dice of the same value again. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>掷骰后，选择任意两个点数相同的骰子重掷。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s1000</Cell><Cell>You can roll up to three dice again. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，重掷最多三颗骰子。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s1200</Cell><Cell>Allows you to add an extra die to your throw. Can be used thrice per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，可在掷骰时额外增加一颗骰子。每局游戏可使用三次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s1400</Cell><Cell>After your throw, change a die of your choosing to a 1. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>掷骰后，选择任意一颗骰子，将其点数更改为1。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s1800</Cell><Cell>Gain double points for this turn. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>使用后，该回合获得的分数翻倍。每局游戏可使用一次</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s2000</Cell><Cell>After an unlucky throw, allows you to throw again. Can be used thrice per game.</Cell><Cell>若对掷骰不满意，你可以使用该徽章进行重掷。每局游戏可使用三次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_dice5_s2400</Cell><Cell>A memento of Agnes and Olda's big day. Allows you to throw up to three dice again. Can be used once per game.</Cell><Cell>用于纪念阿格尼丝和奥达盛大婚礼的徽章。使用后可在一次掷骰中重掷最多三颗骰子。每局游戏可使用一次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_guns_s0000</Cell><Cell>Handgonne</Cell><Cell>手铳</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_guns_s0100</Cell><Cell>The handgonne is a terrifying modern weapon. Its slow loading speed and innaccurate aim are balanced by its sheer destructive force and the fear it causes amongst enemies.</Cell><Cell>手铳是种可怕的新式武器。虽然它装弹速度缓慢且瞄准精度差，但其所具备的强大破坏力以及可对敌人造成的威慑足以弥补它的缺陷。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_guns_s0300</Cell><Cell>Hold $gun_prepare~; &lt;strong&gt;to load pistole&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell><Cell>长按$gun_prepare~;&lt;strong&gt;装填&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_invhint_edit_belt</Cell><Cell>Attach to belt</Cell><Cell>装在腰带上</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_invhint_unequip</Cell><Cell>Unequip</Cell><Cell>卸下</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_invhint_unselect</Cell><Cell>Unselect</Cell><Cell>取消选择</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_item_info_category_Belt</Cell><Cell>Body – Belt</Cell><Cell>躯干–腰带</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_item_info_category_Crossbow</Cell><Cell>Ranged – Crossbow</Cell><Cell>远程武器–弩</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_item_info_category_LongSword</Cell><Cell>Bladed – Long</Cell><Cell>利器–长剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_item_info_category_Rifle</Cell><Cell>Handgonne</Cell><Cell>手铳</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_item_info_category_ShortSword</Cell><Cell>Bladed – Short</Cell><Cell>利器–短剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_loading_hint_38</Cell><Cell>Belladonna, an essential ingredient for Saviour Schnapps, grows mainly in clearings and leafy forests. If you don't know where to find a certain herb, check the Herbs section of the Crafting tab in your inventory.</Cell><Cell>颠茄主要生长于枝繁叶茂的树林与林中空地中，是酿制救世烈酒的重要材料。若不知去何处寻找特定草药，你可以点开物品栏，并查看“制作”分类下的草药部分。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_loading_hint_39</Cell><Cell>Herb paris, an essential ingredient for Saviour Schnapps, grows mainly in clearings and leafy forests. If you don't know where to find a certain herb, check the Herbs section of the Crafting tab in your inventory.</Cell><Cell>四叶重楼主要生长于枝繁叶茂的树林与林中空地中，是酿制救世烈酒的重要材料。若不知去何处寻找特定草药，你可以点开物品栏，并查看“制作”分类下的草药部分。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_loading_hint_62</Cell><Cell>You can save the game by drinking Saviour Schnapps, sleeping in a bed you own, or arriving at important moments in the story.</Cell><Cell>你可以通过饮用救世烈酒、睡在自己的床上、或是在剧情的重要节点保存游戏。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_ambushedBergovsMen</Cell><Cell>Von Bergow's ambushed men</Cell><Cell>遭受伏击的冯·波尔高士兵</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_partyPlace</Cell><Cell>Drinking spot</Cell><Cell>宴会点</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_roadsideCamp</Cell><Cell>Camp by the road</Cell><Cell>路边营地</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_playerCantStudy_lowSkill</Cell><Cell>You haven't reached the skill level needed to be able to use this book.</Cell><Cell>你的能力等级尚未达到阅读这本书的水平</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_recipe_learned_end</Cell><Cell>&lt;/h&gt;. Do you want to see it in the recipe book?</Cell><Cell>&lt;/h&gt;，你想跳转到配方书中查看吗？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_SaveManualGame</Cell><Cell>Consume Saviour Schnapps to save?</Cell><Cell>要使用救世烈酒保存游戏吗？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_tooltip_belt</Cell><Cell>Belt – Belt</Cell><Cell>腰带–腰带</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_warning_move_items_in_outfit</Cell><Cell>Do you want to also move items you have equipped in one of your outfits?</Cell><Cell>是否也移动套装中的物品？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_warning_move_to_basket_item_in_outfit</Cell><Cell>You're moving an item to your cart that's equipped in one of your Outfits!</Cell><Cell>你正在将一件装备在套装中的物品移动到购物篮中！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_wine</Cell><Cell>Wine</Cell><Cell>葡萄酒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_helpoverlay_combos0_s0300</Cell><Cell>Holding down the block button will allow you &lt;strong&gt;block attacks from all opponents&lt;/strong&gt; in front of you. However, a successful block costs &lt;strong&gt;耐力&lt;/strong&gt;, so you'll be unable to defend yourself without it.</Cell><Cell>按住格挡即可&lt;strong&gt;招架面前所有敌人的进攻&lt;/strong&gt;。然而每次成功格挡都会消耗 &lt;strong&gt;stamina&lt;/strong&gt;，一旦耐力消耗干净后，就无法有效抵御攻击。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_combogroup_unarmed</Cell><Cell>Unarmed</Cell><Cell>徒手</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_crime_list_title</Cell><Cell>Crime commited</Cell><Cell>所犯罪行</Cell></Row>
</Table>
