<Table>
<Row><Cell>asidovezi_ukradni_hreb_z__SfQB</Cell><Cell>Steal the nail from the rafter.</Cell><Cell>从椽子处偷取钉子。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>asidovezi_ukradni_minci_z_ClE2</Cell><Cell>Steal the coin from the building's foundation.</Cell><Cell>从建筑地基处偷取硬币。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>asidovezi_vykovej_sekeru__6wjG</Cell><Cell>Forge a protective axe.</Cell><Cell>锻造一把镇宅斧。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_laszlo_mi_nabid_MXNy</Cell><Cell>László made me an offer. If I help him conspire against Jan, I'll receive the dead Peter's equipment. Politely but clearly, I turned him down. I have my honour, after all. The handover will still take place, so that Jan can properly bury his brother. I hope László doesn't cause any more problems.</Cell><Cell>拉斯洛提出一个条件。如果我帮助他密谋反对扬，我将得到死去彼得的装备。我礼貌而明确地拒绝了他。我毕竟要维护自己的荣誉。交接还是要进行，这样扬就可以安葬他的哥哥。我希望拉斯洛不会再制造任何麻烦。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_laszlo_mi_nabid_Zanm</Cell><Cell>László made me an offer. If I help him conspire against Jan, he'll provide me with such equipment that many a knight could only dream about. Sounds interesting, but I don't like the idea of joining up with his Cumans. </Cell><Cell>拉斯洛向我提出了一个条件。如果我帮助他密谋对付扬，他将为我提供许多骑士梦寐以求的装备。听起来很有意思，但我不想与他的库曼人联手。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_p_kdyz_jsem_zji_l9or</Cell><Cell>When I learned that Peter was dead, I knew that László wasn't playing fair with Jan. But that's all I learned.</Cell><Cell>当我得知彼得死了，我知道拉斯洛对扬使了诈，但我就知道这么多。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_p_naoko_jsem_la_mTFg</Cell><Cell>I lied to László, telling him I would betray Jan and lead him into a trap. If I tell Jan about these plans in time, we can think up a way to protect ourselves.</Cell><Cell>我对拉斯洛撒了谎，告诉他我会背叛扬，把他引入陷阱。如果我把这些计划及时告诉扬，我们可以想出一个保护自己的办法。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_p_oboril_jsem_s_aerd</Cell><Cell>I told László that I know what happened to Peter. He responded that Jan will want his body back to bury it. So a handover should take place in any case.</Cell><Cell>我告诉拉斯洛，我知道彼得发生了什么。他回答说，扬会希望要回尸体埋葬。所以无论如何都应该进行交接。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>councilman_konsel_je_na_n_O6WM</Cell><Cell>I fought a duel of honour on Tuchmacher's behalf against Jan of Lesztin. I won, and Tuchmacher promised me he'd support the Kingfisher baths in the council vote.</Cell><Cell>我代表图赫马赫进行了一场荣誉决斗，在这场与列斯汀的扬的较量中，我成功胜出。图赫马赫也因此向我承诺，他将在市议会投票时向翠鸟澡堂提供他的支持。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crouch_v_rybniku_nejsme_s_WDZu</Cell><Cell>Me and Sir Hans are not alone in the pond. A little further along by the banks there are some girls bathing, and Sir Hans, gentleman that he is, wants to go and spy on them. We'll have to keep our heads down in the reeds, otherwise we'll cause a stir.</Cell><Cell>光顾这片池塘的，不止我和汉斯少主。沿岸稍远处有群姑娘在洗澡。汉斯少主一展绅士风度，欲要上前窥探。我们得在芦苇丛中藏好，不然麻烦就大了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>defeatjan_p_laszlo_padl_v_V3ul</Cell><Cell>Everything that could go wrong did go wrong. Sir Peter is dead, Jan of Suchotlesky is dead, and so too is Baron Farkas. No one gained anything from it all. There was no winner…</Cell><Cell>满盘皆输。彼得爵士死了，苏霍茨基的扬也死了，法卡斯男爵也死了。没有人从中获利。没有赢家……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>defeatlas_p_jan_padl_v_bo_oQHZ</Cell><Cell>Unfortunately, Jan did not survive his second encounter with László's Cumans. But at least he's now with his brother. May the earth rest lightly on them.</Cell><Cell>不幸的是，与拉斯洛的库曼人进行第二次对抗时，扬没有幸存下来。但至少他现在和哥哥在一起了。愿他们安息。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>deliverof_knez_marian_ves_0zKe</Cell><Cell>Father Marian doesn't believe in the local legend about a gateway to hell in the abandoned mines near Old Kutna. Nevertheless, he hired me to look into it to put a stop to the rumours. He gave me some food to prepare as an offering for demons in the mines. We'll see who really comes to pick it up.</Cell><Cell>当地传说称老库特纳附近的废弃矿场有一个通往地狱的通道，神父马里安并不相信。尽管如此，他还是雇我去调查，以终止谣言。他给了我一些食物，用来献祭矿井里的恶魔。我们可以看看究竟是谁会来拿走这些东西。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>deliverof_knez_marian_ves_hL9O</Cell><Cell>Father Marian doesn't believe in the local legend about a gateway to hell in the abandoned mines near Old Kutna. Nevertheless, he hired me to look into it to put a stop to the rumours. He gave me some supplies to lower into the mine. That will no longer be possible, since the locals were stricken by an unforseeable event...</Cell><Cell>当地传说称老库特纳附近的废弃矿场有一个通往地狱的通道，神父马里安并不相信。尽管如此，他还是雇我去调查，以终止谣言。他给了我一些物资，让我下放到矿井。这将不再可能实施，因为当地人被一个不可预知的事件所困扰......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>deliverof_knez_marian_ves_y2gR</Cell><Cell>Father Marian doesn't believe in the local legend about a gateway to hell in the abandoned mines near Old Kutna. Nevertheless, he hired me to look into it to put a stop to the rumours. He gave me some supplies and I lowered them into the mine. But what I lured out were no demons. Or were they?</Cell><Cell>当地传说称老库特纳附近的废弃矿场有一个通往地狱的通道，神父马里安并不相信。尽管如此，他还是雇我去调查，以终止谣言。他给了我一些物资，我把它们下放到矿井。但我引出来的东西究竟是不是恶魔，我心里也没数。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_nakonec_jsem_ce_GOA1</Cell><Cell>In the end, I brought Gules Canker's mace as proof.</Cell><Cell>最后，我把“溃疡”的页锤交给了古勒斯作为证据。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_podarilo_se_mi__pmhU</Cell><Cell>I managed to deceive Gules into thinking that Canker is dead when I brought him his mace.</Cell><Cell>我把页锤带给了古勒斯，假称“溃疡”已经死了，成功骗过了他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_ted_uz_mi_staci_nTCL</Cell><Cell>Now all I have to do is pick up Canker's mace and bring it as proof to Gules.</Cell><Cell>现在我只需要捡走“溃疡”的页锤，将其作为证据交给古勒斯就可以了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_ted_uz_mi_staci_SNKq</Cell><Cell>Now all I have to do is bring Canker's mace as proof to Gules.</Cell><Cell>现在我只需要把“溃疡”的页锤作为证据交给古勒斯就可以了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_enn_prinest_vino_vl_uIbm</Cell><Cell>Enneleyn doesn't want anything left to chance, so she'll mix sleeping potion into some wine for the chamberlain. I brought her some wine as a gift. At the very least, she'll be able to fortify herself before the wedding.</Cell><Cell>恩内琳希望事情万无一失，所以她会在给管家的酒里加入安眠药水。于是我决定给她带些酒，这样她可以在婚礼前喝点来壮胆。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_enn_prinest_vino_vl_ZExG</Cell><Cell>Enneleyn didn't want anything left to chance, so she mixed sleeping potion into some wine for the chamberlain. Since she used her own supply of the potion for our sakes, I at least brought her some wine as a gift.</Cell><Cell>恩内琳希望事情万无一失，所以她在给管家的酒里加入了安眠药水。既然她要用自己的东西完成我们的计划，我决定给她带些酒做为礼物。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kdyz_kozesinu_z_kfWI</Cell><Cell>If I hand over the white roebuck's hide to the huntsman, he will rightfully give it to Peter of Pisek, the owner of the local woods.</Cell><Cell>如果我将白狍子皮交给猎人，他自然会将它交给本地森林的主人——皮塞克的彼得。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kozesina_z_bile_Uuwe</Cell><Cell>The white roebuck's hide I happened upon by chance turned out to be from a recently killed rare roebuck. Dobrosh, the huntsman of Suchdol, rewarded me for finding it.</Cell><Cell>我偶然发现的那张白狍子皮原来属于最近被猎杀的一头稀有狍子。苏赫多尔的猎人多布罗什为我提供了发现这张狍子皮的赏金。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kozesinu_jsem_o_kOIX</Cell><Cell>I gave the white hide to Wolfram the knacker. He paid me for it on the spot. What he does with it next is no concern of mine.</Cell><Cell>我将白狍子皮交给了屠夫沃尔夫勒姆。他当场就付钱了。至于他之后要怎么处置这张狍子皮，我就管不着了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kozesinu_jsem_o_tj7p</Cell><Cell>I handed the hide over to Dobrosh, the huntsman. He will rightfully hand it over to Peter of Pisek.</Cell><Cell>我将白狍子皮交给猎人多布罗什。他自然会将它交给皮塞克的彼得。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_ras_wolfram_by__Ew2l</Cell><Cell>Wolfram the knacker, should have a buyer for such a rare hide. If I hand it over to him, I'd make a lot of coin.</Cell><Cell>屠夫沃尔夫勒姆应该找到了一个有意购买这张罕见狍子皮的买家。如果我将狍子皮交给他，就可以赚到许多钱。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>doved_enn_krejzluv_plan_j_F3y4</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl's plan is underway. Enneleyn, wearing the finest Tyrolean brocade and Mintha perfume, is the bait for the chamberlain. Now it's all up to her.</Cell><Cell>克雷泽的计划正在进行中。恩内琳穿着最好的蒂罗尔锦缎，喷着薄荷香水，将引诱管家上钩。而现在就都看她的了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>doved_kur_kurtyzanu_jsem__ObIL</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl's plan is underway. Enneleyn, wearing finest Tyrolean brocade and Mintha perfume, will be bait for the chamberlain. As her bodyguard for the evening, I have to hope she'll do what we agreed and we'll both go straight to Trosky from the wedding. But ideally separately: Enneleyn with the chamberlain, and me with von Bergow. Shall we got to it?</Cell><Cell>克雷泽的计划正在进行中。恩内琳穿着最好的蒂罗尔锦缎，喷着薄荷香水，将引诱管家上钩。而我作为她今晚的保镖，希望她能够遵守我们之间的约定，我们俩将在婚礼上直接去往特罗斯基。但最好是分头行动：恩内琳和管家一起，我和冯·波尔高一起。我们可以走了吗？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_getreinforcemen_o5PF</Cell><Cell>Find reinforcements for Jan.</Cell><Cell>为扬找增援。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_gowithjantohand_Foxl</Cell><Cell>Tell Jan once you are ready to head out.</Cell><Cell>等准备好了，就去找扬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_reinforcements__pqh9</Cell><Cell>Reinforcements - Goliath and Hog.</Cell><Cell>增援——歌利亚和“猪”</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_reinforcements__wNNA</Cell><Cell>Reinforcements - Mikesh and Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>增援——米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_rewardfromjan_m4qx</Cell><Cell>Go and see Jan for your reward.</Cell><Cell>去见扬，要你的奖赏。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_telljanlaszlois_LObM</Cell><Cell>Tell Jan that László died.</Cell><Cell>告诉扬，拉斯洛死了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_telljanwhatyouk_Bp4g</Cell><Cell>Tell Jan what you found out in the camp.</Cell><Cell>告诉扬你在营地里发现了什么。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_zabij_jana_pKMM</Cell><Cell>Kill Jan.</Cell><Cell>杀了扬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fetch_pac_beta_po_me_chce_MYoy</Cell><Cell>Betty wants me to bring her some package from Grund and to pick up Matsek the wagoner, who went there before me.</Cell><Cell>贝蒂希望我能从格兰德为她取回一些包裹，并将早先前往那里的马车夫马切克接回。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>finaltalk_knez_marian_me__wSNx</Cell><Cell>Father Marian rewarded me for my help. There's no one guarding the pit to hell now, as the only demon turned out to be the deranged knight, Taras Mura.</Cell><Cell>神父马里安奖励我伸出援手。现在通往地狱的深坑无人看守，因为疯狂的骑士塔拉斯·穆拉才是唯一的恶魔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>finaltalk_vsechno_co_se_s_j3B4</Cell><Cell>I should visit Father Marian and discuss everything that happened.</Cell><Cell>我应该去拜访神父马里安，讨论所发生的一切。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>findoutwh_k_bozene_prisli_eJ8P</Cell><Cell>Some fellows came to Bozhena's looking for us. They claimed to be from Lord von Bergow, but that was a lie. More likely they belong to that band that attacked us down by the pond.</Cell><Cell>有几个人来博珍娜家找我们，自称在冯·波尔高大人的麾下。胡说八道，他们分明像是在池塘边袭击我们的那伙人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gethalberd_rytir_jan_mi_d_29hr</Cell><Cell>Sir Jan recommended I take one of the halberds previously carried by his men. We won't have the numbers on our side in this fight, so keeping the enemy back will be crucial. I decided to follow the knight's advice.</Cell><Cell>扬爵士建议我拿上他手下以前携带的一把战戟。在这场战斗中，我们要以寡敌众，所以拦阻敌人至关重要。我决定听从这位骑士的建议。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gethalberd_rytir_jan_mi_d_6E1O</Cell><Cell>Sir Jan recommended I take one of the halberds previously carried by his men. We won't have the numbers on our side in this fight, so keeping the enemy back will be crucial.</Cell><Cell>扬爵士建议我拿上他手下以前携带的一把战戟。在这场战斗中，我们要以寡敌众，所以拦阻敌人至关重要。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gethalberd_rytir_jan_mi_d_XHfu</Cell><Cell>Sir Jan recommended I take one of the halberds previously carried by his men. I prefer my own weaponry, however, and don't require anything else.</Cell><Cell>扬爵士建议我拿上他手下以前携带的一把战戟。不过，我更喜欢自己的兵器装备，不需要其他东西。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreinfo_p_bohuzel_se_mi_Y7lT</Cell><Cell>I didn't arrange any reinforcements against László with Jan.</Cell><Cell>我并未与扬指派任何援军来对付拉斯洛。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreinfo_p_na_janovu_zad_1EFU</Cell><Cell>At Jan's request, I've found a few fearless men who I can count on.</Cell><Cell>在扬的要求下，我找到了几个可信而无畏的人选。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreinfo_p_na_janovu_zad_o9ni</Cell><Cell>A nice little group will be accompanying me to meet László. I hope Jan will be happy.</Cell><Cell>一支精锐小队将陪同我去见拉斯洛。我希望扬会很高兴。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gowithjan_mel_bych_si_zar_KBdq</Cell><Cell>I should take care of all necessary affairs, then return to Jan and go for the handover. The journey will take some time. It'll be best if we head out before noon.</Cell><Cell>我应该处理好所有必要事务，再回到扬那里然后去，交接。路途有些遥远，最好在中午前出发。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gowithjan_vzhledem_k_nast_wFK2</Cell><Cell>Given the situation, there's no point in going with Jan to the agreed-upon handover.</Cell><Cell>鉴于这种情况，和扬一起去约定的交接地点没有意义。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>hlad_a_zm_zkus_zkrotit_bo_oLYB</Cell><Cell>Try to tame Boudica.</Cell><Cell>尝试驯服波提卡。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jantlama_rozbji_bandu_hon_iXC6</Cell><Cell>Break up Johnny the Gob's gang.</Cell><Cell>瓦解大嘴约翰尼的帮派。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_do_ve_stestena_nam_pr_OOKh</Cell><Cell>Fortune shone upon us, and the defenders of Maleshov fortress eventually surrendered. We captured the royal chamberlain and rescued Rosa Ruthard.</Cell><Cell>受到幸运之神的眷顾，马列索夫堡垒的守卫们最终选择了投降。我们抓住了那位皇家总管，也救出了罗莎·鲁瑟德。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_po_st_mlyn_na_danemar_Hfu8</Cell><Cell>Something is rotten in Danemark. The mill there has been seized by a band of robbers. They don't look like desperate refugees, more like seasoned outlaws. Fresh traces prove the ambush on the way to Bylany was their doing, so the Striped Tonies' standard will be somewhere in the mill.</Cell><Cell>德内马克状况很糟。那里的磨坊已经被一伙强盗占领。他们看起来不像是绝望的难民，更像是老练的亡命之徒。新的痕迹证明，是他们在去比兰尼的路上发起伏击，所以条纹托尼帮旗杆可能在磨坊里面。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kaspar_rozbij_kasparovu_b_YfA0</Cell><Cell>Break up Casper's band.</Cell><Cell>瓦解卡斯帕的团伙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovarskas_prines_zdimirov_rcnh</Cell><Cell>Bring Zdimir the hunting sword you forged.</Cell><Cell>把你锻造的狩猎剑拿给兹迪米尔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovarskas_vykovej_soutezn_dclU</Cell><Cell>Forge a competition hunting sword.</Cell><Cell>锻造一把竞赛狩猎剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovar_uder_kladivek_do_ob_BdbP</Cell><Cell>Hammer the workpiece.</Cell><Cell>锤打工件。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovar_uder_kladivek_porad_l2sP</Cell><Cell>Hammer the workpiece properly.</Cell><Cell>正确锤打工件。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovar_zakal_mec_KwkK</Cell><Cell>Temper the blade.</Cell><Cell>淬炼剑身。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kubaparalu_podej_zpravu_o_6frC</Cell><Cell>Give the report on the killing of Father Prokop.</Cell><Cell>汇报普罗科普神父被杀一事。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kubaparalu_zabij_prokopa_GkKX</Cell><Cell>Kill Father Prokop.</Cell><Cell>杀死普罗科普神父。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_krcak</Cell><Cell>Kerchak Pond</Cell><Cell>科尔察克池塘</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_vezak</Cell><Cell>Rocktower Pond</Cell><Cell>石塔池塘</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_vidlak</Cell><Cell>Vidlak Pond</Cell><Cell>维德拉克池塘</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lootersco_jak_to_s_dranci_wKNG</Cell><Cell>I'll never know what happened to the looters because I simply walked away. I can't expect Jan to forgive me for doing so.</Cell><Cell>我永远不会知道那些劫掠者发生了什么，因为我直接走开了。我不能指望扬会原谅我的所作所为。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lootersco_osud_dranciru_b_GChI</Cell><Cell>The fate of the looters was sealed the moment Sir Jan beheld their godless behaviour. No one was left alive.</Cell><Cell>当扬爵士看到他们的大逆不道行为时，这些劫掠者已经难逃一死。最终没人幸免。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_a_v_v_poustevnikove_bkVG</Cell><Cell>I did indeed find the broken old sword at the hermit's grave. You can tell at first glance that it's a precious piece made of steel by the master craftsmen of Toledo.</Cell><Cell>我的确在隐士的墓前找到了那把断剑。一看就知道，这是托莱多的工匠大师用钢铁锻造的宝剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_a_v_zastavu_svateho_v8s6</Cell><Cell>I finally tracked down the St. Anthony standard beyond the walls of Kuttenberg in a mill in Danemark. Joerg Preng, the foreman of the All Saints, sold it to a merchant called Hensel, but then Hensel was robbed of it by a band of outlaws. It seems the standard brings bad luck to anyone who seizes it.</Cell><Cell>我终于在库滕堡城墙之外德内马克的一家磨坊里追踪到了圣安东尼旗杆。圣徒矿场的领班乔格·普伦把它卖给了一个叫亨泽尔的商人，但后来一伙亡命之徒把它从亨泽尔手中抢了去。这个旗杆似乎会给夺取它的人带来厄运。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_dev_aby_dostal_tu_s_DKek</Cell><Cell>This time, Kreyzl doesn't even want me to steal the book. He's found some girl called Enneleyn for that. He'll take her to the Semine wedding and dangle her like bait in front of Chamberlain Ulrich's eyes. I ended up going to the wedding with the Tachov blacksmith, so it's hard to say how that turned out.</Cell><Cell>这次，克雷泽甚至都不想让我去偷书。他找来了一个叫恩内琳的姑娘做这件事。他会带她去参加塞米的婚礼，然后让她作为诱饵在管家乌尔里希面前晃悠。最后我和塔霍夫的铁匠去参加了婚礼，所以结果如何就不好说了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_dev_aby_dostal_tu_s_X2jJ</Cell><Cell>I was supposed to find this fearless Enneleyn in the nomads' camp by the Rocktower Pond. I had heard she was likely to ask for quite a tidy sum in return, but she turned out to be a reasonable and experienced woman and more importantly, she agreed to the plan. I even got the impression she was really looking forward to meeting the chamberlain.</Cell><Cell>我应该在石塔池塘边的游牧民营地里找到这位无所畏惧的恩内琳。我听说她可能会索要一笔数目不小的报酬，但结果她是位通情达理且老练的女人，更重要的是，她同意了这个计划。我甚至感觉她实际上非常期待见到管家。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_koz_kuzi_z_bileho_s_wP7u</Cell><Cell>I found the white roebuck's hide in the poachers' camp.</Cell><Cell>我在偷猎者的营地找到了白狍子皮。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_koz_pokud_pytlaci_k_dGfl</Cell><Cell>If the poachers didn't sell the white roebuck's hide, it must be hidden somewhere in their camp.</Cell><Cell>如果偷猎者没有卖掉白狍子皮，那么它肯定就藏在他们的营地里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_tab_snazim_se_vypat_3YOp</Cell><Cell>I'm trying to track down the poachers who killed a white roebuck in the woods near Suchdol. There's a bounty on the poachers' heads. According to Wolfram the knacker, the poachers are holed up somewhere near water in the woods along the road to Raborsch.</Cell><Cell>我正在追查在苏赫多尔附近的树林中猎杀了一头白狍子的偷猎者。有人悬赏缉拿偷猎者的人头。据屠夫沃尔夫勒姆说，偷猎者躲在通往拉博施路边的树林里，那地方附近有水。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_tab_snazim_se_vypat_8q76</Cell><Cell>I'm trying to track down the poachers who killed a white roebuck in the woods near Suchdol. There's a bounty on the poachers' heads.</Cell><Cell>我正在追查在苏赫多尔附近的树林中猎杀了一头白狍子的偷猎者。有人悬赏缉拿偷猎者的人头。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_tab_vypatral_jsem_p_YBph</Cell><Cell>I tracked down the band of poachers that killed a rare white roebuck in the woods near Suchdol.</Cell><Cell>我正追查在苏赫多尔附近的树林中猎杀了一头罕见白狍子的一群偷猎者。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_vep_cenek_me_pozada_k7OK</Cell><Cell>Chenyek asked me to find Hog, who went to find out something about the mysterious symbols in Kuttenberg from a former thief, Hynek, and hasn't returned yet. Hog can take care of himself, but I should go check on him.</Cell><Cell>程叶科让我去找“猪”。“猪”去拜访曾当过盗贼的人了，为了了解有关库滕堡神秘符号的事情，现在还没有回来。“猪”应该能照顾好自己，但我还是想要去看看他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_vep_ted_uz_nema_smy_NlHk</Cell><Cell>There's no use searching for Hog now.</Cell><Cell>现在就算找到“猪”也没意义了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_vep_vepre_jsem_sice_nO8N</Cell><Cell>I managed to find Hog, but he got himself into an unpleasant situation. The fool killed the only person who could point us in the right direction regarding the symbols. Maybe he managed to get something out of him before he died.</Cell><Cell>我设法找到了“猪”，但他让自己陷入了一个不愉快的局面。这个傻瓜杀了唯一能帮助我们解密符号的人。也许在那人死之前，他设法套出了一些东西。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__jakmile_jsme_me_P4Ln</Cell><Cell>Me and Godwin went back down to the secret passageway. We were lucky - nobody came across Zizka or Katherine.</Cell><Cell>我和古德温回到了秘密通道里。杰式卡和凯瑟琳没被人撞见，我们真走运。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__uz_mame_vsechno_jb6a</Cell><Cell>We've already got everything, so now I have to hurry back to Godwin. Zizka and Katherine are waiting.</Cell><Cell>东西都到手了，我得尽快跟古德温汇合。杰式卡和凯瑟琳还在等着我们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__zautocila_na_na_ltPL</Cell><Cell>An unknown band of armed men attacked us. Me and Sir Hans swam across the pond. Our company in the camp was slain to the last man and I was wounded too.</Cell><Cell>我们遭到了一队陌生兵寇的袭击。我和汉斯少主游过池塘，得以幸存。营地里所有人都被杀了，我也身负重伤。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__kozlik_je_jedni_6Dsb</Cell><Cell>Kozliek has been serving under Zizka for a long time. Now he's a member of my company.</Cell><Cell>科兹里克曾在杰式卡手下工作了很久。现在他是我连队的一员了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__kozlik_je_jedni_r0GH</Cell><Cell>Kozliek has been serving under Zizka for a long time. Now he'll be reporting to me.</Cell><Cell>科兹里克曾在杰式卡手下工作了很久。现在他要向我报道了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__zizka_mi_dal_ve_1cxY</Cell><Cell>Zizka assigned two of his most experienced men to my company: Mikesh and Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>杰式卡把他最有经验的两个人派给了我的连队：米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__zizka_mi_dal_ve_1zA6</Cell><Cell>Zizka put me in command of two of his experienced men. I’ll likely find Mikesh and Kozliek on the battlements.</Cell><Cell>杰式卡让我指挥他那两个身经百战的手下。我去城垛上或许就能找到米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nebakovob_osetri_kozlika_aXZ5</Cell><Cell>Treat Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>治疗科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nebakovob_sezen_pro_pelcl_XfK0</Cell><Cell>Find horseshoes for Peltzel.</Cell><Cell>给佩尔泽尔寻找马蹄铁。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>negotiate_nastoupil_jsem__UE7j</Cell><Cell>I told László that I know what happened to Peter. His response surprised me. Not batting an eyelid, he made me an offer, a rather dishonourable one. In my situation, though, it would be foolish to turn it down. I do feel sorry for Jan though…</Cell><Cell>我告诉拉斯洛，我知道彼得发生了什么。他的反应让我吃惊。他眼皮都不眨一下，给我开了个条件，一个相当可耻的条件。不过，如果我拒绝，就显得愚蠢。但我确实为扬感到难过......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>negotiate_oslovil_jsem_la_Qaz6</Cell><Cell>I spoke to László and introduced myself as Jan's intermediary. Although László received me, during our negotiations he made it abundantly clear that he was the one setting conditions. He agreed the handover would take place on neutral ground, but when I wanted to see the captive, László adamantly refused. I hope Jan won't be disappointed with the outcome. </Cell><Cell>我与拉斯洛交谈，说自己是扬的中间人。虽然拉斯洛接待了我，但在我们的谈判中，他非常清楚地表示，他才是开出条件的人。他同意在中立地点进行交接，但当我要看俘虏时，拉斯洛坚决拒绝。我希望扬不会对这个结果感到失望。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>negotiate_p_laszla_jsem_r_fT31</Cell><Cell>I immediately told László I know what happened to Peter. László claimed that Jan will certainly want to bury Peter's body. We agreed where the body will be handed over. Jan should be cautious though…</Cell><Cell>我立即告诉拉斯洛我知道彼得发生了什么。拉斯洛称，扬肯定会想埋葬彼得的尸体。我们商定了要在哪里进行尸体交接。但扬应该谨慎行事......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_naverbuj_kozlika_I3xd</Cell><Cell>Recruit Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>征募科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_naverbuj_mikese_DRBj</Cell><Cell>Recruit Mikesh and Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>征募米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_objective1_5trm</Cell><Cell>Knocked-down ladders:</Cell><Cell>推倒梯子：</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_seber_mece_k_br_7xr4</Cell><Cell>Collect swords to be sharpened.</Cell><Cell>收集需要打磨锋利的剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_shod_zebriky_1SKw</Cell><Cell>Knocked-down ladders:</Cell><Cell>推倒梯子：</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>odnes_mec_drsnak_vasko_po_C7nR</Cell><Cell>Tomcat could tell straightaway that the sword of Damascus steel wasn't made by Radovan, an ordinary village blacksmith, but in the end, he still honoured the wager.</Cell><Cell>公猫一眼就看出，这把用大马士革钢锻造的剑不是出自拉多万这个普通的乡村铁匠之手，但最后他还是兑现了赌约。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>odnes_sek_donesl_jsem_par_CiMA</Cell><Cell>I brought Johann the protective axe I forged for him.</Cell><Cell>我为约翰带来了我锻造的镇宅斧。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>opatrne_n_holky_nas_sice__z1kr</Cell><Cell>Capon and I weren't alone in the pond. A bit further along the shore some laundresses were bathing and Capon had the bright idea of going to spy on them. Although the girls didn’t spot us, we didn’t enjoy their scantily dressed loveliness for long.</Cell><Cell>光顾这片池塘的，不止我和汉斯少主。沿岸稍远处有几名洗衣女在洗澡。卡蓬起了雅兴，欲要上前窥探。虽然我们未被发现，但也没能欣赏她们的曼妙身姿太久。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>opatrne_n_nakonec_se_to_u_z6fe</Cell><Cell>Capon and I weren't alone in the pond. A bit further along the shore some laundresses were bathing and Capon had the bright idea of going to spy on them.That turned out to be one damned stupid idea! We just ended up scaring one of the girls.</Cell><Cell>光顾这片池塘的，不止我和汉斯少主。沿岸稍远处有几名洗衣女在洗澡。卡蓬起了雅兴，欲要上前窥探。真是个馊主意！我们吓到了其中一位姑娘。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osetri_ko_kozlik_byl_rane_f48n</Cell><Cell>Kozliek was wounded in battle. I should take a look at him and treat him.</Cell><Cell>科兹里克在战斗中负伤。我得查看他的伤势并对他进行治疗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osetri_ko_raneneho_kozlik_ly6P</Cell><Cell>I examined the injured Kozliek and treated him.</Cell><Cell>我查看了科兹里克的伤势并提供了治疗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osetri_ko_zraneneho_kozli_1tUG</Cell><Cell>I didn't treat the injured Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>我没有治疗受伤的科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>plesnivec_dones_cevenakov_D3ob</Cell><Cell>Bring Gules Canker's mace.</Cell><Cell>把“溃疡”的页锤带给古勒斯。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>plesnivec_rozbij_plesnivc_FagQ</Cell><Cell>Break up Canker's gang</Cell><Cell>瓦解“溃疡”的团伙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pokracuj__chvala_panu_vuz_GwQT</Cell><Cell>Thank God! I made it to the wagon and Katherine's other allies. After waiting a few hours for von Bergow's soldiers to call off the search, we got Zizka onto the cart and set off for the Kuttenberg region.</Cell><Cell>谢天谢地！我终于找到了那辆马车和凯瑟琳的其他伙伴。我们等了几个小时，终于等到冯·波尔高的手下结束了搜捕，随后帮杰式卡上了马车，便朝着库滕堡地区行进。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomodli_s_knez_prokop_z_k_AgWa</Cell><Cell>Father Prokop of Kuttenberg sent me on a penitential pilgrimage to the shrine of the Virgin Mary in Bohunowitz. I prayed to the Virgin and repented of my sins.</Cell><Cell>库滕堡的普罗科普神父指派我前往博胡诺维茨的圣母玛利亚教堂进行朝圣。我已向圣母祈祷，为我的罪孽进行了忏悔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomodli_s_knez_prokop_z_k_cpsm</Cell><Cell>Father Prokop of Kuttenberg sent me on a penitential pilgrimage to the shrine of the Virgin Mary in Bohunowitz. I am to pray at the chapel and repent of my sins.</Cell><Cell>库滕堡的普罗科普神父指派我前往博胡诺维茨的圣母玛利亚教堂进行朝圣，我得到那里去进行祈祷，为我的罪孽进行忏悔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomodli_s_knez_prokop_z_k_ddIv</Cell><Cell>Father Prokop of Kuttenberg sent me on a penitential pilgrimage to the shrine of the Virgin Mary in Bohunowitz. I was supposed to pray to her and repent of my sins, but Father Procop has since died. I must seek redemption elsewhere.</Cell><Cell>库滕堡的普罗科普神父指派我前往博胡诺维茨的圣母玛利亚教堂进行朝圣。而我本该向圣母祈祷，祈求洗清我的罪孽，然而神父普罗科普却在此期间与世长辞，如今我必须得到别处寻找赎罪之法。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomoz_zaj_po_vsem_co_se_n_T8Bp</Cell><Cell>Despite all the things that went wrong that bloody night, Maleshov fortress still fell, Otto van Bergow was captured, and Lady Rosa Ruthard was rescued. Fortune finally smiled upon us, and we literally had the royal chamberlain in the palm of our hand.</Cell><Cell>即使在那个腥风血雨的夜晚发生了很多意外，随着马列索夫堡垒的最终沦陷，奥托·冯·波尔高落入了我们手里，同时罗莎·鲁瑟德夫人也就此得救。幸运女神终于朝我们微笑了，而我们也确实将那位皇家总管掌握在了手中。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>po_pytlac_dones_kozesinu__5Noe</Cell><Cell>Bring the white roebuck's hide to the knacker.</Cell><Cell>将白狍子皮交给屠夫。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>po_pytlac_dones_kozesinu__Bcii</Cell><Cell>Bring the white roebuck's hide to the huntsman.</Cell><Cell>将白狍子皮交给猎人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>po_pytlac_najdi_kozesinu__6Z1t</Cell><Cell>Find the white roebuck's hide.</Cell><Cell>找到白狍子皮</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poslicek__event_caption_g6Xa</Cell><Cell>Errand boy</Cell><Cell>小跟班</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poslicek__player_caption_XjIG</Cell><Cell>Errand boy</Cell><Cell>小跟班</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>postarej__na_mlyne_danema_x2I4</Cell><Cell>A band of brutes has occupied Danemark and killed the miller's son Vashek. Unfortunately, I wasn't able to deal with them.</Cell><Cell>一伙强盗抢占了德内马克磨坊，并杀害了磨坊主的儿子瓦谢克。很不幸，我没能解决掉他们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>postarej__pomstil_jsem_sm_8a4t</Cell><Cell>I avenged the death of the miller's son Vashek. The black souls of those miserable wretches who took over Danemark are already knocking on the gates of Hell.</Cell><Cell>我替被害的磨坊主儿子瓦谢克报仇了。那些抢占了德内马克磨坊还给他人招致苦难的肮脏灵魂，现在的他们肯定在敲响地狱的大门。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>prohledej_musim_prohledat_Yz5B</Cell><Cell>I have to search Hynek's body and find the parchment he showed Hog before he died.</Cell><Cell>我必须搜索海尼克的尸体，找到他死前给“猪”看的羊皮纸。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_kozlik_byl_vybr_Rbr9</Cell><Cell>Kozliek was chosen for the raid. I could send Mikesh with him.</Cell><Cell>我选择派科兹里克参加突袭，也也可以派米凯什和他一起去。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_kozlik_se_rad_v_NIIc</Cell><Cell>Kozliek is a betting man, but should I be betting his life on today's raid?</Cell><Cell>科兹里克是个赌徒，但我要拿他的命作今天突袭的赌注吗？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mikes_a_kozlik__Xhu8</Cell><Cell>Mikesh and Kozliek should be on guard duty in the courtyard. If I want to select them for the raid I should find them there.</Cell><Cell>米凯什和科兹里克正在庭院执勤。若想派他们参加突袭，我应该去那里找到他们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mikes_byl_vybra_l9oL</Cell><Cell>Mikesh was chosen for the raid. I could send Kozliek with him.</Cell><Cell>我选择派米凯什参加突袭，也可以派科兹里克和他一起去。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mikes_i_kozlik__RV4t</Cell><Cell>Mikesh and Kozliek were both chosen for the raid. They work well together.</Cell><Cell>米凯什和科兹里克都被选中参加突袭，他们配合默契。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_musim_od_vepre__g5oM</Cell><Cell>I have to find out from Hog what happened with Hynek.</Cell><Cell>我必须从“猪”那里了解海尼克的情况。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_na_vypad_jsem_z_Q62e</Cell><Cell>From my company, I chose Kozliek for the raid.</Cell><Cell>我从部下中选择了科兹里克去参加突袭。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_nikdy_jsem_vdov_NqcL</Cell><Cell>I never told the widow what happened to the remains of her admirer Jan.</Cell><Cell>我从未告诉这位寡妇她的仰慕者扬的遗体发生了什么。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_posvecena_puda__lkc5</Cell><Cell>The graveyard's consecrated earth covered Jan's bones, and his soul will now find redemption. All that's left to do now is talk to the widow Margaret.</Cell><Cell>墓地圣土覆盖了扬的尸骨，他的灵魂现在将得到救赎。现在所要做的就是和寡妇玛格丽特谈谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vdova_marketa_k_d5o4</Cell><Cell>The widow Margaret finally redeemed her sin, because she didn't kill her admirer Jan, but only covered up the truth about his death.</Cell><Cell>寡妇玛格丽特终于赎了罪，因为她没有杀死她的仰慕者扬，只是掩盖了他死亡的真相。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vdova_marketa_m_VWra</Cell><Cell>The widow Margaret told me her secret: an innocent man died because of her. What makes her sin even worse is that the soul of the hermit's brother Jan is not at peace. Margaret never told anyone that her lover killed his rival, Jan, in a duel, and together they covered his tracks. When the young man was found dead with a broken skull at the bottom of a cliff, it was assumed he'd killed himself out of unrequited love. Jan's body was buried outside the graveyard because suicides cannot enter the Kingdom of Heaven.</Cell><Cell>寡妇玛格丽特将她的秘密告诉了我：一个无辜的男人因她而死。隐士的弟弟扬的灵魂不得安宁，这令她的罪孽更加深重。玛格丽特从未告诉过任何人，她的情人在决斗中杀死了对手扬，然后他们一起掩盖了他的踪迹。当这个年轻人的尸体在悬崖下被发现时，头骨已经破碎，人们认为他是因为爱而不得才寻短见。扬的尸体被埋在墓地外，因为自杀者不能进入天国。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vepr_mi_rekl_co_LDUR</Cell><Cell>Hog told me what happened, and that he killed Hynek in a fit of rage. Before he died, Hynek offered him a parchment, I could take a look at it.</Cell><Cell>“猪”将经过告诉我，说自己一怒之下杀了海尼克。海尼克死之前，给了他一张羊皮纸，我可以看一看。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vepr_mi_uz_tezk_ot9w</Cell><Cell>I won't get anything out of Hog now.</Cell><Cell>我现在不能从“猪”那里获得任何东西。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vybral_jsem_na__ChY3</Cell><Cell>I chose Kozliek for the raid. I hope it's the right choice.</Cell><Cell>我选择了科兹里克去突袭。希望这是正确的选择。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_asidovezi_4fPy</Cell><Cell>Builder Johann Parler is working on the Church of Saint Barbara, and he wants to protect the building from fire and lightning with a bit of magic. He couldn't get his hands on a magical talisman or thunderstone anywhere, so he wants me to steal three protective talismans from Kuttenberg burghers, to melt them down, and forge a protective axe out of them to get rid of any evidence.</Cell><Cell>建筑商约翰·帕勒正在修建圣芭芭拉教堂，他想要利用一些魔法来保护教堂免受火灾和雷电的侵害。他无法找到有魔力的护身符或雷石，所以他想让我从库滕堡的市民那里偷取三枚护身符，将它们熔化，然后锻造成一把镇宅斧，以此销毁偷窃的证据。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_dvojityagent_27AM</Cell><Cell>Jan of Suchotlesky has sent me in his name to negotiate the release of his brother, a knight who is held captive in Sigismund's camp.</Cell><Cell>苏霍茨基的扬派我以他之名去谈判，要求释放他的哥哥，后者被囚禁在西格斯蒙德营地。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_kovarskasoutez_iKaI</Cell><Cell>If you ask me, Zdimir the blacksmith boasts about the skills of his apprentice, Matthias, a bit too much. He even suggested we make a bet on who can forge the best hunting sword. The winner gets both weapons and a nice pile of groschen on top.</Cell><Cell>要我说，铁匠兹迪米尔吹嘘了徒弟马蒂亚斯的技能。他甚至建议我们打一个赌，赌谁能锻造出最好的狩猎剑。赢家可以得到这两把武器和一大笔钱。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_po_pytlacke_stezce_sSoi</Cell><Cell>A rare white roebuck was felled by a poacher. Such a thing cannot be left unpunished.</Cell><Cell>一只罕见的白狍子落入了偷猎者手中。偷猎者必须为此受到惩罚。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_tragedienadanemarku_nMsH</Cell><Cell>The Danemark Mill was occupied by a band of cutthroats. They slaughtered the hired hands and took miller Hermann's family captive. </Cell><Cell>一伙强盗抢占了德内马克磨坊，他们还屠杀了那里的工人，并将磨坊主赫尔曼的家人俘虏了。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_zachrana_IRWe</Cell><Cell>Me and Hans Capon managed to flee from the raiders who attacked us at the pond. We found refuge that night with Bozhena, an old herb woman living nearby. She took care of me, but Sir Hans got worse during the night. Now I have to get my strength back and then help Bozhena care for Sir Hans, if at all possible.</Cell><Cell>我和汉斯·卡蓬成功从池塘的偷袭脱身，当晚在附近的老采药女博珍娜家中避难。她对我悉心照料，但汉斯大人的伤情在夜间加重。现在我必须尽可能恢复体力，帮助博珍娜护理汉斯大人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qname_po_pytlacke_stezce_g2sR</Cell><Cell>The White Roebuck</Cell><Cell>白狍子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qname_sq09__mlynaruv_ucen_r6e5</Cell><Cell>Materia Prima</Cell><Cell>原初物质</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qname_tragedienadanemarku_EUNY</Cell><Cell>Tragedy in Danemark</Cell><Cell>德内马克的悲剧</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>quest_can_od_nepovoleneho_gGNk</Cell><Cell>Some time has passed since the unpermitted hunting of the white roebuck and more serious things have begun to happen in the region, so the folks have other things to worry about and no one is offering a reward for the poachers anymore.</Cell><Cell>自非法偷猎白狍子事件以来已经过去了一段时间，而该地区开始发生更严重的问题。人们又多了些需要操心的事，也没人再悬赏追捕偷猎者了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>questfail_jan_ze_suchotle_rqWv</Cell><Cell>Jan of Suchotlesky died before we managed to put an end to this matter. I'll pray for him this evening at least.</Cell><Cell>苏霍茨基的扬在我们了结这件事之前就死了。至少今晚我会为他祈祷。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>reinforce_mikes_s_kozlike_TyTD</Cell><Cell>Mikesh and Kozliek from Zizka's band could come in handy.</Cell><Cell>杰式卡的米凯什和科兹里克可以派上用场。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>reinforce_s_vazounem_a_ve_c5qc</Cell><Cell>I'll feel better with Goliath and Hog by my side.</Cell><Cell>有歌利亚和“猪”在我身边，我感觉更安心。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>reinforce_vazoun_by_se_la_9ODB</Cell><Cell>Goliath and Hog certainly won't be afraid of László. I'll try asking them.</Cell><Cell>歌利亚和“猪”当然不会害怕拉斯洛。我会问问他们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_bitka_u_preda_wfyw</Cell><Cell>László made his bed and now sleeps in it. I think that Jan will recognise me for my aid and that I deserve a reward.</Cell><Cell>拉斯洛自作自受。我想，扬会感激我的援助，并认为我值得奖赏。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_jana_sme_kras_H19N</Cell><Cell>Jan paid for his gullibility and is now with his brother Peter. I hope that László Farkas recognises my help and rewards me as promised.</Cell><Cell>扬为他的轻信付出了代价，现在跟哥哥彼得在黄泉相聚了。我希望拉斯洛·法卡斯能赏识我的帮助，并按承诺给我奖励。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_jan_umrel_nez_qQtV</Cell><Cell>Jan didn't manage to thank me before he died.</Cell><Cell>扬还没来得及感谢我就去世了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_jsem_sice_vsi_5bX6</Cell><Cell>Jan acted honourably and courageously, but still lost in the end. And I profited from it.</Cell><Cell>扬的行为体面而勇敢，但最后还是输了。而我却从中获利。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_s_janem_jsme__AnIW</Cell><Cell>I probably won't get any reward from Jan now. </Cell><Cell>看来现在我无法再向扬获取报酬了。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_vsechno_krasn_GjyV</Cell><Cell>Jan was devastated by the loss of his brother but admitted that without my help, things would have ended much worse.</Cell><Cell>扬为失去哥哥而感到悲痛，但他承认，如果没有我的帮助，事情的结局会更糟糕。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rutinaavy_promluv_si_s_ko_E96O</Cell><Cell>Speak with Kozliek</Cell><Cell>与科兹里克谈谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>s54_trask_poslechni_si_st_5czR</Cell><Cell>Listen to Knuckle's proposal.</Cell><Cell>听取巧指的建议。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_hynek_nelhal_ry_Sdmq</Cell><Cell>The captured knight, Hynek wasn't lying. Sir Peter of Suchotlesky is dead, yet László still wants to get his hands on Jan's money. I could threaten to reveal the truth. Or go straight to Jan…</Cell><Cell>那个被俘的骑士海尼克并没有说谎。苏霍茨基的彼得爵士已经死了，然而拉斯洛仍然想得到扬的钱。我可以威胁说要揭露真相。或者直接去找扬…</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_jan_me_posila_s_gRBP</Cell><Cell>Jan has sent me to negotiate on his behalf with László Farkas. Jan told me nothing more about him, so I'll have to find him myself in Sigismund's camp.</Cell><Cell>扬派我代表他与拉斯洛·法卡斯进行谈判。扬没有告诉我更多关于他的信息，所以我必须亲自到西格斯蒙德营地去找他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_jan_me_poslal_d_4KqX</Cell><Cell>Jan has sent me to Sigismund's camp to negotiate with László Farkas. After asking around a bit, I found out I should look somewhere below the smithy. I hope that doesn't mean half the camp.</Cell><Cell>扬派我去西格斯蒙德的营地找拉斯洛·法卡斯进行谈判。四处打听了一下，线索指向铁匠铺下面的某个地方，希望能好找一点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_moje_podezreni__sxLD</Cell><Cell>I immediately had the feeling something was off. My suspicions were warranted. Sir Peter of Suchotlesky has already met his maker, and here László Farkas is prattling on about a prisoner exchange. I could tell him I know the truth. After all, if Jan finds out what has happened, he won't let it go.</Cell><Cell>一股不祥的预感瞬间生起。我怀疑得没错。苏霍茨基的彼得爵士已经去见了上帝，而拉斯洛·法卡斯却在这里喋喋不休地谈论交换囚犯的事情。我可以告诉他我知道真相。毕竟，如果扬知道了这件事，他不会善罢甘休。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_p_s_laszlem_jse_jjXT</Cell><Cell>I negotiated the terms of the captive's release and went to inform Jan. I didn't see Peter in the camp. László says he'll take him to the agreed-upon place for the handover.</Cell><Cell>我谈好了释放俘虏的条件，然后去通知扬。 我在营地里没有看到彼得。拉斯洛说他会带他到约定的地点进行交接。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>setkanivr_plc_hodor_plumm_s7Zp</Cell><Cell>Bring the confiscated goblet to Bailiff Plumel.</Cell><Cell>将被执行官普卢梅尔没收的高脚杯交给他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_dam_krejzl_neprekva_0XVu</Cell><Cell>Unsurprisingly, Kreyzl came up with a complicated plan. We'll find an ordinary wench from the Zhelejov baths, the miller will give her some fine clothes and perfume and take her to the Semine wedding. There we'll dangle her in front of Ulrich, the Trosky chamberlain. If he takes the bait, the wench, posing as a lady, will be invited to his chambers at Trosky and I, as her bodyguard, will have time to myself in the castle, ideally to spend looking for the book. But above all, this plan will finally get me to von Bergow. Now I just have to talk to Dorothy from the bathhouse and find out which of the wenches will be keen to attend the biggest celebration in the region. </Cell><Cell>不出所料，克雷泽想出了一个复杂的计划。我们要在哲勒约夫澡堂找一位普通的女人，磨坊主会给她一些漂亮衣服和香水，然后带她去塞米的婚礼。然后我们就把她留在特罗斯基的管家，也就是乌尔里希眼前。如果他上钩了，这位冒充淑女的女人，就会被邀请前去他在特罗斯基的房间。而我，身为她的保镖，就可以在城堡里自由行动，最好是把时间用在找那本书上。但最重要的是，这个计划最终会让我找到冯·波尔高那里。现在，我只需要和澡堂的多萝西聊聊，然后看看哪个女人愿意参加这个地区最盛大的庆典。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_dam_krejzl_neprekva_oNWE</Cell><Cell>Unsurprisingly, Kreyzl came up with a complicated plan. We'd have to find an ordinary wench from the Zhelejov baths, the miller would give her some fine clothes and perfume and take her to the Semine wedding. There he'd parade her in front of Ulrich, the Trosky chamberlain. If he took the bait, the wench, posing as a lady, would be invited to his chambers at Trosky and I, as her bodyguard, would have time to myself in the castle, ideally to spend looking for the book. But above all, this plan would finally get me to von Bergow. I talked to Dorothy from the bathhouse and found out that the wenches have had bad experiences with the chamberlain and don't want anything to do with him. Luckily, I was recommended a woman called Enneleyn of Wintherthur, who isn't afraid of the deviant chamberlain. </Cell><Cell>不出所料，克雷泽想出了一个复杂的计划。我们要在哲勒约夫澡堂找一位普通的女人，磨坊主会给她一些漂亮衣服和香水，然后带她去塞米的婚礼。然后他就把她留在特罗斯基的管家，也就是乌尔里希眼前。如果他上钩了，这位冒充淑女的女人，就会被邀请前去他在特罗斯基的房间。而我，身为她的保镖，就可以在城堡里自由行动，最好是把时间用在找那本书上。但最重要的是，这个计划最终会让我找到冯·波尔高那里。我和澡堂的多萝西聊过了，发现那些女人和总管有过不愉快的过往，因此不想和他有任何瓜葛。幸运的是，有人向我推荐了一位女士——温特图尔的恩内琳，她不怕那位变态管家。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_dobry_skutek_ne_Pzzk</Cell><Cell>A good deed never offends and at least I got into Peltzel's good books.</Cell><Cell>种善因，结善果，至少我给佩尔泽尔留下了好印象。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_krejzl_nechtel__MCg4</Cell><Cell>Not wanting to leave anything to chance, Kreyzl knows exactly the kind of dress he wants to turn the chamberlain's head. I got hold of a red cotehardie of Tyrolean brocade, of course.</Cell><Cell>克雷泽希望事情万无一失，他很清楚要弄来什么样的衣服才能让管家眼前一亮。当然，我弄来了一件蒂罗尔锦缎制成的贴身红裙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_pelcl_ma_staros_LFtv</Cell><Cell>Peltzel is worried about the departure. He needs to shoe three remaining horses with new horseshoes. It would help if I brought the horseshoes for them.</Cell><Cell>佩尔泽尔对启程一事稍有担忧。他现在需要给剩余的三只马换上新的马蹄铁，如果我能够弄到马蹄铁，就能帮到他们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_podkovy_pro_pel_9Qg5</Cell><Cell>I didn't get the horseshoes for Peltzel, so I'm not in his good books.</Cell><Cell>我没有为佩尔泽尔取得马蹄铁，所以他不看好我。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_prinest_vino_vl_bsRq</Cell><Cell>Enneleyn doesn't want anything left to chance, so she'll mix a sleeping potion into some wine for the chamberlain. As she's using her own supplies of the potion for our plan, maybe I could bring her some wine as a gift. Maybe she could use it to boost her courage before the wedding.</Cell><Cell>恩内琳希望事情万无一失，所以她会在给管家的酒里加入安眠药水。既然她要用自己的东西完成我们的计划，或许我可以给她带些酒做礼物，这样她可以在婚礼前喝点来壮胆。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>starymistr_promluv_si_s_v_0XfY</Cell><Cell>Find out from Hog what happened.</Cell><Cell>向“猪”了解情况。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>starymistr_znovu_si_proml_3hZj</Cell><Cell>Talk to Hog again.</Cell><Cell>再和“猪”谈谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>talktobal_konflikt_s_mist_EXgR</Cell><Cell>Conflict with the local riffraff was averted. Now I need to decide with Jan on how to move forward.</Cell><Cell>与当地暴徒的冲突得以避免。现在我需要和扬一起决定后续行动。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>talktobal_po_zazehnani_ko_czCr</Cell><Cell>Having averted the conflict with the looters, Jan and I decided on our next move. Tracking the band of Cumans won't be difficult.</Cell><Cell>在避免了与劫掠者的冲突之后，扬和我决定了我们的下一步行动。追踪库曼人的队伍并不困难。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>talktobal_po_zazehnani_ko_GUVB</Cell><Cell>Having averted the conflict with the looters, Jan and I have yet to discuss our next move. That's because I went away, bringing our quest to an unsuccessful finish.</Cell><Cell>在避免了与劫掠者的冲突之后，扬和我还没有讨论我们的下一步行动。因为我离开了，我们的探险以失败告终。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>taras_mura_finaltalkvilla_92Ug</Cell><Cell>Talk to Father Marian.</Cell><Cell>和神父马里安交谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanla_jana_mrzelo_ze__cFTY</Cell><Cell>Jan regretted not getting his brother's body back, but he was glad that László got what he deserved…</Cell><Cell>没有拿回哥哥的尸体，扬感到遗憾，但他很高兴拉斯洛得到了报应......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanla_mel_bych_zajit__gBT3</Cell><Cell>I should go to Jan and tell him about László.</Cell><Cell>我应该去找扬，将拉斯洛的事告诉他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_jan_hodla_pro_s_m8x0</Cell><Cell>Jan is willing to risk his life for his brother Peter. But I serve the Lords of Leipa... The Lords of Suchotlesky will have to manage without me.</Cell><Cell>扬甘愿为了他的兄弟彼得赌上性命。但我在为莱佩的领主效力……苏霍茨基的领主们只能自己想办法处理问题了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_kdyz_jsem_rekl__9gl8</Cell><Cell>When I told Jan about his brother's death, he cursed László and his whole damned family. He has now sworn himself to avenging Peter. But we need more men for that…</Cell><Cell>当我告诉扬他哥哥的死讯时，他诅咒了拉斯洛和他整个该死的家族。他现在发誓要为彼得报仇。但要复仇，我们需要更多的人......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_kdyz_se_jan_dov_yj68</Cell><Cell>When Jan heard about his brother's death, he was devastated. The news about the impending attack was the final drop. Taking to heart the adage 'the best defence is a good offense', he told me to get ready for combat and find a few experienced warriors to accompany us to the handover site.</Cell><Cell>当听说自己哥哥的死讯时，扬大受打击。最后的一击，是即将发生的袭击。他牢记“最佳防御是一种良好的进攻”这句格言，让我做好战斗准备，找几个有经验的战士陪同我们去交接地点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_misto_predani_a_42OF</Cell><Cell>Jan was surprised by where the handover was to take place and the ransom amount, but he says the blood of kin can't be counted in coin. He also regretted that I hadn't seen Peter, but understood that in our situation I couldn't be giving orders. I should prepare for departure.</Cell><Cell>扬对交接地点和赎金数额感到惊讶，但他说亲人不能用钱币衡量。我没有见到彼得，他对此感到遗憾，但他明白，鉴于我们的情况，当时的我不可能发号施令。我应该准备出发了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_p_mrtvy_petr_na_mPRO</Cell><Cell>Jan, informed of Peter's death, still sent me back to the camp to negotiate the handover of the captive.</Cell><Cell>扬在得知彼得的死讯后，仍然派我回到营地，商谈俘虏的交接......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_povedel_jsem_ja_DGAF</Cell><Cell>I told Jan everything about the conditions of the handover, but kept the truth about Peter to myself, instead assuring him that everything would go smoothly. Now we must go to the handover location.</Cell><Cell>我把交接条件全部告诉了扬，但隐瞒了有关彼得的真相，向他保证一切会顺利进行。现在我们必须去交接地点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_p_sice_jsem_jan_mNxt</Cell><Cell>At first, I lied a bit to Jan, but then it began to gnaw on me. In the end, I admitted everything and told him the truth about Peter. Jan, understanding the situation, decided to exact revenge upon Farkas.</Cell><Cell>起初，我对扬撒了谎，但后来我于心不忍。最后，我承认了一切，将有关彼得的真相告诉了他。扬了解情况后，决定对法卡斯进行报复......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_p_vzhledem_k_ok_A7Kj</Cell><Cell>Given the circumstances, there's no use in talking over the outcomes of the negotiations with Jan.</Cell><Cell>鉴于这种情况，跟扬谈论谈判的结果没有意义。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_vyjednal_jsem_v_KY0b</Cell><Cell>I've negotiated everything I need to in the camp. I must now return to Jan and prepare for the handover.</Cell><Cell>我已经在营地里进行了所有必要的谈判。我现在必须回到扬身边，为交接做准备。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tmp_poraz_abych_byl_konec_PPEB</Cell><Cell>In order to finally be recognised as the winner of the blacksmithing competition, I have to defeat Matthias in a duel with the hunting sword I forged.</Cell><Cell>为了最终在锻造比赛中获胜，我必须在决斗中用自己锻造的狩猎剑击败马蒂亚斯。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tmp_setke_mam_jit_do_tabo_RVPP</Cell><Cell>They must have noticed we're gone, because the forest is swarming with soldiers looking for us! It seems Katherine's ally Mika is waiting for us with a wagon in some abandoned camp south of here, but Zizka's in a really bad way! I’ll go and find him and tell him what happened. But I have to be careful no soldiers see me. That would be the end.</Cell><Cell>我们逃跑的事情一定是败露了，因为树林里到处都是搜捕我们的士兵！凯瑟琳的朋友米卡，似乎就在南边某个废弃的营地，备好了马车等着我们，可是现在杰式卡的处境很糟糕！我得找到他，并告诉他发生了什么。但是我得小心，不能让士兵们发现我，万一被逮到就全完了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tmp_setke_stretl_jsem_bor_VoJ8</Cell><Cell>Our absence must have been discovered, because the forest is swarming with soldiers looking for us! It seems Katherine's ally Mika is waiting for us with a wagon in some abandoned camp south of here, but Zizka's in a really bad way! I’ll go and find him and tell him what happened.</Cell><Cell>我们逃跑的事情一定是败露了，因为树林里到处都是搜捕我们的士兵！凯瑟琳的朋友米卡，似乎就在南边某个废弃的营地，备好了马车等着我们，可是现在杰式卡的处境很糟糕！我得找到他，并告诉他发生了什么。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tragedien_postarej_se_o_l_NeZ6</Cell><Cell>Take care of the bandits at Danemark.</Cell><Cell>解决德内马克的强盗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_hunting_spot_roe_deer</Cell><Cell>Roe hunting spot</Cell><Cell>猎狍地点</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_hunting_spot_wolf</Cell><Cell>Wolf hunting spot</Cell><Cell>猎狼地点</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_laundry</Cell><Cell>Laundry</Cell><Cell>洗衣点</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_saddler</Cell><Cell>Saddler</Cell><Cell>鞍匠</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>utok_vesnice_horela_a_my__PctG</Cell><Cell>There was a large garrison at Maleshov that we managed to draw out of the fortress to extinguish the fire we'd set. Von Bergow's mercenaries assumed that a horrible fire had broken out in the village and didn't expect an enemy raid on the royal chamberlain's seat. The village was burning, and we gained the upper hand.</Cell><Cell>我们成功引出了马列索夫的大批守卫，让他们前去扑火。冯·波尔高的士兵们皆以为那不过是村庄意外失火，也未曾料到他们的敌人将突袭皇家总管的领地。烈火之下，我们占据了上风。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vezninatr_dojdi_na_konec__qO96</Cell><Cell>Accompany Zizka, Katherine and Godwin to the end of the passageway.</Cell><Cell>陪杰式卡、凯瑟琳、古德温一起走出密道。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vloz_osta_splnil_jsem_o_c_iwns</Cell><Cell>I did what the widow asked of me, exactly as the old hermit prophesied. The widow Margaret's sins were forgiven and Jan's soul finally found peace.</Cell><Cell>正如老隐士预言的那样，我做了寡妇要求我做的事。寡妇玛格丽特的罪孽得到了宽恕，而扬的灵魂也最终得到安宁。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vloz_osta_zbyva_posledni__4Hkq</Cell><Cell>All that's left to do is lay Jan's bones in the graveyard's consecrated ground where they belong.</Cell><Cell>剩下要做的就是把扬的遗骨安葬在墓地圣土上，那才是它们的归宿。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vrat_se_z_mel_bych_rict_m_K3N3</Cell><Cell>I should tell miller Hermann that I've rid Danemark of a dangerous gang of bandits.</Cell><Cell>我得告诉磨坊主赫尔曼，我已让德内马克磨坊摆脱了一群凶恶强盗的控制。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vrat_se_z_mlynar_herman_n_mnJK</Cell><Cell>Miller Hermann never got his mill in Danemark back.</Cell><Cell>磨坊主赫尔曼没能夺回他在德内马克的磨坊。</Cell></Row>
I was also given a tournament waffenrock and I'm expected to wear it during my duels but I reckon I could also wear a different one.</Cell><Cell>我需要一把比武长剑。
至于护甲，我得穿上一件比武软甲，但不可穿戴任何铁甲、锁甲以及头盔。因此，我得格外小心。
至于护甲，我得穿上一件比武软甲，一只比武衬垫头巾以及一顶比武头盔，但不可穿戴任何铁甲或锁甲。
至于护甲，我得穿上一件比武软甲，一只比武衬垫头巾以及一顶比武头盔，但不可穿戴任何铁甲或锁甲。
<Row><Cell>vykopej_h_pokud_chci_vdov_FpIK</Cell><Cell>If I'm going to help the widow, I have to dig a grave in consecrated ground and lay Jan's remains to rest here.</Cell><Cell>如果我要帮助这个寡妇，我必须在圣土上挖一个坟墓，将扬的遗体安葬在这里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vykovej_s_abych_mateje_po_lNAu</Cell><Cell>To beat Matthias, I have to forge a better hunting sword than him. </Cell><Cell>要打败马蒂亚斯，我必须锻造一把胜过他的狩猎剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vykovej_s_donesl_jsem_kut_0YiC</Cell><Cell>I forged an axe for Johann Parler.</Cell><Cell>我为约翰·帕勒锻造了一把斧头。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vykovej_s_tesak_jsem_vyko_LqhE</Cell><Cell>I forged a hunting sword, now I have to hope it will be better than Matthias'.</Cell><Cell>我锻造了一把狩猎剑，只希望它能胜过马蒂亚斯锻造的狩猎剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vykovej_s_ze_tri_udajne_k_cRNf</Cell><Cell>I'm supposed to forge an axe out of the three supposedly magical talismans Johann had me steal, so that nobody knows we took them.</Cell><Cell>我得用约翰让我偷走的那三枚据说拥有魔力的护身符去锻造一把斧头，这样就没有人知道它们被我们偷走了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__dle_otce_prokop_rXWA</Cell><Cell>According to Father Prokop, Jarka was a kind girl who served the local von Grolle family. Father Prokop feels responsible, but mainly blames a wandering minstrel named William.</Cell><Cell>通过与普罗科普神父了解得知，贾卡生前是个好姑娘，还曾服侍过冯·格罗尔一家。尽管心怀愧疚，但神父普罗科普还是将贾卡的死怪罪到了一位叫威廉的吟游诗人头上。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__jarka_nejstarsi_c3Oh</Cell><Cell>Jarka, the oldest victim of the mad murderer, was the ward of a local priest, Father Prokop. It shouldn't be too hard to track him down and talk to him about Jarka and her condition before the murder.</Cell><Cell>贾卡是头几位惨遭疯狂杀手谋害的姑娘，同时也是当地牧师普罗科普神父的养女。要想找到这位神父并与他谈论贾卡及其生前境况并非难事。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__nepodarilo_se_m_KLSW</Cell><Cell>I didn't manage to learn anything more from Father Prokop about the life and death of his ward Jarka, and so the investigation has hit a dead end. Just like Father Prokop.</Cell><Cell>我没能向普罗科普神父打探到任何与其养女贾卡生死相关的信息。正如一命呜呼的神父，案件调查的进展也因此被中断。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__podarilo_se_mi__3ykB</Cell><Cell>I managed to glean from Father Prokop that Jarka was pregnant, so it was a double murder. Perhaps the father of the child wanted to silence the mother before she disgraced  him?</Cell><Cell>通过向普罗科普神父了解得知，当时的贾卡已经怀有身孕，因此那凶手实际上害死了两条人命。难道是孩子父亲担忧名誉扫地，才杀害了贾卡？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_jana_planovane_miro_UA1T</Cell><Cell>The idea of a peaceful handover was a naive one. First an argument broke out that soon grew into a fight. I had to make a quick decision. Jan might be honourable, but he's also naive, dangerously so. There is a war on, and in war, it's the strong that win. And Baron Farkas is strong. I'm not proud of it, but he offered a better deal. At least Jan is with Peter now.</Cell><Cell>和平交接的想法太过天真。双方先是发生了争执，很快就发展成争斗。我不得不迅速做出决定。扬可能品格高尚，但他也很天真，这很危险。现在一场战争正在进行，而在战争中，强者才能获胜。而法卡斯男爵是强者。这事虽并不光彩，但他给出的条件更好。至少扬现在和彼得在一起了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_jana_planovane_miro_uIWj</Cell><Cell>The idea of a peaceful handover was a naive one. First an argument broke out that soon grew into a fight. I had to make a quick decision. Jan might be honourable, but he's also naive, dangerously so. There is a war on, and in war, it's the strong that win. And Baron Farkas is strong. </Cell><Cell>和平交接的想法太过天真。双方先是发生了争执，很快就发展成争斗。我不得不迅速做出决定。扬可能品格高尚，但他也很天真，这很危险。现在一场战争正在进行，而在战争中，强者才能获胜。而法卡斯男爵是强者。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_pro_dle_dlouhe_deba_Z3QR</Cell><Cell>After much debate and argument we decided that Father Prokop was the murderer. I then killed him and hopefully stopped his murderous rampage.</Cell><Cell>经过费尽心力的探究与讨论后，我们断定是普罗科普神父就是杀人凶手。随后我便将其杀死，只愿能以此终结他的屠杀行径。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_pro_dle_nasi_dlouhe_CvDv</Cell><Cell>After a long debate in which we concluded Father Prokop was the murderer, I just couldn't bring myself to kill the old man. I didn't want to have that on my conscience. </Cell><Cell>经过了漫长的探讨，我们得出了普罗科普神父就是凶手的结论，但是并不想让自己良心不安的我，无法下手杀死一位年迈的老者。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_pro_dohodli_jsme_se_LGRP</Cell><Cell>We agreed that Father Prokop was the murderer and that we needed to kill him to stop his murderous rampage.</Cell><Cell>我们都认为普罗科普神父就是杀人凶手，为阻止他惨无人道的屠杀行为，我们必须把他杀死。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zeptej_se_bozena_mi_porad_zTA0</Cell><Cell>Bozhena told me where I could find the Cumans. They're camping near the pond where the nomads are.</Cell><Cell>博珍娜告诉我库曼人的位置。他们在池塘边扎营，和游牧民族待在一起。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zeptej_se_lovci_dobros_se_ZRVo</Cell><Cell>Huntsman Dobrosh mentioned that Wolfram the knacker used to do some business with the poachers. The knacker wasn't involved in killing the roebuck, but at least he had an idea where the poachers might be hiding.</Cell><Cell>猎人多布罗什提到了屠夫沃尔夫勒姆曾经和偷猎者做过交易。那个屠夫没有参与猎杀白狍子，但至少他知道偷猎者可能藏在何处。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zeptej_se_lovci_tibor_mi__IsR2</Cell><Cell>Natan told me where to find the Cumans. They're camping near the pond where the nomads are.</Cell><Cell>纳坦告诉我库曼人的位置。他们在池塘边扎营，和游牧民族待在一起。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_os_nasel_jsem_jano_AuNY</Cell><Cell>I've found Jan's remains. Thirty years on, all that's left is yellowed bones and a skull with a clump of red hair. No coffin - they simply wrapped him in a shroud and the worms soon got to work on him.</Cell><Cell>我找到了扬的遗体。三十年过去了，只剩下发黄的骨头和长着一丛红发的头骨。没有棺材——他们只给他用了裹尸布，虫子很快就啃噬了他的身体。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_os_za_hrbitovni_zd_z8VG</Cell><Cell>Apparently, there's a spot by the graveyard wall where Jan's body is buried. Finding and moving all the bones into the sacred ground of the graveyard will be dirty work.</Cell><Cell>显然，扬的尸体埋在墓地墙边某处。找到所有遗骨，并将它们移到墓地圣土，将是个脏活。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_zp_krejcikova_podk_rqwF</Cell><Cell>The tailor's horseshoe was mine, but I lost it. Without it, I won't be able to forge that axe for Parler.</Cell><Cell>我拿到了裁缝的马蹄铁却把它弄丢了。没有马蹄铁，我就没法为帕勒锻造斧头了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_zp_uz_jsem_drzel_p_Ooo0</Cell><Cell>I had the coin in my hand, but I lost it. I have to find it quickly.</Cell><Cell>我拿到了硬币，但是弄丢了。我得快点把它找回来。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zjisti_vo_krejzl_puvodne__gEGO</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl originally meant to get the book through the Trosky chamberlain at the Semine wedding, but he wasn't able to arrange it. The castle was still closed off at the time. But now he knows me, and I have near unlimited access to the castle, making the whole situation a lot simpler. I found Erazim the scribe at the castle and asked him where the book is. He gave me a few names, the most important of which is Nikvard Libak. </Cell><Cell>克雷泽原本想在塞米的婚礼上通过特罗斯基的管家拿到那本书，但他的安排出了差错。那时候的城堡还处于关闭中。但现在他认识了我，我几乎可以不受限制地进出城堡，这就让整件事简单多了。我在城堡这儿找到了特罗斯基的抄写员埃拉兹姆，并问了他书在哪里。他告诉了我几个名字，其中最重要的一位叫尼克瓦德·利巴克。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zjisti_vo_krejzl_puvodne__hroH</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl originally meant to get the book through the Trosky chamberlain at the Semine wedding, but he wasn't able to arrange it. The castle was still closed off at the time. But now he knows me, and I have near unlimited access to the castle, making the whole situation a lot simpler. Now I just have to go to the castle writing room and talk Erazim the scribe. He should know where the book is.</Cell><Cell>克雷泽原本想在塞米的婚礼上通过特罗斯基的管家拿到那本书，但他的安排出了差错。那时候的城堡还处于关闭中。但现在他认识了我，我几乎可以不受限制地进出城堡，这就让整件事简单多了。现在我只需要去城堡的抄写室，和抄写员埃拉兹姆聊聊。他应该知道书在哪里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>znovu_si__musim_si_promlu_T5kU</Cell><Cell>I have to talk to Hog about the parchment's contents.</Cell><Cell>我必须和“猪”谈谈羊皮纸上的内容。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>znovu_si__s_veprem_si_uz__Ffpn</Cell><Cell>I don't think I'll be talking to Hog again.</Cell><Cell>我想我不会再搭理“猪”。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>znovu_si__vepr_mi_neprimo_cowJ</Cell><Cell>Hog didn't give me much advice on where I should start my search for the thieves' hideout.</Cell><Cell>至于该从何处开始寻找那些盗贼的藏身处，“猪”并没有给我提供太多建议。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zucastni__vsadil_jsem_se__09j1</Cell><Cell>I made a bet with the master blacksmith Zdimir that I could forge a better hunting sword than his apprentice Matthias. If I succeed, I'll not only get some money, but also Matthias's weapon.</Cell><Cell>我和铁匠大师兹迪米尔打了个赌，赌我能比他的徒弟马蒂亚斯锻造更好的狩猎剑。如果我赢了，我不仅可以得到一些钱，还可以得到马蒂亚斯的武器。</Cell></Row>
</Table>
