<Table>
<Row><Cell>amuletfor_p_promluil_jsem_dFQ0</Cell><Cell>I found Marika, the daughter of the nomads' Voivode, in a cave hideout in Apollonia. She needs his magic amulet, but the Voivode won't give it up.</Cell><Cell>我在阿波罗尼亚的一处隐蔽洞穴内找到了游牧民司令官的女儿玛丽卡。玛丽卡想要得到司令官的魔法护符，但是后者并不打算拱手相让。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>amuletfor_p_rekni_si_u_va_24hc</Cell><Cell>The Voivode has an amulet with him, which is said to be endowed with magical powers that protect the wearer from all illnesses and troubles. Marika wants to get the amulet.</Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官有一枚护身符，据说这枚护符被赋予了神秘的能量，能保护佩戴者免于病痛与灾祸，玛丽卡想要得到那枚护符。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>amuletfor_p_vajda_amulet__Mzmh</Cell><Cell>I found Marika, the daughter of the nomads' Voivode, in a cave hideout in Apollonia. She needs his magic amulet, but the Voivode won't give it up.</Cell><Cell>我在阿波罗尼亚的一处隐蔽洞穴内找到了游牧民司令官的女儿玛丽卡。玛丽卡想要得到司令官的魔法护符，但是后者并不打算拱手相让。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>amuletfor_p_vajda_nosi_am_DIYS</Cell><Cell>The Voivode wears an amulet, which is said to be endowed with magical powers that protect the wearer from all illnesses and troubles. Marika wanted to get the amulet to help Bohush.</Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官佩戴着一枚护身符，据说这枚护符被赋予了神秘的能量，能保护佩戴者免于病痛与灾祸。玛丽卡想要得到那枚护符，以此帮助博胡什。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>amuletfor_p_vajda_odmita__qbI2</Cell><Cell>The Voivode doesn't want to give up the amulet, I suppose I'll have to find some other way. I'll try to talk to some of his family, maybe they could think of something.</Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官并不想放弃那枚护符，看来我得想想别的办法了。我该试着跟他的其他家人谈谈，或许他们会有主意。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>asidovezi_ukradni_minci_z_ClE2</Cell><Cell>Steal the coin from the building's foundation.</Cell><Cell>偷走酒馆地窖里的硬币。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>azzahrob_dones_pecetidlo__dueJ</Cell><Cell>Take the seal to Rat</Cell><Cell>将印章交给“老鼠”</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>barnabas__trosecky_zapasn_H1CM</Cell><Cell>The Trosky fighting grandmaster is dead. May God rest his soul.</Cell><Cell>特罗斯基的那位大师已然与世长辞，愿上帝让他的灵魂安息。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>betcontes_abych_vyhral_sa_iu5l</Cell><Cell>Aranka wants to help me win the bet with a herbal decoction to drug Tibor's horse, Dzar. </Cell><Cell>阿兰卡想帮我赢下赌局，她打算用一种草本药剂给提波的马下药，那匹马叫德扎尔。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>bez_s_kum_nabidl_jsem_se__4GdQ</Cell><Cell>I offered to help interpret for the Cuman, Jasak, in the nomads' camp. He'd like to confess his love to one of their women. I should go with him so he can show me which one he means.</Cell><Cell>我提出帮库曼人贾萨克在游牧民营地里做翻译。他想和他们族的一个女人表白，我要跟他一起去，看看他喜欢哪个。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>bez_s_kum_snazil_jsem_se__nMnE</Cell><Cell>I followed Jasak to the nomads' camp, and he showed me the woman he's interested in.</Cell><Cell>我跟着贾萨克到了游牧民营地，见到了他喜欢的那个女人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>bitvazabo_obsad_hradbu_a__n0Up</Cell><Cell>Knock down the ladder!</Cell><Cell>推倒梯子！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>burygejza_vajduv_syn_gejz_NezR</Cell><Cell>The Voivode's son Gejza died fighting the villagers. The Voivode and his wife Aranka want me to take care of him and bury him properly.</Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官的儿子盖萨在与村民的冲突中死亡，司令官和他的妻子阿兰卡请求我将其安葬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_laszlo_mi_nabid_MXNy</Cell><Cell>László made me an offer. If I help him conspire against Jan, I'll receive the dead Peter's equipment. Politely but clearly, I turned him down. I have my honour, after all. The handover will still take place, so that Jan can properly bury his brother. I hope László doesn't cause any more problems.</Cell><Cell>拉斯洛提出一个条件。如果我帮助他密谋反对扬，我将得到死去彼得的装备。我礼貌而明确地拒绝了他。我毕竟要维护自己的荣誉。交接还是要进行，这样扬就可以安葬他的哥哥。我希望拉斯洛不会再制造任何麻烦。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_laszlo_mi_nabid_Zanm</Cell><Cell>László made me an offer. If I help him conspire against Jan, he'll provide me with such equipment that many a knight could only dream about. Sounds interesting, but I don't like the idea of joining up with his Cumans. </Cell><Cell>拉斯洛向我提出了一个条件。如果我帮助他密谋对付扬，他将为我提供许多骑士梦寐以求的装备。听起来很有意思，但我不想与他的库曼人联手。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_p_kdyz_jsem_zji_l9or</Cell><Cell>When I learned that Peter was dead, I knew that László wasn't playing fair with Jan. But that's all I learned.</Cell><Cell>当我得知彼得死了，我知道拉斯洛对扬使了诈，但我就知道这么多。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_p_naoko_jsem_la_mTFg</Cell><Cell>I lied to László, telling him I would betray Jan and lead him into a trap. If I tell Jan about these plans in time, we can think up a way to protect ourselves.</Cell><Cell>我对拉斯洛撒了谎，告诉他我会背叛扬，把他引入陷阱。如果我把这些计划及时告诉扬，我们可以想出一个保护自己的办法。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>confrontl_p_oboril_jsem_s_aerd</Cell><Cell>I told László that I know what happened to Peter. He responded that Jan will want his body back to bury it. So a handover should take place in any case.</Cell><Cell>我告诉拉斯洛，我知道彼得发生了什么。他回答说，扬会希望要回尸体埋葬。所以无论如何都应该进行交接。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>councilman_konsel_je_na_n_O6WM</Cell><Cell>I fought a duel of honour on Tuchmacher's behalf against Jan of Lesztin. I won, and Tuchmacher promised me he'd support the Kingfisher baths in the council vote.</Cell><Cell>我代表图赫马赫进行了一场荣誉决斗，在这场与列斯汀的扬的较量中，我成功胜出。图赫马赫也因此向我承诺，他将在市议会投票时向翠鸟澡堂提供他的支持。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crosscoun_jed_do_cile_ejnf</Cell><Cell>Head for the finish!</Cell><Cell>Head for the finish!</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crosscoun_projed_branu1_XxKu</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint near Semine.</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint near Semine.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crosscoun_projed_branu2_URjD</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint in Sdiar.</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint in Sdiar.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crosscoun_projed_branu3_uaby</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint in Slatego.</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint in Slatego.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crosscoun_projed_branu4_ogBc</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint on the bridge.</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint on the bridge.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crosscoun_projed_branu5_Jt0C</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint near Troskovitz.</Cell><Cell>Pass the checkpoint near Troskovitz.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crosscoun_promluv_s_mikol_Tr0w</Cell><Cell>Speak to Mikolai about the results.</Cell><Cell>Speak to Mikolai about the results.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>crouch_v_rybniku_nejsme_s_WDZu</Cell><Cell>Me and Sir Hans are not alone in the pond. A little further along by the banks there are some girls bathing, and Sir Hans, gentleman that he is, wants to go and spy on them. We'll have to keep our heads down in the reeds, otherwise we'll cause a stir.</Cell><Cell>光顾这片池塘的，不止我和汉斯少主。沿岸稍远处有群姑娘在洗澡。汉斯少主一展绅士风度，欲要上前窥探。我们得在芦苇丛中藏好，不然麻烦就大了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>defeatjan_p_laszlo_padl_v_V3ul</Cell><Cell>Everything that could go wrong did go wrong. Sir Peter is dead, Jan of Suchotlesky is dead, and so too is Baron Farkas. No one gained anything from it all. There was no winner…</Cell><Cell>满盘皆输。彼得爵士死了，苏霍茨基的扬也死了，法卡斯男爵也死了。没有人从中获利。没有赢家……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>defeatlas_p_jan_padl_v_bo_oQHZ</Cell><Cell>Unfortunately, Jan did not survive his second encounter with László's Cumans. But at least he's now with his brother. May the earth rest lightly on them.</Cell><Cell>不幸的是，与拉斯洛的库曼人进行第二次对抗时，扬没有幸存下来。但至少他现在和哥哥在一起了。愿他们安息。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>deliverof_knez_marian_ves_0zKe</Cell><Cell>Father Marian doesn't believe in the local legend about a gateway to hell in the abandoned mines near Old Kutna. Nevertheless, he hired me to look into it to put a stop to the rumours. He gave me some food to prepare as an offering for demons in the mines. We'll see who really comes to pick it up.</Cell><Cell>当地传说称老库特纳附近的废弃矿场有一个通往地狱的通道，神父马里安并不相信。尽管如此，他还是雇我去调查，以终止谣言。他给了我一些食物，用来献祭矿井里的恶魔。我们可以看看究竟是谁会来拿走这些东西。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>deliverof_knez_marian_ves_hL9O</Cell><Cell>Father Marian doesn't believe in the local legend about a gateway to hell in the abandoned mines near Old Kutna. Nevertheless, he hired me to look into it to put a stop to the rumours. He gave me some supplies to lower into the mine. That will no longer be possible, since the locals were stricken by an unforseeable event...</Cell><Cell>当地传说称老库特纳附近的废弃矿场有一个通往地狱的通道，神父马里安并不相信。尽管如此，他还是雇我去调查，以终止谣言。他给了我一些物资，让我下放到矿井。这将不再可能实施，因为当地人被一个不可预知的事件所困扰......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>deliverof_knez_marian_ves_y2gR</Cell><Cell>Father Marian doesn't believe in the local legend about a gateway to hell in the abandoned mines near Old Kutna. Nevertheless, he hired me to look into it to put a stop to the rumours. He gave me some supplies and I lowered them into the mine. But what I lured out were no demons. Or were they?</Cell><Cell>当地传说称老库特纳附近的废弃矿场有一个通往地狱的通道，神父马里安并不相信。尽管如此，他还是雇我去调查，以终止谣言。他给了我一些物资，我把它们下放到矿井。但我引出来的东西究竟是不是恶魔，我心里也没数。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_nakonec_jsem_ce_GOA1</Cell><Cell>In the end, I brought Gules Canker's mace as proof.</Cell><Cell>最后，我把“溃疡”的钉头锤交给了古勒斯作为证据。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_podarilo_se_mi__pmhU</Cell><Cell>I managed to deceive Gules into thinking that Canker is dead when I brought him his mace.</Cell><Cell>我把钉头锤带给了古勒斯，假称“溃疡”已经死了，成功骗过了他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_ted_uz_mi_staci_nTCL</Cell><Cell>Now all I have to do is pick up Canker's mace and bring it as proof to Gules.</Cell><Cell>现在我只需要捡走“溃疡”的钉头锤，将其作为证据交给古勒斯就可以了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_cev_ted_uz_mi_staci_SNKq</Cell><Cell>Now all I have to do is bring Canker's mace as proof to Gules.</Cell><Cell>现在我只需要把“溃疡”的钉头锤作为证据交给古勒斯就可以了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_enn_prinest_vino_vl_uIbm</Cell><Cell>Enneleyn doesn't want anything left to chance, so she'll mix sleeping potion into some wine for the chamberlain. I brought her some wine as a gift. At the very least, she'll be able to fortify herself before the wedding.</Cell><Cell>恩内琳希望事情万无一失，所以她会在给管家的酒里加入安眠药水。于是我决定给她带些酒，这样她可以在婚礼前喝点来壮胆。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_enn_prinest_vino_vl_ZExG</Cell><Cell>Enneleyn didn't want anything left to chance, so she mixed sleeping potion into some wine for the chamberlain. Since she used her own supply of the potion for our sakes, I at least brought her some wine as a gift.</Cell><Cell>恩内琳希望事情万无一失，所以她在给管家的酒里加入了安眠药水。既然她要用自己的东西完成我们的计划，我决定给她带些酒做为礼物。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_jan_janek_je_mrtvy__mA5j</Cell><Cell>Janek is dead; forging those horseshoes for him was pointless...</Cell><Cell>雅内克死了，为他打造那些马蹄铁完全是白费功夫……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_jan_konecne_mam_pro_sPmT</Cell><Cell>I have a set of spiked horseshoes for Janek’s big race. All I need to do is bring them to him.</Cell><Cell>为了雅内克重要的比赛，我准备好了一套带刺马蹄铁。现在只需要把马蹄铁送给他就行。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_jan_predal_jsem_jan_5Jfx</Cell><Cell>I gave Janek his new horseshoes.</Cell><Cell>我把新马蹄铁交给了雅内克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kdyz_kozesinu_z_kfWI</Cell><Cell>If I hand over the white roebuck's hide to the huntsman, he will rightfully give it to Peter of Pisek, the owner of the local woods.</Cell><Cell>如果我将白狍子皮交给猎人，他自然会将它交给本地森林的主人——皮塞克的彼得。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kozesina_z_bile_Uuwe</Cell><Cell>The white roebuck's hide I happened upon by chance turned out to be from a recently killed rare roebuck. Dobrosh, the huntsman of Suchdol, rewarded me for finding it.</Cell><Cell>我偶然发现的那张白狍子皮原来属于最近被猎杀的一头稀有狍子。苏赫多尔的猎人多布罗什为我提供了发现这张狍子皮的赏金。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kozesinu_jsem_o_kOIX</Cell><Cell>I gave the white hide to Wolfram the knacker. He paid me for it on the spot. What he does with it next is no concern of mine.</Cell><Cell>我将白色兽皮交给了屠夫沃尔夫勒姆。他当场就付钱了。至于他之后要怎么处置我就管不着了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_koz_kozesinu_jsem_o_tj7p</Cell><Cell>I handed the hide over to Dobrosh, the huntsman. He will rightfully hand it over to Peter of Pisek.</Cell><Cell>我将兽皮交给猎人多布罗什。他自然会将它交给皮塞克的彼得。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_pec_mam_pecetidlo_o_Sgac</Cell><Cell>Now I just have to take it to Rat of the Guild.</Cell><Cell>现在我得把它拿给公会的“老鼠”。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dones_pec_ziskal_jsem_pro_I0Sh</Cell><Cell>I got the seal of the dead mine owner for Rat. Rich mine owner Hanuman Rot died without heirs and in his will he left his property to the church, the city and King Sigismund. With the seal in hand, however, the Guild could make a few changes, much to the chagrin of the Hungarian king and his allies.</Cell><Cell>我将已故矿主哈奴曼·罗特的印章交给了“老鼠”。这位富裕的矿主后继无人，死前立下遗嘱决定将遗产留给教会、市政厅以及西格斯蒙德国王。如今有了那枚印章，公会将会掀起风浪，这将让那位匈牙利国王以及他的盟友很是苦恼。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>doved_enn_krejzluv_plan_j_F3y4</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl's plan is underway. Enneleyn, wearing the finest Tyrolean brocade and Mintha perfume, is the bait for the chamberlain. Now it's all up to her.</Cell><Cell>克雷泽的计划正在进行中。恩内琳穿着最好的蒂罗尔锦缎，喷着薄荷香水，将引诱管家上钩。而现在就都看她的了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>doved_kur_kurtyzanu_jsem__ObIL</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl's plan is underway. Enneleyn, wearing finest Tyrolean brocade and Mintha perfume, will be bait for the chamberlain. As her bodyguard for the evening, I have to hope she'll do what we agreed and we'll both go straight to Trosky from the wedding. But ideally separately: Enneleyn with the chamberlain, and me with von Bergow. Shall we got to it?</Cell><Cell>克雷泽的计划正在进行中。恩内琳穿着最好的蒂罗尔锦缎，喷着薄荷香水，将引诱管家上钩。而我作为她今晚的保镖，希望她能够遵守我们之间的约定，我们俩将在婚礼上直接去往特罗斯基。但最好是分头行动：恩内琳和管家一起，我和冯·波尔高一起。我们可以走了吗？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>drak_tady_mas_kosti_dane_VMAq</Cell><Cell>Dig out the bones.</Cell><Cell>挖出骨头。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dulezita__bitka_na_pastvi_kj7R</Cell><Cell>The brawl in the pasture took a bad turn and people started dropping dead. Damn it, it's all gone wrong!</Cell><Cell>牧场上的争吵演变成了斗殴，甚至出现了死者。该死的，一切都搞砸了！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_getreinforcemen_o5PF</Cell><Cell>Find reinforcements for Jan.</Cell><Cell>为扬找增援。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_gowithjantohand_Foxl</Cell><Cell>Tell Jan once you are ready to head out.</Cell><Cell>等准备好了，就去找扬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_reinforcements__wNNA</Cell><Cell>Reinforcements - Mikesh and Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>增援——米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_rewardfromjan_m4qx</Cell><Cell>Go and see Jan for your reward.</Cell><Cell>去见扬，要你的奖赏。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_telljanlaszlois_LObM</Cell><Cell>Tell Jan that László died.</Cell><Cell>告诉扬，拉斯洛死了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_telljanwhatyouk_Bp4g</Cell><Cell>Tell Jan what you found out in the camp.</Cell><Cell>告诉扬你在营地里发现了什么。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>dvojityag_zabij_jana_pKMM</Cell><Cell>Kill Jan.</Cell><Cell>杀了扬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fetch_pac_beta_po_me_chce_MYoy</Cell><Cell>Betty wants me to bring her some package from Grund and to pick up Matsek the wagoner, who went there before me.</Cell><Cell>贝蒂希望我能从格兰德为她取回一些包裹，并将早先前往那里的马车夫马切克接回。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_hrobnik_frantis_Qbpk</Cell><Cell>The gravedigger Frantishek is dead.</Cell><Cell>掘墓人弗朗特齐歇克死了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_poraz_stanika_KeOq</Cell><Cell>Defeat Stanley!</Cell><Cell>打败斯塔尼克！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_poraz_velmistra_J3F4</Cell><Cell>Defeat grandmaster Frantishek.</Cell><Cell>打败大师弗朗特齐歇克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_poraz_velmistra_uppz</Cell><Cell>Defeat grandmaster Barnaby.</Cell><Cell>打败大师巴纳比。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_promluv_si_se_s_Qso1</Cell><Cell>Talk to Stanley.</Cell><Cell>与斯塔尼克交谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_promluv_si_s_fr_0n4e</Cell><Cell>Talk to Frantishek.</Cell><Cell>与弗朗特齐歇克交谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_stanik_umrel_AHeO</Cell><Cell>Stanley died.</Cell><Cell>斯塔尼克死了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_vyhledej__i6dZ</Cell><Cell>Find the Trosky grandmaster.</Cell><Cell>寻找特罗斯基的大师。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_vyhledej_kutnoh_RALP</Cell><Cell>Search for the Kuttenberg grandmaster.</Cell><Cell>寻找库滕堡的大师。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_vyzvi_hrobnika__O8oa</Cell><Cell>Challenge the gravedigger Frantishek to a night fight.</Cell><Cell>向掘墓人弗朗特齐歇克于夜晚进行决斗的发起挑战。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fight_clu_vyzvi_na_zapas__m4Lm</Cell><Cell>Challenge hired hand Stanley to a fight.</Cell><Cell>向雇工斯塔尼克发起挑战。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>finaltalk_knez_marian_me__wSNx</Cell><Cell>Father Marian rewarded me for my help. There's no one guarding the pit to hell now, as the only demon turned out to be the deranged knight, Taras Mura.</Cell><Cell>神父马里安奖励我伸出援手。现在通往地狱的深坑无人看守，因为疯狂的骑士塔拉斯·穆拉才是唯一的恶魔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>finaltalk_vsechno_co_se_s_j3B4</Cell><Cell>I should visit Father Marian and discuss everything that happened.</Cell><Cell>我应该去拜访神父马里安，讨论所发生的一切。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>findingma_p_dozvedel_jsem_P8ob</Cell><Cell>Marika slept in the nomadic camp right next to Aranka's stall beside the rocks.</Cell><Cell>玛丽卡睡在了游牧民营地，就在山岩附近，紧挨着阿兰卡的马厩。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>findingma_p_vajda_po_me_c_KKek</Cell><Cell>The Voivode asked me to find his daughter, Marika. I didn't promise him anything, but I met her by chance.</Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官请求我帮他找回他的女儿玛丽卡，虽然我并没有答应他任何事，但却碰巧遇到了玛丽卡。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>findmarika_p_hledej_v_apo_1SzJ</Cell><Cell>The Voivode tracked his lost daughter Marika to the rock towers in Apollonia. I'll have to search the place.</Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官为找回他失踪的女儿玛丽卡，已追查到了阿波罗尼亚的石塔附近，我该去那个地方打探一番。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>findmarika_p_mariku_jsem__U3dG</Cell><Cell>I found Marika, just like her father, the nomads' Voivode, asked me to. But she is afraid to return to the camp because her brothers stabbed Bohush, her lover.</Cell><Cell>依照游牧民司令官，即玛丽卡父亲的嘱托，我找到了玛丽卡。但她对返回营地一事表现得很是惶恐，因为她的兄弟将她的爱人博胡什刺伤了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>findoutwh_k_bozene_prisli_eJ8P</Cell><Cell>Some fellows came to Bozhena's looking for us. They claimed to be from Lord von Bergow, but that was a lie. More likely they belong to that band that attacked us down by the pond.</Cell><Cell>有几个人来博珍娜家找我们，自称是冯·波尔高大人的人。胡说八道，分明像是在池塘边袭击我们的那伙人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gethalberd_rytir_jan_mi_d_29hr</Cell><Cell>Sir Jan recommended I take one of the halberds previously carried by his men. We won't have the numbers on our side in this fight, so keeping the enemy back will be crucial. I decided to follow the knight's advice.</Cell><Cell>扬爵士建议我拿上他手下以前携带的一把战戟。在这场战斗中，我们要以寡敌众，所以拦阻敌人至关重要。我决定听从这位骑士的建议。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gethalberd_rytir_jan_mi_d_6E1O</Cell><Cell>Sir Jan recommended I take one of the halberds previously carried by his men. We won't have the numbers on our side in this fight, so keeping the enemy back will be crucial.</Cell><Cell>扬爵士建议我拿上他手下以前携带的一把战戟。在这场战斗中，我们要以寡敌众，所以拦阻敌人至关重要。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gethalberd_rytir_jan_mi_d_XHfu</Cell><Cell>Sir Jan recommended I take one of the halberds previously carried by his men. I prefer my own weaponry, however, and don't require anything else.</Cell><Cell>扬爵士建议我拿上他手下以前携带的一把战戟。不过，我更喜欢自己的兵器装备，不需要其他东西。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreinfo_o_laszla_farkas_7ak2</Cell><Cell>I took care of Lászlo Farkas myself, so there’s no need to gather any more reinforcements.</Cell><Cell>我亲自解决了拉斯洛·法卡斯，所以无需再呼叫帮手。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreinfo_p_bohuzel_se_mi_Y7lT</Cell><Cell>I didn't arrange any reinforcements against László with Jan.</Cell><Cell>我并未与扬指派任何援军来对付拉斯洛。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreinfo_p_na_janovu_zad_1EFU</Cell><Cell>At Jan's request, I've found a few fearless men who I can count on.</Cell><Cell>在扬的要求下，我找到了几个可信而无畏的人选。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreinfo_p_na_janovu_zad_o9ni</Cell><Cell>A nice little group will be accompanying me to meet László. I hope Jan will be happy.</Cell><Cell>一支精锐小队将陪同我去见拉斯洛。我希望扬会很高兴。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreward_vyzvedavat_si_o_Foh7</Cell><Cell>I won't be picking up the reward for dealing with the Guild now.</Cell><Cell>我不会去领解决公会的报酬了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>getreward_vyzvedl_jsem_si_a1v2</Cell><Cell>I picked up the reward for my service. The Guild is over.</Cell><Cell>公会的事解决了，我也领到了报酬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gettingsa_kdyz_marika_ute_JNPC</Cell><Cell>When Marika escaped from the camp, she took Vajda's letter of passage with her as a guarantee. This infuriated the Voivode, because the letter gives him nomad's rights and the freedom to travel. So he wanted me to get it back for him.</Cell><Cell>玛丽卡逃出营地时顺手带走了通行函，以作保障。司令官对此非常愤怒，因为通行函授予了他游牧民固有的权利以及自由旅居的资格，因此他想让我替他取回通行函。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gowithjan_mel_bych_si_zar_KBdq</Cell><Cell>I should take care of all necessary affairs, then return to Jan and go for the handover. The journey will take some time. It'll be best if we head out before noon.</Cell><Cell>我应该处理好所有必要事务，再回到扬那里然后去，交接。路途有些遥远，最好在中午前出发。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>gowithjan_vzhledem_k_nast_wFK2</Cell><Cell>Given the situation, there's no point in going with Jan to the agreed-upon handover.</Cell><Cell>鉴于这种情况，和扬一起去约定的交接地点没有意义。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>hadkakona_osvedc_se_u_bib_B2hR</Cell><Cell>Prove yourself with Bibrek.</Cell><Cell>向布烈克证明你的实力。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>hadkakona_osvedc_se_u_mik_Hg8G</Cell><Cell>Prove yourself to Mikolai.</Cell><Cell>向米科莱证明你的实力。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>hadkakona_rozsoudi_oba_je_bpEj</Cell><Cell>Judge both riders.</Cell><Cell>对两位骑手做出评判。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>hrobnik_f_velmistr_franti_lyUk</Cell><Cell>Grandmaster Frantishek is now resting with his corpses.</Cell><Cell>大师弗朗特齐歇克已然与世长辞。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>informuj__podle_vseho_to__1ZWs</Cell><Cell>Everything pointed to Prokop being the murderer, but I refused to deal with him. Katherine wasn’t pleased to hear that, and it was clear I disappointed her, though she didn’t show it and claimed she’d kill him herself.</Cell><Cell>所有的迹象都在表明普罗科普就是凶手，但我拒绝将他就地正法。凯瑟琳对此很是不快，声称要亲手将普罗科普杀死。尽管她并未表露，但显然我让她失望了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_dopec_bez_zajice_mam__lFSr</Cell><Cell>Without Hare I have a problem though. I don't know where to go. I have to find Pasha's camp on my own. I hope it's somewhere nearby.</Cell><Cell>没了黑尔，我倒有了麻烦。我不知道方向。我得自己去找帕夏的营地。我希望它就在附近。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_dopec_hura_kemp_jsem__tkWD</Cell><Cell>Hurray! I found the encampment, even without Hare. I'll give the arrow to Pasha, grab the reward and vanish.</Cell><Cell>万岁！即使没有黑尔，我还是找到了营地！我把箭交给帕夏，拿上赏金就消失无踪了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_do_ve_stestena_nam_pr_OOKh</Cell><Cell>Fortune shone upon us, and the defenders of Maleshov fortress eventually surrendered. We captured the royal chamberlain and rescued Rosa Ruthard.</Cell><Cell>受到幸运之神的眷顾，马列索夫堡垒的守卫们最终选择了投降。我们抓住了那位皇家总管，也救出了罗莎·鲁瑟德。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_za_za_kaslu_na_zajice_kLJd</Cell><Cell>Fuck Hare. Pasha was supposed to come for the arrow.</Cell><Cell>该死的黑尔，本来应该是帕夏来拿箭的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_za_za_kaslu_na_zajice_SynE</Cell><Cell>Fuck Hare. Pasha was supposed to come for the arrow.</Cell><Cell>该死的黑尔，本来应该是帕夏来拿箭的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_za_za_tak_pecha_se_mu_QExe</Cell><Cell>Pasha had to return to the encampment in the forest, and Hare is supposed to lead me to him. It looks like the reward will have to wait.</Cell><Cell>帕夏不得不回到森林营地，而黑尔应该带我去找他。看来赏金暂时拿不到了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jdi_za_za_vyrazili_jsme_d_grKX</Cell><Cell>We headed out to the encampment in the forest, but Hare suddenly stopped and wants to speak to me.</Cell><Cell>我们向森林营地走去，但黑尔突然停下，要和我说话。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jed_do_ci_jed_do_cile_ODqi</Cell><Cell>And now head back to the finish line near the nomads’ camp.</Cell><Cell>And now head back to the finish line near the nomads’ camp.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jizdniluk_sestrilej_za_ji_YoZG</Cell><Cell>Shoot as many targets as possible while riding.</Cell><Cell>Shoot as many targets as possible while riding.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jizdniluk_zajdi_za_bibrek_Gd4R</Cell><Cell>Go to Bibrek for the result.</Cell><Cell>Go to Bibrek for the result.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>jizdniluk_zbyva_poslednic_w4az</Cell><Cell>The race is at the halfway point.</Cell><Cell>The race is at the halfway point.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>katuvsleh_ziskej_stastnou_B6pH</Cell><Cell>Get a horseshoe from the ghostly horse.</Cell><Cell>从幽灵马那里取一只马蹄铁。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovar_bez_ke_kovadline_pWkB</Cell><Cell>Go to the anvil.</Cell><Cell>转移到铁砧。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovar_dokovej_mec_I27d</Cell><Cell>Finish forging the hunting sword.</Cell><Cell>完成猎刀的锻造。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovarskas_prines_zdimirov_rcnh</Cell><Cell>Bring Zdimir the hunting sword you forged.</Cell><Cell>把你铸造的猎刀拿给兹迪米尔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kovarskas_vykovej_soutezn_dclU</Cell><Cell>Forge a competition hunting sword.</Cell><Cell>锻造一把竞赛用猎刀。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kralovske_najdi_vstup_do__vEQj</Cell><Cell>Enter the mine.</Cell><Cell>进入矿场。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kubaparalu_podej_zpravu_o_6frC</Cell><Cell>Give the report on the killing of Father Prokop.</Cell><Cell>汇报普罗科普神父被杀一事。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kubaparalu_zabij_prokopa_GkKX</Cell><Cell>Kill Father Prokop.</Cell><Cell>杀死普罗科普神父。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>kutnohors_vrat_se_na_turn_oUPQ</Cell><Cell>Go back to the tourney.</Cell><Cell>回到比武大会。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_cikanskyTabor</Cell><Cell>Nomads' Camp</Cell><Cell>游牧民营地</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_kocovnickyTabor</Cell><Cell>Nomads' Camp</Cell><Cell>游牧民营地</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_krcak</Cell><Cell>Kerchak Pond</Cell><Cell>科尔察克池塘</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_svet_kl</Cell><Cell></Cell><Cell>Perun ví kde</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_vezak</Cell><Cell>Rocktower Pond</Cell><Cell>石塔池塘</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_vezickoHerbalist</Cell><Cell>Herbalist Bozhena's hut</Cell><Cell>采药女博珍娜的小屋</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>location_vidlak</Cell><Cell>Vidlak Pond</Cell><Cell>维德拉克池塘</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lootersco_jak_to_s_dranci_wKNG</Cell><Cell>I'll never know what happened to the looters because I simply walked away. I can't expect Jan to forgive me for doing so.</Cell><Cell>我永远不会知道那些劫掠者发生了什么，因为我直接走开了。我不能指望扬会原谅我的所作所为。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lootersco_osud_dranciru_b_GChI</Cell><Cell>The fate of the looters was sealed the moment Sir Jan beheld their godless behaviour. No one was left alive.</Cell><Cell>当扬爵士看到他们的大逆不道行为时，这些劫掠者已经难逃一死。最终没人幸免。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>magickysip_jdi_za_zajicem_pdxT</Cell><Cell>Follow Hare.</Cell><Cell>跟随黑尔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>magickysip_pobij_zajice_A8Cm</Cell><Cell>Defeat Hare.</Cell><Cell>击败黑尔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>magickysip_promluv_si_se__9lsy</Cell><Cell>Talk to Hare.</Cell><Cell>和黑尔交谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>makeheali_nasbiral_jsem_b_EnJl</Cell><Cell>I picked the herbs as Bozhena advised and brewed the chamomile remedy for Sir Hans. I handed it over to Bozhena, and now she'll take care of Sir Hans.</Cell><Cell>我按照博珍娜的指示采摘了草药，为汉斯大人熬制了甘菊药剂。我把它交给了博珍娜，她会去治好汉斯大人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>mapakpokl_promluv_si_s_kr_1B5A</Cell><Cell>Talk to Krizhan about the map's authenticity.</Cell><Cell>向克日然质问地图的真实性。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_cas_mel_bych_si_co__rkDu</Cell><Cell>I should examine all the maps as soon as I can, then continue with my search.</Cell><Cell>我应该尽快将所有的地图检查一遍，然后继续搜索。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_dev_aby_dostal_tu_s_DKek</Cell><Cell>This time, Kreyzl doesn't even want me to steal the book. He's found some girl called Enneleyn for that. He'll take her to the Semine wedding and dangle her like bait in front of Chamberlain Ulrich's eyes. I ended up going to the wedding with the Tachov blacksmith, so it's hard to say how that turned out.</Cell><Cell>这次，克雷泽甚至都不想让我去偷书。他找来了一个叫恩内琳的姑娘做这件事。他会带她去参加塞米的婚礼，然后让她作为诱饵在管家乌尔里希面前晃悠。最后我和塔霍夫的铁匠去参加了婚礼，所以结果如何就不好说了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_dev_aby_dostal_tu_s_X2jJ</Cell><Cell>I was supposed to find this fearless Enneleyn in the nomads' camp by the Rocktower Pond. I had heard she was likely to ask for quite a tidy sum in return, but she turned out to be a reasonable and experienced woman and more importantly, she agreed to the plan. I even got the impression she was really looking forward to meeting the chamberlain.</Cell><Cell>我应该在石塔池塘边的游牧民营地里找到这位无所畏惧的恩内琳。我听说她可能会索要一笔数目不小的报酬，但结果她是位通情达理且老练的女人，更重要的是，她同意了这个计划。我甚至感觉她实际上非常期待见到管家。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_han_musel_jsem_naji_6Nai</Cell><Cell>When I rescued Adder, he started asking about Janosh. He said they were last in Miskowitz together. That's where I found him. In the pillory! He was there because he had injured one of the locals.</Cell><Cell>救下了阿德尔之后，他开始谈起了亚诺什。据说他们最后一次碰面是在米斯科维茨，而我也在那里的颈手枷上找到了亚诺什！这全然是因为他伤害了本地的一位村民。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_han_musel_jsem_naji_eKfe</Cell><Cell>When I rescued Adder, he started asking about Janosh. He said they were last in Miskowitz, so I promised him I'd look for him there. The Miskowitz Bailiff told me that Janosh was in the pillory because he had seriously injured one of the locals.</Cell><Cell>救下了阿德尔之后，他开始谈起了亚诺什。据说他们最后一次碰面是在米斯科维茨，我答应了他会到那里去寻找亚诺什。米斯科维茨的执行官告诉我，因亚诺什重伤了一个村民，他现已被套上颈手枷示众。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_han_potreboval_jsem_htKM</Cell><Cell>When I rescued Adder, he started asking about Janosh. He said they were last in Miskowitz together. That's where I found him. In the pillory! I didn't waste any time and got him out of there immediately.</Cell><Cell>救下了阿德尔之后，他开始谈起了亚诺什。据说他们最后一次碰面是在米斯科维茨，而我也在那里的颈手枷处找到了被锁着的亚诺什！我没有浪费时间，立马带他离开了那里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_han_potrebuju_naji__xYKY</Cell><Cell>When I rescued Adder, he started asking about Janosh. He said they were last in Miskowitz, so I promised him I'd look for him there. The local innkeeper told me to go straight to the pillory, saying I'd find Janosh there. </Cell><Cell>救下了阿德尔之后，他开始谈起了亚诺什。据说他们最后一次碰面是在米斯科维茨，我答应了他会到那里去寻找亚诺什。当地的旅店老板让我直接到颈手枷那去看看，他说亚诺什应该就在那里。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_koz_kuzi_z_bileho_s_wP7u</Cell><Cell>I found the white roebuck's hide in the poachers' camp.</Cell><Cell>我在偷猎者的营地找到了白狍子皮。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_koz_pokud_pytlaci_k_dGfl</Cell><Cell>If the poachers didn't sell the white roebuck's hide, it must be hidden somewhere in their camp.</Cell><Cell>如果偷猎者没有卖掉白狍子皮，那么它肯定就藏在他们的营地里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_pod_nasel_jsem_kouz_mgc9</Cell><Cell>I managed to find out the secret of the nomads' horseshoes. There's nothing magical about them, but they have special spikes attached. It shouldn't be difficult to forge a few.</Cell><Cell>我总算弄清楚了游牧民马蹄铁的秘密。其实这种马蹄铁没什么神奇的，只是上面有特殊的刺。打造几个应该不难。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_pod_v_cikanskem_tab_QKQH</Cell><Cell>There must be at least one set of the nomads' mysterious horseshoes lying around somewhere in their camp.Or maybe I can find someone who takes care of horses, who might reveal to me how those horseshoes are forged.</Cell><Cell>游牧民的营地里，肯定至少有一套他们那种神秘的马蹄铁。或许我可以找个照看马匹的人，打听一下这种马蹄铁是怎么锻造的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_pok_todo_hrac_dosel_Cohq</Cell><Cell>Svatava told me where in Mesoles I would find her family inheritance and asked me to bring it to her. I found their burned down house, the third on the right in the village when coming from the main road. She took it in secret at night on a handcart through a hole in the fence behind the house, along a path behind the yard, around the neighbour's barn, taking it out of the village and across a field to the woods, where the handcart got stuck and she had to bury everything quickly. Her description should help me locate the exact spot.</Cell><Cell>斯瓦塔娅将他们家族遗产的埋藏点告诉了我，并请求我前往梅索莱斯将其取回。我找到了他们那早已被焚毁的房屋，即是从主路进村路上的右侧第三座。据说当时斯瓦塔娅悄悄地将遗产转移到了一辆手推车上，趁着夜色推车穿过了屋后篱笆上的一处漏洞，沿着邻居家谷仓周围一间庭院后的道路离去。她在将遗产带出村庄后穿过了一片通往树林的田地，过程中手推车却在田地中卡住不动，她因此不得不迅速将遗产都埋了起来。她对埋藏点的描述应该能帮助我锁定遗产的具体位置。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_sek_placeholder__se_PXeA</Cell><Cell>By pure chance, I managed to find the axe from Zdenyek's legend even before he'd told me about it. However, time has taken a cruel toll on it.</Cell><Cell>机缘巧合下，在他告诉我之前，我就找到了兹登耶克传说中的那把斧头。不过岁月已经在它上面留下了不少痕迹。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_sta_chtel_jsem_po_c_qZ7U</Cell><Cell>I asked Chenyek for advice about the riddle, but he didn’t help much - just hinted that “gushing water” could mean a fountain in the town?</Cell><Cell>我向程叶科请教了一些关于谜题的建议，但他并未给出多少提示——只是说所谓的“潺潺流水”可能指的是镇上的喷泉？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_svo_svoje_veci_jsem_WCRe</Cell><Cell>Fleeing from the castle without our stuff would be stupid. But Istvan confiscated our things and had them taken to his chambers. Luckily, I found them and it looks like nothing's missing. Besides that, the keys of the Lord of the Castle also turned up.</Cell><Cell>空手逃离城堡并非明智之举。伊斯特万收走了我们的东西，还命人将其送至他的房间。幸运的是，我找回了它们，而且似乎无一遗漏。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_vst_mam_kristianuv__0Txu</Cell><Cell>I have Christian's letter, which will allow me to enter the mines.</Cell><Cell>我有克里斯蒂安的信，这下能进矿场了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>najdi_vst_zastiten_kristi_fPau</Cell><Cell>With Christian's letter, I entered the mines without any issue.</Cell><Cell>凭着克里斯蒂安的信，我顺利地进了矿场。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__jakmile_jsme_me_P4Ln</Cell><Cell>Me and Godwin went back down to the secret passageway. We were lucky - nobody came across Zizka or Katherine.</Cell><Cell>我和古德温回到了秘密通道里。杰式卡和凯瑟琳没被人撞见，我们真走运。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__kubenka_me_priv_aONo</Cell><Cell>Kubyenka led me to their old camp where the hand cannons were supposed to have been hidden. All we had to do was to find them.</Cell><Cell>库宾卡把我带到了他们的营地旧址，那些手铳应该就藏在这个地方，我们得找到它们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__nakonec_jsem_na_ZrFG</Cell><Cell>Kubyenka waited for me at their old camp where the hand cannons were supposed to have been hidden. All we had to do was to find them.</Cell><Cell>库宾卡在他们的营地旧址等着我，那些手铳应该就藏在这个地方，我们要做的就是找到它们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__uz_mame_vsechno_jb6a</Cell><Cell>We've already got everything, so now I have to hurry back to Godwin. Zizka and Katherine are waiting.</Cell><Cell>东西都到手了，我得尽快跟古德温汇合。杰式卡和凯瑟琳还在等着我们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nasleduj__z_brany_byl_sly_IXYY</Cell><Cell>An alarm could be heard from the gate. When we ran to see what was the matter, the army of Markvart von Aulitz was already on the horizon. The lord who led the sacking of Skalitz…</Cell><Cell>大门处可以听到警报声。当我们跑去查看时，马科瓦尔·冯·奥利茨的军队已经出现。是带头洗劫斯卡里茨的领主...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nauc_se_s_zatraceny_certo_ehwX</Cell><Cell>Bloody handgonne! Aiming was nigh impossible and it was more dangerous to us than to those straw targets on the other side. Anyhow, the result unexpectedly dampened Godwin's initial enthusiasm and belief in any promising future for firearms.</Cell><Cell>该死的手铳！这东西太难瞄准了，而且与对面那些稻草靶子相比，它对我们来说更为危险。总而言之，如此结果出乎预料，古德温最初对它们的热情和美好期盼也随之消减。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__kozlik_je_jedni_6Dsb</Cell><Cell>Kozliek has been serving under Zizka for a long time. Now he's a member of my company.</Cell><Cell>科兹里克曾在杰式卡手下工作了很久。现在他是我连队的一员了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__kozlik_je_jedni_r0GH</Cell><Cell>Kozliek has been serving under Zizka for a long time. Now he'll be reporting to me.</Cell><Cell>科兹里克曾在杰式卡手下工作了很久。现在他要向我报道了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__zizka_mi_dal_ve_1cxY</Cell><Cell>Zizka assigned two of his most experienced men to my company: Mikesh and Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>杰式卡把他最有经验的两个人派给了我的连队：米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>naverbuj__zizka_mi_dal_ve_1zA6</Cell><Cell>Zizka put me in command of two of his experienced men. I’ll likely find Mikesh and Kozliek on the battlements.</Cell><Cell>杰式卡让我指挥他那两个身经百战的手下。我去城垛上或许就能找到米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nebakovob_nauc_se_strilet_hFAB</Cell><Cell>Learn to shoot a hand cannon.</Cell><Cell>学习使用手铳。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nebakovob_odraz_zebriky_aUkx</Cell><Cell>Knock down the ladders!</Cell><Cell>推倒梯子！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nebakovob_osetri_kozlika_aXZ5</Cell><Cell>Treat Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>治疗科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nebakovob_shod_zebrik_1_3AwA</Cell><Cell>Knock down the ladders!</Cell><Cell>推倒梯子！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>nebo_zust_erik_se_utoku_n_UzbH</Cell><Cell>Erik did not participate in the attack on Skalitz. I certainly don’t need to take revenge on him, and maybe I should just stay at the castle. If I want to stay here, I should probably discuss it with Zizka and tell him what I've decided.</Cell><Cell>埃里克没有参与对斯卡里茨的袭击，所以我当然没必要向他复仇。或许我应该就待在城堡里。如果要留在这的话，我也许该和杰式卡商量一下，告诉他我的决定。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>negotiate_nastoupil_jsem__UE7j</Cell><Cell>I told László that I know what happened to Peter. His response surprised me. Not batting an eyelid, he made me an offer, a rather dishonourable one. In my situation, though, it would be foolish to turn it down. I do feel sorry for Jan though…</Cell><Cell>我告诉拉斯洛，我知道彼得发生了什么。他的反应让我吃惊。他眼皮都不眨一下，给我开了个条件，一个相当可耻的条件。不过，如果我拒绝，就显得愚蠢。但我确实为扬感到难过......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>negotiate_oslovil_jsem_la_Qaz6</Cell><Cell>I spoke to László and introduced myself as Jan's intermediary. Although László received me, during our negotiations he made it abundantly clear that he was the one setting conditions. He agreed the handover would take place on neutral ground, but when I wanted to see the captive, László adamantly refused. I hope Jan won't be disappointed with the outcome. </Cell><Cell>我与拉斯洛交谈，说自己是扬的中间人。虽然拉斯洛接待了我，但在我们的谈判中，他非常清楚地表示，他才是开出条件的人。他同意在中立地点进行交接，但当我要看俘虏时，拉斯洛坚决拒绝。我希望扬不会对这个结果感到失望。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>negotiate_p_laszla_jsem_r_fT31</Cell><Cell>I immediately told László I know what happened to Peter. László claimed that Jan will certainly want to bury Peter's body. We agreed where the body will be handed over. Jan should be cautious though…</Cell><Cell>我立即告诉拉斯洛我知道彼得发生了什么。拉斯洛称，扬肯定会想埋葬彼得的尸体。我们商定了要在哪里进行尸体交接。但扬应该谨慎行事......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>objective1_nasel_jsem_u_j_53Xm</Cell><Cell>If I'm lucky I'll be able to figure out where the map leads before Krizhan notices it's gone.</Cell><Cell>如果足够幸运，我就能在克日然发现地图丢失之前找出宝藏的位置。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>objective1_od_podivneho_t_ApxN</Cell><Cell>Krizhan was unfortunately unable to find out where the map actually leads, I hope I'll have better luck…</Cell><Cell>很遗憾克日然没能找出这张地图实际指向的目的地，但愿我比他能更走运些…</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>objective1_od_podivneho_t_GRv1</Cell><Cell>I think I've found the place Krizhan's map leads to, but it looks like there's a camp here…</Cell><Cell>看来我已经找到了克日然的地图指向的地点，但似乎那里有一个营地…</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_naverbuj_kozlika_I3xd</Cell><Cell>Recruit Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>征募科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_naverbuj_mikese_DRBj</Cell><Cell>Recruit Mikesh and Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>征募米凯什和科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_objective1_5trm</Cell><Cell>Knocked-down ladders:</Cell><Cell>推倒的梯子：</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_seber_mece_k_br_7xr4</Cell><Cell>Collect swords to be sharpened.</Cell><Cell>收集需要打磨锋利的剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oblehanis_shod_zebriky_1SKw</Cell><Cell>Knocked-down ladders:</Cell><Cell>推倒的梯子：</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>opatrne_n_holky_nas_sice__z1kr</Cell><Cell>Capon and I weren't alone in the pond. A bit further along the shore some laundresses were bathing and Capon had the bright idea of going to spy on them. Although the girls didn’t spot us, we didn’t enjoy their scantily dressed loveliness for long.</Cell><Cell>光顾这片池塘的，不止我和汉斯少主。沿岸稍远处有几名洗衣女在洗澡。卡蓬起了雅兴，欲要上前窥探。虽然我们未被发现，但也没能欣赏她们的曼妙身姿太久。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>opatrne_n_nakonec_se_to_u_z6fe</Cell><Cell>Capon and I weren't alone in the pond. A bit further along the shore some laundresses were bathing and Capon had the bright idea of going to spy on them.That turned out to be one damned stupid idea! We just ended up scaring one of the girls.</Cell><Cell>光顾这片池塘的，不止我和汉斯少主。沿岸稍远处有几名洗衣女在洗澡。卡蓬起了雅兴，欲要上前窥探。真是个馊主意！我们吓到了其中一位姑娘。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>opatrne_n_v_rybniku_nejsm_ycT3</Cell><Cell>Me and Sir Hans aren't alone in the pond. A little further along by the banks there are some girls bathing, and Sir Hans, gentleman that he is, wants to go and spy on them. </Cell><Cell>光顾这片池塘的，不止我和汉斯少主。沿岸稍远处有群姑娘在洗澡。汉斯少主一展绅士风度，欲要上前窥探。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>oprav_sek_placeholder__se_Abz0</Cell><Cell>Although I didn't know what a rarity I had discovered, I took the axe to the forge to mend, and now it looks as good as new.</Cell><Cell>当时我还不知道它是多珍贵的宝物，但我还是把它拿去铁匠铺修好了。现在这把斧头焕然一新。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osetri_ko_kozlik_byl_rane_f48n</Cell><Cell>Kozliek was wounded in battle. I should take a look at him and treat him.</Cell><Cell>科兹里克在战斗中负伤。我得查看他的伤势并对他进行治疗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osetri_ko_raneneho_kozlik_ly6P</Cell><Cell>I examined the injured Kozliek and treated him.</Cell><Cell>我查看了科兹里克的伤势并提供了治疗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osetri_ko_zraneneho_kozli_1tUG</Cell><Cell>I didn't treat the injured Kozliek.</Cell><Cell>我没有治疗受伤的科兹里克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osvedc_se_bibrek_byl_luko_0q8v</Cell><Cell>Bibrek organized shooting competitions in the region. I succeeded in everything he set up for me, so he'd take my opinion seriously.</Cell><Cell>Bibrek organized shooting competitions in the region. I succeeded in everything he set up for me, so he'd take my opinion seriously.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osvedc_se_bibrek_je_lukos_KweN</Cell><Cell>Bibrek organizes shooting competitions in the region. If I succeed in everything he sets up for me, he'll surely consider my opinion.</Cell><Cell>Bibrek organizes shooting competitions in the region. If I succeed in everything he sets up for me, he'll surely consider my opinion.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osvedc_se_mikolaj_byl_rom_lMkn</Cell><Cell>Mikolai was used to organize horse races in the region. I won everything he set up for me, which gave my word some weight with him.</Cell><Cell>Mikolai was used to organize horse races in the region. I won everything he set up for me, which gave my word some weight with him.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>osvedc_se_mikolaj_je_roms_8ZKT</Cell><Cell>Mikolai organizes horse races in the region. If I win everything he sets up for me, he'll certainly take my word seriously.</Cell><Cell>Mikolai organizes horse races in the region. If I win everything he sets up for me, he'll certainly take my word seriously.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>plesnivec_dones_cevenakov_D3ob</Cell><Cell>Bring Gules Canker's mace.</Cell><Cell>把“溃疡”的钉头锤带给古勒斯。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pockej_pa_celedin_janek_p_dqqs</Cell><Cell>Stable hand Janek will soon be racing with the horseshoes I made for him. He promised me that if he wins, he’ll give me a few extra groschen.</Cell><Cell>马棚工人雅内克很快就要用我给他打造的马蹄铁参加比赛了。他答应我，要是赢了，就再给我一些格罗申。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pockej_pa_celedin_je_mrtv_4SHS</Cell><Cell>Janek unfortunately died. Now I won’t get any reward for the horseshoes I made for him.</Cell><Cell>不幸的是，雅内克死了。虽然我给他打造了马蹄铁，但现在也拿不到报酬了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pockej_pa_celedin_pojede__ioCw</Cell><Cell>I think it’s time I went back to Janek and collected my reward from him.</Cell><Cell>该是时候回去找雅内克，领取我的报酬了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pockej_pa_celedin_vyhral__LcRl</Cell><Cell>Janek won the race thanks to my horseshoes and shared the prize with me.</Cell><Cell>多亏了我打造的马蹄铁，雅内克赢得了比赛，还跟我分享了奖金。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pockej_pa_celedin_v_zavod_Y2cl</Cell><Cell>The horseshoes didn’t help Janek much. He lost the race, and I’m left without a reward.</Cell><Cell>马蹄铁对雅内克没什么帮助。他输了比赛，我也没拿到报酬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>podivej_s_tak_hanse_jsem__zYt2</Cell><Cell>So I eventually found Janosh in Miskowitz. In the pillory. It doesn't even surprise me.</Cell><Cell>我最终在米斯科维茨找到了亚诺什，他被锁在了颈手枷上，而我对此并不惊讶。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pokracuj__chvala_panu_vuz_GwQT</Cell><Cell>Thank God! I made it to the wagon and Katherine's other allies. After waiting a few hours for von Bergow's soldiers to call off the search, we got Zizka onto the cart and set off for the Kuttenberg region.</Cell><Cell>谢天谢地！我终于找到了那辆马车和凯瑟琳的其他伙伴。我们等了几个小时，终于等到冯·波尔高的手下结束了搜捕，随后帮杰式卡上了马车，便朝着库滕堡地区行进。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomodli_s_knez_prokop_z_k_AgWa</Cell><Cell>Father Prokop of Kuttenberg sent me on a penitential pilgrimage to the shrine of the Virgin Mary in Bohunowitz. I prayed to the Virgin and repented of my sins.</Cell><Cell>库滕堡的普罗科普神父指派我前往博胡诺维茨的圣母玛利亚教堂进行朝圣。我已向圣母祈祷，为我的罪孽进行了忏悔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomodli_s_knez_prokop_z_k_cpsm</Cell><Cell>Father Prokop of Kuttenberg sent me on a penitential pilgrimage to the shrine of the Virgin Mary in Bohunowitz. I am to pray at the chapel and repent of my sins.</Cell><Cell>库滕堡的普罗科普神父指派我前往博胡诺维茨的圣母玛利亚教堂进行朝圣，我得到那里去进行祈祷，为我的罪孽进行忏悔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomodli_s_knez_prokop_z_k_ddIv</Cell><Cell>Father Prokop of Kuttenberg sent me on a penitential pilgrimage to the shrine of the Virgin Mary in Bohunowitz. I was supposed to pray to her and repent of my sins, but Father Procop has since died. I must seek redemption elsewhere.</Cell><Cell>库滕堡的普罗科普神父指派我前往博胡诺维茨的圣母玛利亚教堂进行朝圣。而我本该向圣母祈祷，祈求洗清我的罪孽，然而普罗科普神父却在此期间与世长辞，如今我必须得到别处寻找赎罪之法。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pomoz_zaj_po_vsem_co_se_n_T8Bp</Cell><Cell>Despite all the things that went wrong that bloody night, Maleshov fortress still fell, Otto van Bergow was captured, and Lady Rosa Ruthard was rescued. Fortune finally smiled upon us, and we literally had the royal chamberlain in the palm of our hand.</Cell><Cell>即使在那个腥风血雨的夜晚发生了很多意外，随着马列索夫堡垒的最终沦陷，奥托·冯·波尔高落入了我们手里，同时罗莎·鲁瑟德夫人也就此得救。幸运女神终于朝我们微笑了，而我们也确实将那位皇家总管掌握在了手中。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>po_pytlac_dones_kozesinu__5Noe</Cell><Cell>Bring the white roebuck's hide to the knacker.</Cell><Cell>将白狍子皮交给屠夫。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>po_pytlac_dones_kozesinu__Bcii</Cell><Cell>Bring the white roebuck's hide to the huntsman.</Cell><Cell>将白狍子皮交给猎人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>po_pytlac_najdi_kozesinu__6Z1t</Cell><Cell>Find the white roebuck's hide.</Cell><Cell>找出白狍子皮。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poraz_sta_jako_tretiho_mu_m03h</Cell><Cell>The third person I have to beat is Stanley.</Cell><Cell>我的第三个对手将会是斯塔尼克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poraz_sta_porazil_jsem_i__B2HK</Cell><Cell>I also beat Stanley.</Cell><Cell>我还打败了斯塔尼克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poraz_sta_prohral_jsem_za_BAU1</Cell><Cell>I lost the fight with the hired hand Stanley.</Cell><Cell>我没能打败雇工斯塔尼克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poraz_vel_frantisek_mi_po_sqtb</Cell><Cell>Frantishek gave me a right proper beating. A few more punches and he could bury me here and now to rest in peace. He did agree, however, that I could try again. Maybe I'll be lucky next time.</Cell><Cell>弗朗特齐歇克把我打得上气不接下气，要是再多来几拳，估计他能让我就此倒地不起，然后将我埋在此地。而即便如此，他还是同意了让我再试一次，但愿下次我能走运些。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poraz_vel_jindra_prohral_JtNw</Cell><Cell>I reckon I overestimated myself. A fight with a grandmaster is not a fight in the tavern... I got a royal beating and can forget about winning the title.</Cell><Cell>或许我高估了自己的实力。与大师的比试，岂是寻常酒馆斗殴能比拟的......我被狠狠地教训了一顿，所以还是别再惦记赢取那个大师头衔了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poraz_vel_jindra_vyhral_wD8S</Cell><Cell>I don't even know how I did it, but I reckon I'm the local grandmaster now... Hopefully that won't change for a while.</Cell><Cell>我甚至不知道自己到底是怎么做到的，但似乎我现在已经成为了本地的大师......但愿这一头衔不会太快变成别人的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poraz_vel_velmistr_je_por_hgDw</Cell><Cell>The grandmaster has been defeated, long live the new grandmaster! I now truly am the best fighter in the region.</Cell><Cell>旧王惨败，新王当立！现在我就是这片区域最强的战士。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>porus_doh_sice_jsme_se_s__e6NR</Cell><Cell>Even though I agreed to let Radmil win… my honour is still in the balance. I can still change my mind and show him what a Skalitz blacksmith can do.</Cell><Cell>尽管我先前同意故意输给拉德米尔…但我的良心最终占据了上风。我仍然可以反悔，并向他展示一名斯卡里茨铁匠的真本事。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poslednip_shod_zebriky_8Vh2</Cell><Cell>Knock down the ladder!</Cell><Cell>推倒梯子！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pozehnej__pecha_chtel_aby_V3fi</Cell><Cell>Pasha wanted me to shoot the arrow into his head, but I managed to persuade him, that it's not the best idea. These bandits are really a weird bunch.</Cell><Cell>帕夏想让我往他头上射箭，但我成功说服了他这不是个好主意。这帮强盗真是性情古怪。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pracharna_sezen_pro_ennel_JEVT</Cell><Cell>Get some Mintha perfume for the companion.</Cell><Cell>为女伴找来些薄荷香水。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>pracuj_na_na_vinici_jsem__K5bG</Cell><Cell>I finished labouring in the vineyard.</Cell><Cell>我完成了葡萄园的工作。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>prines_kr_krysa_by_rada_z_VPob</Cell><Cell>Rat would like to get the seal of dead mine owner Hanuman Rot. The rich mine owner died without an heir so his property was divided up between the church, the city and King Sigismund. A cleverly forged contract with a genuine seal could, however, change a lot in favour of the Guild.</Cell><Cell>家财万贯的矿主哈奴曼·罗特因后继无人，去世以后他的财产便被教会、市议会以及国王西格斯蒙德一一瓜分，而他生前拥有的一枚印章也成了“老鼠”觊觎已久的物件，毕竟将其贴在一份巧妙伪造的合约上将会使公会大获裨益。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>priprav_s_do_tabora_doraz_GrOL</Cell><Cell>Sigismund's executioner, Stibor of Stiborzitz, has arrived at the camp to investigate Chertan's murder. I have to gather evidence fast and tell Katz what I've found.</Cell><Cell>为调查牵涉赫尔坦的谋杀案件，西格斯蒙德手下的刽子手，斯蒂博尔齐茨的斯蒂博尔已经抵达了营地。我得尽快搜集证据，并将自己的发现向卡茨汇报。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>probud_st_strazny_na_bran_YPC4</Cell><Cell>The guard on the gate fell asleep on watch. Now he's dead, so nothing will wake him.</Cell><Cell>城门守卫在站岗时睡着了。现在他已经死了，所以也不会再苏醒了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>prohledni_nabidl_jsem_ze__1gHJ</Cell><Cell>I examined Peter really closely and found that he was suffering from melancholy. The cause? The presence of Sigismund's army and the fear of death. His treatment is clear. A chamomile decoction to improve his sleep, and a bag of dried chamomile to soothe the mind. Peter needs to change his diet, I'll help him with that. I should also think of some words to give him hope. Naturally, I should not forget about a prayer. When I get everything ready and give it some thought, I'll go back to Peter.</Cell><Cell>我仔细检查了彼得的身体，发现他患有忧郁症。病因是什么？是他对波希米亚国王西格斯蒙德的军队和对死亡的恐惧。他的治疗方案显而易见。服用甘菊药剂以改善他的睡眠，并用一袋干燥的甘菊来平复精神。彼得需要改变饮食习惯，我会帮助他做到这一点。我还得想一些鼓舞人心的话语来开导他。当然，我不能忘记祈祷。待我准备好一切并认真思考之后，我就会回到彼得那里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>prohledni_nabidl_jsem_ze__ztiZ</Cell><Cell>I examined Peter, but I didn't learn much. He suffers from an unnatural anxiety. As a treatment, I suggest a chamomile decoction to help him fall asleep, a change in diet, prayer, and it wouldn't hurt if I could think of some encouraging words to help him overcome his fears. As soon as I get everything ready, I'll return to Peter.</Cell><Cell>我给彼得做了检查，但并没有什么收获。他因为一种不正常的焦虑而备受折磨。为了治疗，我建议他服用甘菊药剂来助眠，改变饮食习惯并做祷告。如果我能想出一些鼓励的话来帮助他克服恐惧，那就更好了。待我准备好这一切，我就会回到彼得那里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>projed_br_projed_branu_2CY8</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint on the bridge by the Zhelejov inn.</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint on the bridge by the Zhelejov inn.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>projed_br_projed_branu_9Mgc</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint near the Slatego greengrocer.</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint near the Slatego greengrocer.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>projed_br_projed_branu_RUtt</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint by Semine Pond.</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint by Semine Pond.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>projed_br_projed_branu_vm4N</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint near the western Sdiar homestead.</Cell><Cell>I must pass the checkpoint near the western Sdiar homestead.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_ale_tohle_ja_si_hk8Z</Cell><Cell>Things got a little heated with Krizhan and it came to blows! He's a thief and a deceiver! Shame on him!</Cell><Cell>我与克日然的对峙产生些许火药味儿，因此我们打了起来！他就是个小偷、骗子！简直厚颜无耻！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_ale_tohle_ja_si_hPG6</Cell><Cell>Eventually I came to an agreement with Krizhan and got my coin back. Next time I should be more careful. Times are bad and people are wicked.</Cell><Cell>最终，我与克日然达成一致，并拿回了我的钱。下次我应该更小心点，毕竟如今世态拙劣、人心险恶。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_ale_tohle_ja_si_HUUy</Cell><Cell>I won't stand for this! I drag myself halfway across this land and nothing's here. Krizhan owes me an explanation and my coin back!</Cell><Cell>真是叫人无法容忍！我千辛万苦走了大半个地球，才发现这里什么都没有。克日然欠我一个解释！还有我的钱！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_kdyz_jsme_s_kub_UcAu</Cell><Cell>When we arrived at the ambush spot, Zizka was already there with some other men. Once I handed him the bundle of hand cannons, we could start preparing for the arrival of the convoy transporting our prisoner.</Cell><Cell>当我们抵达伏击点时，才发现杰式卡和他的一些部下早已抵达。等我将那捆手铳交给他，我们就可以为伏击那只押运犯人的车队做准备了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_kdyz_ted_vim_pr_5xjO</Cell><Cell>Now that I know why Janosh is in the pillory, maybe it will help if I talk to the local bailiff.</Cell><Cell>既然我已知晓亚诺什上颈手枷的原因，或许去跟当地的执行官谈谈会有所帮助。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_kozlik_byl_vybr_Rbr9</Cell><Cell>Kozliek was chosen for the raid. I could send Mikesh with him.</Cell><Cell>我选择派科兹里克参加突袭，也也可以派米凯什和他一起去。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_kozlik_se_rad_v_NIIc</Cell><Cell>Kozliek is a betting man, but should I be betting his life on today's raid?</Cell><Cell>科兹里克是个赌徒，但我要拿他的命作今天突袭的赌注吗？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mel_bych_franti_t490</Cell><Cell>I should thank Frantishek for the fight.</Cell><Cell>我应该感谢弗朗特齐歇克与我搏斗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mel_bych_stanik_4P4R</Cell><Cell>I should thank Stanley for the fight.</Cell><Cell>我应该感谢斯塔尼克与我搏斗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mikes_a_kozlik__Xhu8</Cell><Cell>Mikesh and Kozliek should be on guard duty in the courtyard. If I want to select them for the raid I should find them there.</Cell><Cell>米凯什和科兹里克正在庭院执勤。若想派他们参加突袭，我应该去那里找到他们。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mikes_byl_vybra_l9oL</Cell><Cell>Mikesh was chosen for the raid. I could send Kozliek with him.</Cell><Cell>我选择派米凯什参加突袭，也可以派科兹里克和他一起去。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mikes_i_kozlik__RV4t</Cell><Cell>Mikesh and Kozliek were both chosen for the raid. They work well together.</Cell><Cell>米凯什和科兹里克都被选中参加突袭，他们配合默契。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_mohli_bych_se_d_QlSv</Cell><Cell>There must be someone in the camp who can tell me something about these special horseshoes. All I need to do is ask cleverly.</Cell><Cell>营地里肯定有人知道这种特殊马蹄铁的事情。我只需要巧妙地打听一下。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_myska_me_zavedl_bE56</Cell><Cell>Myshka led me to a lovely little pond. There we chatted for a while and then we went dancing, which got me thinking back to the dances in Skalitz. She's a really sweet girl.</Cell><Cell>米什卡领着我来到了一处宜人的小池边，在那里交谈片刻后，我们结伴前去跳舞，这也让我忆起了在斯卡里茨尽兴舞蹈的瞬间。而米什卡，她可真是位翩翩佳人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_na_vypad_jsem_z_Q62e</Cell><Cell>From my company, I chose Kozliek for the raid.</Cell><Cell>我从部下中选择了科兹里克去参加突袭。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_nikdy_jsem_vdov_NqcL</Cell><Cell>I never told the widow what happened to the remains of her admirer Jan.</Cell><Cell>我从未告诉这位寡妇她的仰慕者约翰的遗体发生了什么。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_posvecena_puda__lkc5</Cell><Cell>The graveyard's consecrated earth covered Jan's bones, and his soul will now find redemption. All that's left to do now is talk to the widow Margaret.</Cell><Cell>墓地圣土覆盖了约翰的尸骨，他的灵魂现在将得到救赎。现在所要做的就是和寡妇玛格丽特谈谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_tak_uz_je_to_ja_yqIy</Cell><Cell>Now it’s clear. Hare wanted the arrow for himself, but when I didn’t give him anything, he took off.</Cell><Cell>现在真相大白了，黑尔想要把箭据为己有。但他发现从我这占不到便宜，就走了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_ten_zmrd_zajic__UFi0</Cell><Cell>That fucker Hare wanted the arrowhead for himself, and started getting aggressive! The bloody bastard!</Cell><Cell>那个混蛋黑尔变得咄咄逼人，想自己拿走箭头！该死的杂碎！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_uz_vim_jake_pod_5g1q</Cell><Cell>I spoke with Mikolai, who looks after the horses in the camp. The horseshoes, he says, aren’t magical at all, but they keep the horses steady on rocky surfaces thanks to the spikes.</Cell><Cell>我和营地里负责照料马匹的米科莱聊过了。他表示这种马蹄铁根本没有魔力，关键是上面的刺，这些刺能让马在崎岖的地面上也能稳稳当当的奔跑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vdova_marketa_k_d5o4</Cell><Cell>The widow Margaret finally redeemed her sin, because she didn't kill her admirer Jan, but only covered up the truth about his death.</Cell><Cell>寡妇玛格丽特终于赎了罪，她没有杀死她的仰慕者约翰，只是掩盖了他死亡的真相。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vdova_marketa_m_VWra</Cell><Cell>The widow Margaret told me her secret: an innocent man died because of her. What makes her sin even worse is that the soul of the hermit's brother Jan is not at peace. Margaret never told anyone that her lover killed his rival, Jan, in a duel, and together they covered his tracks. When the young man was found dead with a broken skull at the bottom of a cliff, it was assumed he'd killed himself out of unrequited love. Jan's body was buried outside the graveyard because suicides cannot enter the Kingdom of Heaven.</Cell><Cell>寡妇玛格丽特将她的秘密告诉了我：一个无辜的男人因她而死。隐士的弟弟约翰的灵魂不得安宁，这令她的罪孽更加深重。玛格丽特从未告诉过任何人，她的情人在决斗中杀死了对手约翰，然后他们一起掩盖了他的踪迹。当这个年轻人的尸体在悬崖下被发现时，头骨已经破碎，人们认为他是因为爱而不得才寻短见。约翰的尸体被埋在墓地外，因为自杀者不能进入天国。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_vybral_jsem_na__ChY3</Cell><Cell>I chose Kozliek for the raid. I hope it's the right choice.</Cell><Cell>我选择了科兹里克去突袭。希望这是正确的选择。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_zajic_nechtel_a_EZHa</Cell><Cell>Hare didn't want me to bring the arrow back to the encampment. He's worried that the power of the arrow will drive Pasha mad, and he'll start engaging in suicidal robberies. He wanted it for himself and I thought giving it to him would be a good idea, but it was a mistake. So I took it back. It belongs to Pasha, and unlike Hare, he'll pay me for it. </Cell><Cell>黑尔不想让我把箭带回营地。他担心箭的威力会把帕夏逼疯，会开始搞自杀式抢劫。黑尔想要箭，我最初以为把箭给他是一个好主意。但我给了他之后又觉得那是个错误的决定，所以我又把箭拿了回来。这箭属于帕夏，而且帕夏不会像黑尔一样不给我报酬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_zajic_nechtel_a_lVjz</Cell><Cell>Hare didn't want me to bring the arrow back to the encampment. He's worried that the power of the arrow will drive Pasha mad, and he'll start engaging in suicidal robberies. I gave the arrow to Hare. He didn't pay me for it, but I saved a few good men from certain death.</Cell><Cell>黑尔不想让我把箭带回营地。他担心箭的威力会把帕夏逼疯，会开始搞自杀式抢劫。我把箭给了黑尔。他没有付我赏金，但我让几个好人免于一死。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_zajic_si_chtel__KYi4</Cell><Cell>Hare wanted to talk, but I sent him packing.</Cell><Cell>黑尔想谈谈，但我把他打发走了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_zavod_jsem_doje_PhMV</Cell><Cell>The race is over. Time to find out the results from Mikolai.</Cell><Cell>The race is over. Time to find out the results from Mikolai.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_z_cikanu_inform_l7Mm</Cell><Cell>I tried to find out from Mikolai what kind of horseshoes he uses, but he didn’t say a word. I’ll have to find out some other way.</Cell><Cell>我试着从米科莱嘴里套话，想知道他使用的马蹄铁是什么样子，可他嘴严得很。我得另想办法弄清楚。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_zizka_na_miste__FRWk</Cell><Cell>I'm sure Zizka is waiting for the hand cannons he sent us to find.</Cell><Cell>想必杰式卡一定在等着他派我们前去寻找的手铳。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>promluv_s_zjistil_jsem_vy_KgCK</Cell><Cell>I’ve found out Mikolai’s results.</Cell><Cell>I’ve found out Mikolai’s results.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>proveyour_kovar_by_vypomo_mwOH</Cell><Cell>Radovan the blacksmith could use my help, but first he wants to test me, to see if I know what I'm doing.</Cell><Cell>铁匠拉多万需要帮手，但他得先考考我，看我是否能胜任。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>proveyour_kovar_lorenc_si_SCsz</Cell><Cell>Radovan the blacksmith wants to test me, I should return to the forge and take the test.</Cell><Cell>铁匠拉多万想考考我，我应该回到铁匠铺，接受考验。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>proveyour_kovar_prijal_vy_COhX</Cell><Cell>I may not have stood at the forge for some time, but thankfully there are some things you don't forget. I passed the test and Radovan took me on as his hand. He's even letting me sleep in a chamber by the woodshed.</Cell><Cell>我有一阵子没打过铁了，但幸好有些技能是不会忘记的。我通过考验，拉多万收下了我。还让我睡在柴房旁的一个房间里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>prozkoume__sima_je_mrtvej_6vDP</Cell><Cell>Shima is dead. I should find out about the skulduggery Grund from one of the other miners.</Cell><Cell>斯马已经死了。我应该和其他矿工了解格兰德的欺诈事件。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_azzahrob_GbwV</Cell><Cell>Rat needs to get the seal of a dead mine owner from his grave in Sedletz for the Guild.</Cell><Cell>“老鼠”想要替公会取得已故矿主的印章，而那枚印章就在塞德莱茨的矿主坟墓里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_cikanskacest_w337</Cell><Cell>The nomads' Voivode wants to find his lost daughter Marika.</Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官想要找回他失踪的女儿玛丽卡。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_crosscountrytrosecko_ZIjz</Cell><Cell>Mikolai’s races through the forests and fields of Trosky region.</Cell><Cell>Mikolai’s races through the forests and fields of Trosky region.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_dvojityagent_27AM</Cell><Cell>Jan of Suchotlesky has sent me in his name to negotiate the release of his brother, a knight who is held captive in Sigismund's camp.</Cell><Cell>苏霍茨基的扬派我以他之名去谈判，要求释放他的哥哥，后者被囚禁在西格斯蒙德营地。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_fightclubvelmistrku_hHY7</Cell><Cell>At the cemetery in Kuttenberg, I could meet the strongest fighter around. Maybe it's a superstition, maybe I'm going to fight for the title of grandmaster</Cell><Cell>据说库滕堡的墓园里能遇到一位此地最强的战士。也许那不过是种装神弄鬼的说辞，但也许我还是得为了最强的大师名号而尝试一番。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_fightclubvelmistrtr_wt4n</Cell><Cell>There's supposedly a grandmaster fighter living in Kopanina. If I challenge him to a fight I might win his title.</Cell><Cell>据说科帕尼那居住着一位大师，倘若我向他发起挑战，或许会有机会赢走他的头衔。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_hadkakonaru_JAIP</Cell><Cell>In the nomad camp, I met two riders whose disagreement about which horse race is the best seemed unsolvable. But it wouldn't be me if I didn't get involved and try to settle it. First, however, it was necessary to prove myself to them so that they would even consider me an equal horseman.&lt;/p&gt;</Cell><Cell>In the nomad camp, I met two riders whose disagreement about which horse race is the best seemed unsolvable. But it wouldn't be me if I didn't get involved and try to settle it. First, however, it was necessary to prove myself to them so that they would even consider me an equal horseman.&lt;/p&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_jizdnilukostrelbatr_ZsPe</Cell><Cell>Bibrek puts my riding and archery skills to the test.</Cell><Cell>Bibrek puts my riding and archery skills to the test.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_koneczabomysichvalek_LsWW</Cell><Cell>Every year, disputes over the pasture between Tachov and Zhelejov culminate in the men from both villages getting together, arguing, and punching each other in the mouth. But this year, they'll have a guest from Skalitz to share in the glory.</Cell><Cell>每年，塔霍夫和哲勒约夫之间关于牧场的纠纷都会升级，两个村子的男人聚在一起，争吵不休，互相打斗。但今年，一位来自斯卡里茨的客人将与他们分享荣耀。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_kovarskasoutez_iKaI</Cell><Cell>If you ask me, Zdimir the blacksmith boasts about the skills of his apprentice, Matthias, a bit too much. He even suggested we make a bet on who can forge the best hunting sword. The winner gets both weapons and a nice pile of groschen on top.</Cell><Cell>要我说，铁匠兹迪米尔吹嘘了徒弟马蒂亚斯的技能。他甚至建议我们打一个赌，赌谁能锻造出最好的猎刀。赢家可以得到这两把武器和一大笔钱。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_mapakpokladu_pr3x</Cell><Cell>In Pschitoky I was able to get a treasure map from a hired hand named Krizhan. Perhaps it will lead me to riches.</Cell><Cell>我从普西托克的一位名为克日然的雇工手中得到了一份藏宝图，或许它会指引我走向暴富之路。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_pasacek_nechuta_bwDt</Cell><Cell>The shepherd boy Natan thinks a werewolf is stealing his sheep. I'll see where these tracks lead me.</Cell><Cell>牧羊人纳坦认为有只狼人在正在偷猎他的羊羔。我得看看这些踪迹会把我带去哪里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_pasacek_zibrid_UkbA</Cell><Cell>Herdsboy Siegfried is having trouble with wolves.</Cell><Cell>牧羊人西格弗里德正受到狼群的侵扰。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_rasuvucen_1n5P</Cell><Cell>Life is anything but boring with Kreyzl. As soon as I finished one task, I got another straight away. This time I'm supposed to find a saltpetre pit somewhere in the Trosky region. The miller wants to use it to bring life to a golem made of flour.</Cell><Cell>跟克雷泽相处的时光真是无聊至极。每当我完成一项任务，就会马上接到另一项。而这一次，我受命前往特罗斯基周边寻找一处硝石坑。那位磨坊主想要借助它来给一个面粉做的泥人儿赋予生命。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_spravedlnost_gb4j</Cell><Cell>To have a chance with his beloved, Pavel needs help with a local farmer's son. I offered to help ruin the fellow's reputation.</Cell><Cell>为了能和心爱的人在一起，帕维尔需要有人帮他对付当地农夫的儿子。我提了个主意，说会帮他搞臭那小子的名声。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_zachrana_IRWe</Cell><Cell>Me and Hans Capon managed to flee from the raiders who attacked us at the pond. We found refuge that night with Bozhena, an old herb woman living nearby. She took care of me, but Sir Hans got worse during the night. Now I have to get my strength back and then help Bozhena care for Sir Hans, if at all possible.</Cell><Cell>我和汉斯·卡蓬成功从池塘边的偷袭脱身，当晚在附近的老采药女博珍娜家中避难。她对我悉心照料，但汉斯大人的伤情在夜间加重。现在我必须尽可能恢复体力，帮助博珍娜护理汉斯大人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_zakopanyzitrek_FMPL</Cell><Cell>In a forest near Bylany, there's a family of refugees who escaped the destruction of Mesoles living in an abandoned hut. The head of the household, a tailor named Mikush, never returned from Bylany where he works. I must set out to find him.</Cell><Cell>就在比兰尼附近的一片树林里，一间废弃小屋内住着从梅索莱斯逃难而出的一家人。裁缝米库什，作为这个家庭的顶梁柱，前往比兰尼工作后至今都未曾归家，亨利也将要为了寻找他而踏上旅途。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qdesc_zavodnipodkovy_Iu46</Cell><Cell>Janek, the Semine saddler's hired hand, is preparing for a big race, and he's heard about magical horseshoes, thanks to which a horse never slips and runs as fast as the wind. If I could forge him such horseshoes, he would pay me well.</Cell><Cell>雅内克，塞米鞍匠的雇工，正在为一场重要比赛做准备，他听说有一种有魔力的马蹄铁，能让马跑起来永远不会打滑，而且快得像风一样。如果我能为他打造这样的马蹄铁，他会给我不少钱。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qname_crosscountrytrosecko_7ve9</Cell><Cell>Horse races</Cell><Cell>Horse races</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qname_hadkakonaru_ZNx4</Cell><Cell>Horses for Courses</Cell><Cell>马贩之间的争吵</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qname_jizdnilukostrelbatr_eahd</Cell><Cell>Mounted archery</Cell><Cell>Mounted archery</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>qname_sq09__mlynaruv_ucen_r6e5</Cell><Cell>Materia Prima</Cell><Cell>原初质料</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>questendi_p_vajda_xq5N</Cell><Cell>The Voivode gave the amulet to Marika and she and Bohush returned to the nomads' camp.</Cell><Cell>司令官将护身符交给了玛丽卡，而后者也和博胡什返回了游牧民营地。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>questfail_jan_ze_suchotle_rqWv</Cell><Cell>Jan of Suchotlesky died before we managed to put an end to this matter. I'll pray for him this evening at least.</Cell><Cell>苏霍茨基的扬在我们了结这件事之前就死了。至少今晚我会为他祈祷。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>reinforce_mikes_s_kozlike_TyTD</Cell><Cell>Mikesh and Kozliek from Zizka's band could come in handy.</Cell><Cell>杰式卡的米凯什和科兹里克可以派上用场。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>reporttot_mluvil_jsem_s_k_X3qi</Cell><Cell>I spoke to the Kuttenberg bailiff about the Guild. He offered me to work for him and continue to report any suspicious activities.</Cell><Cell>我和库滕堡的执行官就公会的事进行了交谈，他希望我协助他工作，并继续为他报告任何可疑活动。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rescuingt_p_najdi_tibora_cBQi</Cell><Cell>The Voivode's son, Tibor, was taken captive by the Semine villagers. I must find him and rescue him. </Cell><Cell>游牧民司令官的儿子提波被塞米的村民俘虏了，我必须找到并解救他。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_bitka_u_preda_wfyw</Cell><Cell>László made his bed and now sleeps in it. I think that Jan will recognise me for my aid and that I deserve a reward.</Cell><Cell>拉斯洛自作自受。我想，扬会感激我的援助，并认为我值得奖赏。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_jana_sme_kras_H19N</Cell><Cell>Jan paid for his gullibility and is now with his brother Peter. I hope that László Farkas recognises my help and rewards me as promised.</Cell><Cell>扬为他的轻信付出了代价，现在跟哥哥彼得在黄泉相聚了。我希望拉斯洛·法卡斯能赏识我的帮助，并按承诺给我奖励。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_jan_umrel_nez_qQtV</Cell><Cell>Jan didn't manage to thank me before he died.</Cell><Cell>扬还没来得及感谢我就去世了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_jsem_sice_vsi_5bX6</Cell><Cell>Jan acted honourably and courageously, but still lost in the end. And I profited from it.</Cell><Cell>扬的行为体面而勇敢，但最后还是输了。而我却从中获利。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_s_janem_jsme__AnIW</Cell><Cell>I probably won't get any reward from Jan now. </Cell><Cell>看来现在我无法再向扬获取报酬了。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rewardfro_p_vsechno_krasn_GjyV</Cell><Cell>Jan was devastated by the loss of his brother but admitted that without my help, things would have ended much worse.</Cell><Cell>扬为失去哥哥而感到悲痛，但他承认，如果没有我的帮助，事情的结局会更糟糕。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rozsoudi__kdyz_mam_ted_ob_Zbtj</Cell><Cell>Now that I've ridden both races, I should talk with the horsemen and finally settle their dispute. After all, I know everything there is to know about them. Or do I? </Cell><Cell>Now that I've ridden both races, I should talk with the horsemen and finally settle their dispute. After all, I know everything there is to know about them. Or do I? </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rozsoudi__nez_jsem_stihl__CbAj</Cell><Cell>Before I could judge the riders, everything went wrong.</Cell><Cell>在我对两位骑手做出评判之前，一切就乱了套。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rozsoudi__s_obema_jezdci__d9YM</Cell><Cell>I talked with both riders. It was intense like before, but in the end, I had to admit that Bibrek's archery was the best.</Cell><Cell>I talked with both riders. It was intense like before, but in the end, I had to admit that Bibrek's archery was the best.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rozsoudi__s_obema_jezdci__VzbO</Cell><Cell>I talked with both riders. Like before, it was intense, but in the end, I had to admit that Mikolai's racing was the best.</Cell><Cell>I talked with both riders. Like before, it was intense, but in the end, I had to admit that Mikolai's racing was the best.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rozsoudi__s_obema_jezdci__WfhL</Cell><Cell>I talked with both riders. As always, it was intense, but I managed to reconcile them without taking sides.</Cell><Cell>我和两位骑手都聊过了。意料之中，气氛很紧张，不过我居中周旋，为两人调解了关系。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rozsoudi__s_obema_jezdci__xjOx</Cell><Cell>I talked with both riders. As always, it was intense. I wanted to reconcile them without taking sides, but my trick didn’t work.</Cell><Cell>我和两位骑手都聊过了。意料之中，气氛很紧张。我想居中调解，让他们别争了，但没奏效。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>rutinaavy_promluv_si_s_ko_E96O</Cell><Cell>Speak with Kozliek</Cell><Cell>与科兹里克谈谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>s54_trask_poslechni_si_st_5czR</Cell><Cell>Listen to Knuckle's proposal.</Cell><Cell>听取巧指的建议。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sabotazla_wine_CGUQ</Cell><Cell>Pour Chamomile Brew to the councillor's cask of wine.</Cell><Cell>将甘菊药剂倒入议员的酒桶里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_hynek_nelhal_ry_Sdmq</Cell><Cell>The captured knight, Hynek wasn't lying. Sir Peter of Suchotlesky is dead, yet László still wants to get his hands on Jan's money. I could threaten to reveal the truth. Or go straight to Jan…</Cell><Cell>那个被俘的骑士海尼克并没有说谎。苏霍茨基的彼得爵士已经死了，然而拉斯洛仍然想得到扬的钱。我可以威胁说要揭露真相。或者直接去找扬…</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_jan_me_posila_s_gRBP</Cell><Cell>Jan has sent me to negotiate on his behalf with László Farkas. Jan told me nothing more about him, so I'll have to find him myself in Sigismund's camp.</Cell><Cell>扬派我代表他与拉斯洛·法卡斯进行谈判。扬没有告诉我更多关于他的信息，所以我必须亲自到西格斯蒙德营地去找他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_jan_me_poslal_d_4KqX</Cell><Cell>Jan has sent me to Sigismund's camp to negotiate with László Farkas. After asking around a bit, I found out I should look somewhere below the smithy. I hope that doesn't mean half the camp.</Cell><Cell>扬派我去西格斯蒙德的营地找拉斯洛·法卡斯进行谈判。四处打听了一下，线索指向铁匠铺下面的某个地方，希望能好找一点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_moje_podezreni__sxLD</Cell><Cell>I immediately had the feeling something was off. My suspicions were warranted. Sir Peter of Suchotlesky has already met his maker, and here László Farkas is prattling on about a prisoner exchange. I could tell him I know the truth. After all, if Jan finds out what has happened, he won't let it go.</Cell><Cell>一股不祥的预感瞬间生起。我怀疑得没错。苏霍茨基的彼得爵士已经去见了上帝，而拉斯洛·法卡斯却在这里喋喋不休地谈论交换囚犯的事情。我可以告诉他我知道真相。毕竟，如果扬知道了这件事，他不会善罢甘休。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>searching_p_s_laszlem_jse_jjXT</Cell><Cell>I negotiated the terms of the captive's release and went to inform Jan. I didn't see Peter in the camp. László says he'll take him to the agreed-upon place for the handover.</Cell><Cell>我谈好了释放俘虏的条件，然后去通知扬。 我在营地里没有看到彼得。拉斯洛说他会带他到约定的地点进行交接。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>seber_obe_ukradene_veci_j_107S</Cell><Cell>The stolen items are in Goatskin's underground hideout. Some clever bloke drew a map to it, but Goatskin doesn't have it. Apparently it's sewn onto the coat of some fellah called Angel, who I hope is strung up on the gallows outside the city.</Cell><Cell>偷来的东西都放在了山羊皮的地下藏身处，有个聪明的人画了一张地图，但山羊皮没能拿到。那张地图应该是缝在一个叫安吉尔的人的外套上，希望这家伙已经被抓住吊死在城外了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>seber_obe_ukradene_veci_j_SHfJ</Cell><Cell>The stolen items are in Goatskin's underground hideout. Some clever bloke drew a map to it, but Goatskin didn't have it. He pointed me towards the gallows outside the city, where his "friend" and final owner of the map, a fellah called Angel, was hanging. Fortunately he was still there and had the map sewn onto his coat, just like Goatskin said.</Cell><Cell>偷来的物品在山羊皮的地下藏身处。有个聪明人画了一张地图，但山羊皮没有拿到。他说可以去城外的绞刑架，他的一个“朋友”，叫安吉尔，同时是最后一个拿到地图的人，被吊死在了那里。幸运的是，他的尸体还在，地图也正如山羊皮所说，缝在了他的衣服上。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sedmstate_promluv_si_s_zi_5ja1</Cell><Cell>Give the hand cannons you found to Zizka.</Cell><Cell>将找来的手铳交给杰式卡。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sedmstate_vysvobod_hanse__hVid</Cell><Cell>Get Janosh out of the pillory.</Cell><Cell>解开亚诺什身上的颈手枷。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sestrilej_strilej_a_nezas_tY6m</Cell><Cell>I ride without stopping.</Cell><Cell>I ride without stopping.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_dam_krejzl_neprekva_0XVu</Cell><Cell>Unsurprisingly, Kreyzl came up with a complicated plan. We'll find an ordinary wench from the Zhelejov baths, the miller will give her some fine clothes and perfume and take her to the Semine wedding. There we'll dangle her in front of Ulrich, the Trosky chamberlain. If he takes the bait, the wench, posing as a lady, will be invited to his chambers at Trosky and I, as her bodyguard, will have time to myself in the castle, ideally to spend looking for the book. But above all, this plan will finally get me to von Bergow. Now I just have to talk to Dorothy from the bathhouse and find out which of the wenches will be keen to attend the biggest celebration in the region. </Cell><Cell>不出所料，克雷泽想出了一个复杂的计划。我们要在哲勒约夫澡堂找一位普通的女人，磨坊主会给她一些漂亮衣服和香水，然后带她去塞米的婚礼。然后我们就把她留在特罗斯基的管家，也就是乌尔里希眼前。如果他上钩了，这位冒充淑女的女人，就会被邀请前去他在特罗斯基的房间。而我，身为她的保镖，就可以在城堡里自由行动，最好是把时间用在找那本书上。但最重要的是，这个计划最终会让我找到冯·波尔高那里。现在，我只需要和澡堂的多萝西聊聊，然后看看哪个女人愿意参加这个地区最盛大的庆典。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_dam_krejzl_neprekva_oNWE</Cell><Cell>Unsurprisingly, Kreyzl came up with a complicated plan. We'd have to find an ordinary wench from the Zhelejov baths, the miller would give her some fine clothes and perfume and take her to the Semine wedding. There he'd parade her in front of Ulrich, the Trosky chamberlain. If he took the bait, the wench, posing as a lady, would be invited to his chambers at Trosky and I, as her bodyguard, would have time to myself in the castle, ideally to spend looking for the book. But above all, this plan would finally get me to von Bergow. I talked to Dorothy from the bathhouse and found out that the wenches have had bad experiences with the chamberlain and don't want anything to do with him. Luckily, I was recommended a woman called Enneleyn of Wintherthur, who isn't afraid of the deviant chamberlain. </Cell><Cell>不出所料，克雷泽想出了一个复杂的计划。我们要在哲勒约夫澡堂找一位普通的女人，磨坊主会给她一些漂亮衣服和香水，然后带她去塞米的婚礼。然后他就把她留在特罗斯基的管家，也就是乌尔里希眼前。如果他上钩了，这位冒充淑女的女人，就会被邀请前去他在特罗斯基的房间。而我，身为她的保镖，就可以在城堡里自由行动，最好是把时间用在找那本书上。但最重要的是，这个计划最终会让我找到冯·波尔高那里。我和澡堂的多萝西聊过了，发现那些女人和管家有过不愉快的过往，因此不想和他有任何瓜葛。幸运的是，有人向我推荐了一位女士——温特图尔的恩内琳，她不怕那位变态管家。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pit_nejdriv_jsem_po_3MHG</Cell><Cell>First, I had to deal with the cellar guard. Fortunately, I managed to get rid of him. I managed to find the booze in the cellar, now I just have to bring it to Jurko.</Cell><Cell>我要做的第一件事就是应付地窖守卫，所幸我成功搞定了他，谁曾想到他竟然和那帮摩拉维亚人一样欲求解渴。我已在地窖中找到那些酒水，当前只需带给朱尔科即可。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pit_nejdriv_jsem_po_gDQi</Cell><Cell>First, I had to deal with the cellar guard. Fortunately, I managed to get rid of him. Now I have to find the booze in the cellar.</Cell><Cell>我要做的第一件事就是应付地窖守卫，所幸我成功搞定了他，谁曾想到他竟然和那帮摩拉维亚人一样欲求解渴。现在我得到地窖里找出那些酒水。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pit_nejdriv_jsem_po_YHMv</Cell><Cell>First, I had to deal with the cellar guard. Fortunately, I managed to get rid of him. I also found the booze in the cellar, so I brought it to Jurko as quickly as I could before their thirst would make them do something foolish. Of course, we had to raise a toast or two to my success.</Cell><Cell>我要做的第一件事就是应付地窖守卫，所幸我成功搞定了他，谁曾想到他竟然和那帮摩拉维亚人一样欲求解渴。我已在地窖中找到那些酒水，趁那帮饥渴难耐的酒棍干出蠢事之前，我将酒水带给了朱尔科。当然了，为了庆祝我的成功，我和他们一起喝了一两杯。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_krejzl_nechtel__MCg4</Cell><Cell>Not wanting to leave anything to chance, Kreyzl knows exactly the kind of dress he wants to turn the chamberlain's head. I got hold of a red cotehardie of Tyrolean brocade, of course.</Cell><Cell>克雷泽希望事情万无一失，他很清楚要弄来什么样的衣服才能让管家眼前一亮。当然，我弄来了一件蒂罗尔锦缎制成的贴身红裙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_prinest_vino_vl_bsRq</Cell><Cell>Enneleyn doesn't want anything left to chance, so she'll mix a sleeping potion into some wine for the chamberlain. As she's using her own supplies of the potion for our plan, maybe I could bring her some wine as a gift. Maybe she could use it to boost her courage before the wedding.</Cell><Cell>恩内琳希望事情万无一失，所以她会在给管家的酒里加入安眠药水。既然她要用自己的东西完成我们的计划，或许我可以给她带些酒做礼物，这样她可以在婚礼前喝点来壮胆。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_sehnat_vonavku__x7wx</Cell><Cell>I need to find some Mintha perfume. The miller doesn't want his companion to arrive at the wedding smelling of horse manure and pine needles. That's understandable, but where am I supposed to find the perfume? Ale isn't the only reason Betty's tavern is always full - I could have a look around for the perfume there. The other option is to brew the perfume myself - the Troskowitz apothecary should have the recipe.</Cell><Cell>我需要找来些薄荷香水。磨坊主不希望他的女伴带着马粪和松针的味道前去婚礼。这可以理解，但我要去哪找香水呢？贝蒂的酒馆常年客满，原因可不只是那里的麦酒——我可以去那里找找香水。另一个办法是自己酿造——特罗斯科维茨的草药师那里应该有配方。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_pro_vonavku_minthu__SfW0</Cell><Cell>The miller didn't want his companion to arrive at the wedding smelling of horse manure and pine needles, so I got hold of some Mintha perfume for the girl we chose.</Cell><Cell>磨坊主不希望他的女伴带着马粪和松针的味道前去婚礼，所以我给我们选中的姑娘弄来了些薄荷香水。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>sezen_si__bez_potrebnych__5wCH</Cell><Cell>I can't start forging without the necessary raw materials. I should get them somewhere.</Cell><Cell>缺少必要的原材料，我无法开始锻造，得到别处去收集材料。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_checktheloot1_Z8Tf</Cell><Cell>Check Smil's supplies.</Cell><Cell>清点史麦尔的物资</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_checktheloot2_icdf</Cell><Cell>Check the supplies of the farmer Fowl.</Cell><Cell>清点农夫福尔的物资</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_checktheloot3_oxOe</Cell><Cell>Check Willow's supplies.</Cell><Cell>清点温洛的物资</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_checktheloot4_jqOH</Cell><Cell>Check Bynyek's supplies.</Cell><Cell>清点拜涅克的物资</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_loadupsupplies_JbdU</Cell><Cell>Load the supplies on the cart.</Cell><Cell>将物资装车</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_lootvillage_RAJH</Cell><Cell>Once you've loaded the supplies, talk to the commander.</Cell><Cell>将物资装车后跟指挥官交谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_prohlidni_zrane_StX7</Cell><Cell>Examine the injured villager.</Cell><Cell>查看受伤的村民。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_prozkoumej_moro_2iUZ</Cell><Cell>Examine the plague graves.</Cell><Cell>检查瘟疫病人的坟墓。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_searchthecellar_5mC0</Cell><Cell>Explore the cellar.</Cell><Cell>搜查地窖</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_sestrel_cennost_kQkC</Cell><Cell>Find valuables in the pidgeon loft.</Cell><Cell>寻找鸽棚内的贵重物品</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_speakwithcomman_g0D6</Cell><Cell>Talk to the commander.</Cell><Cell>与指挥官交谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>spizovaci_speakwithsomeon_DCQF</Cell><Cell>Talk to your superior in the camp.</Cell><Cell>在营地里与你的长官交谈</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>stanik_je_trapic_stanik_u_s2qg</Cell><Cell>The bully Stanley is already with the Lord. At least Darling can breathe a sigh of relief that no one will bother him anymore.</Cell><Cell>恶霸斯塔尼克已经奔赴天堂。至少“达令”可以松一口气，再也没人会欺负他了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>stanik_um_bez_stanika_zap_v0nN</Cell><Cell>The fights are over without Stanley.</Cell><Cell>斯塔尼克不在，搏击将无法进行。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>svatba_posbirej_jildo_ze__4rSe</Cell><Cell>Collect food at the wedding.</Cell><Cell>在婚礼上收集食物。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>svatba_vyhraj_zlaty_odzna_eeSt</Cell><Cell>Win the gold badge from Innkeeper Betty.</Cell><Cell>赢得酒馆老板贝蒂的金制徽章。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tady_mas__kost_kost_23Qa</Cell><Cell>I found the bones, now all I have to do is dig them up.</Cell><Cell>我找到了骨头的位置，现在只需要把它们挖出来即可。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tady_mas__kost_kost_kost_WFlG</Cell><Cell>I dug up the bones.</Cell><Cell>我把骨头挖出来了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>talktobal_konflikt_s_mist_EXgR</Cell><Cell>Conflict with the local riffraff was averted. Now I need to decide with Jan on how to move forward.</Cell><Cell>与当地暴徒的冲突得以避免。现在我需要和扬一起决定后续行动。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>talktobal_po_zazehnani_ko_czCr</Cell><Cell>Having averted the conflict with the looters, Jan and I decided on our next move. Tracking the band of Cumans won't be difficult.</Cell><Cell>在避免了与劫掠者的冲突之后，扬和我决定了我们的下一步行动。追踪库曼人的队伍并不困难。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>talktobal_po_zazehnani_ko_GUVB</Cell><Cell>Having averted the conflict with the looters, Jan and I have yet to discuss our next move. That's because I went away, bringing our quest to an unsuccessful finish.</Cell><Cell>在避免了与劫掠者的冲突之后，扬和我还没有讨论我们的下一步行动。因为我离开了，我们的探险以失败告终。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>taras_mura_finaltalkvilla_92Ug</Cell><Cell>Talk to Father Marian.</Cell><Cell>和神父马里安交谈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanla_jana_mrzelo_ze__cFTY</Cell><Cell>Jan regretted not getting his brother's body back, but he was glad that László got what he deserved…</Cell><Cell>没有拿回哥哥的尸体，扬感到遗憾，但他很高兴拉斯洛得到了报应......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanla_mel_bych_zajit__gBT3</Cell><Cell>I should go to Jan and tell him about László.</Cell><Cell>我应该去找扬，将拉斯洛的事告诉他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_jan_hodla_pro_s_m8x0</Cell><Cell>Jan is willing to risk his life for his brother Peter. But I serve the Lords of Leipa... The Lords of Suchotlesky will have to manage without me.</Cell><Cell>扬甘愿为了他的兄弟彼得赌上性命。但我在为莱佩的领主效力……苏霍茨基的领主们只能自己想办法处理问题了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_kdyz_jsem_rekl__9gl8</Cell><Cell>When I told Jan about his brother's death, he cursed László and his whole damned family. He has now sworn himself to avenging Peter. But we need more men for that…</Cell><Cell>当我告诉扬他哥哥的死讯时，他诅咒了拉斯洛和他整个该死的家族。他现在发誓要为彼得报仇。但要复仇，我们需要更多的人......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_kdyz_se_jan_dov_yj68</Cell><Cell>When Jan heard about his brother's death, he was devastated. The news about the impending attack was the final drop. Taking to heart the adage 'the best defence is a good offense', he told me to get ready for combat and find a few experienced warriors to accompany us to the handover site.</Cell><Cell>当听说自己哥哥的死讯时，扬大受打击。最后的一击，是即将发生的袭击。他牢记“最佳防御是一种良好的进攻”这句格言，让我做好战斗准备，找几个有经验的战士陪同我们去交接地点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_misto_predani_a_42OF</Cell><Cell>Jan was surprised by where the handover was to take place and the ransom amount, but he says the blood of kin can't be counted in coin. He also regretted that I hadn't seen Peter, but understood that in our situation I couldn't be giving orders. I should prepare for departure.</Cell><Cell>扬对交接地点和赎金数额感到惊讶，但他说亲人不能用钱币衡量。我没有见到彼得，他对此感到遗憾，但他明白，鉴于我们的情况，当时的我不可能发号施令。我应该准备出发了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_p_mrtvy_petr_na_mPRO</Cell><Cell>Jan, informed of Peter's death, still sent me back to the camp to negotiate the handover of the captive.</Cell><Cell>扬在得知彼得的死讯后，仍然派我回到营地，商谈俘虏的交接......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_povedel_jsem_ja_DGAF</Cell><Cell>I told Jan everything about the conditions of the handover, but kept the truth about Peter to myself, instead assuring him that everything would go smoothly. Now we must go to the handover location.</Cell><Cell>我把交接条件全部告诉了扬，但隐瞒了有关彼得的真相，向他保证一切会顺利进行。现在我们必须去交接地点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_p_sice_jsem_jan_mNxt</Cell><Cell>At first, I lied a bit to Jan, but then it began to gnaw on me. In the end, I admitted everything and told him the truth about Peter. Jan, understanding the situation, decided to exact revenge upon Farkas.</Cell><Cell>起初，我对扬撒了谎，但后来我于心不忍。最后，我承认了一切，将有关彼得的真相告诉了他。扬了解情况后，决定对法卡斯进行报复......</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_p_vzhledem_k_ok_A7Kj</Cell><Cell>Given the circumstances, there's no use in talking over the outcomes of the negotiations with Jan.</Cell><Cell>鉴于这种情况，跟扬谈论谈判的结果没有意义。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>telljanwh_vyjednal_jsem_v_KY0b</Cell><Cell>I've negotiated everything I need to in the camp. I must now return to Jan and prepare for the handover.</Cell><Cell>我已经在营地里进行了所有必要的谈判。我现在必须回到扬身边，为交接做准备。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>temp_hlas_nakonec_jsem_se_59eB</Cell><Cell>In the end, I decided to end all the pointless running around the woods my own way.</Cell><Cell>最终，我决定以自己的方式结束那些毫无意义的林间奔波。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tmp_poraz_abych_byl_konec_PPEB</Cell><Cell>In order to finally be recognised as the winner of the blacksmithing competition, I have to defeat Matthias in a duel with the hunting sword I forged.</Cell><Cell>为了最终在锻造比赛中获胜，我必须在决斗中用自己锻造的猎刀击败马蒂亚斯。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tmp_setke_mam_jit_do_tabo_RVPP</Cell><Cell>They must have noticed we're gone, because the forest is swarming with soldiers looking for us! It seems Katherine's ally Mika is waiting for us with a wagon in some abandoned camp south of here, but Zizka's in a really bad way! I’ll go and find him and tell him what happened. But I have to be careful no soldiers see me. That would be the end.</Cell><Cell>我们逃跑的事情一定是败露了，因为树林里到处都是搜捕我们的士兵！凯瑟琳的朋友米卡，似乎就在南边某个废弃的营地，备好了马车等着我们，可是现在杰式卡的处境很糟糕！我得找到他，并告诉他发生了什么。但是我得小心，不能让士兵们发现我，万一被逮到就全完了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>tmp_setke_stretl_jsem_bor_VoJ8</Cell><Cell>Our absence must have been discovered, because the forest is swarming with soldiers looking for us! It seems Katherine's ally Mika is waiting for us with a wagon in some abandoned camp south of here, but Zizka's in a really bad way! I’ll go and find him and tell him what happened.</Cell><Cell>我们逃跑的事情一定是败露了，因为树林里到处都是搜捕我们的士兵！凯瑟琳的朋友米卡，似乎就在南边某个废弃的营地，备好了马车等着我们，可是现在杰式卡的处境很糟糕！我得找到他，并告诉他发生了什么。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_barber</Cell><Cell>Barber</Cell><Cell>理发</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_fasttravel</Cell><Cell>Fast travel destination</Cell><Cell>快速旅行目的地</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_hunting_spot</Cell><Cell>Deer hunting spot </Cell><Cell>鹿狩猎点</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_hunting_spot_roe_deer</Cell><Cell>Roe hunting spot</Cell><Cell>狍子狩猎点</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_laundry</Cell><Cell>Laundry</Cell><Cell>洗衣点</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_maplegend_pillory</Cell><Cell>Pillory</Cell><Cell>颈手枷</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ukovej_sa_pry_mam_vyrobit_K7LP</Cell><Cell>Aranka from the nomads' camp told me that the Voivode had been cursed. She gave me soot water in which I am supposed to quench the sabre so that I can transfer the curse that has been dissolved in the water since the Voivode washed in it.</Cell><Cell>我从游牧民营地的阿兰卡那里得知，司令官遭到了诅咒。她给了我一些煤灰水，司令官曾在这水中沐浴，而我将用这些水淬炼军刀，如此一来便可把溶于水中的诅咒转移到军刀上。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ukradni_m_pri_stavbe_bara_TODy</Cell><Cell>In the tavern opposite the Town Hall, there's supposed to be a commemorative coin hidden in the building's foundation. I have to find it and take it without being noticed.</Cell><Cell>在市政厅对面的酒馆里，据说有一枚纪念硬币藏在其地窖的墙壁上。我得找到它，并在不被察觉的情况下拿走它。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>umrel_ber_chudak_beruska__7UUZ</Cell><Cell>Poor Darling's now in God's hands. At least he'll finally get some holy respite from Stanley and others like him.</Cell><Cell>可怜的达令最终还是踏进了上帝的圣堂里，至少他终于逃离了斯塔尼克等人的欺凌，得到了喘息的机会。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>utok_vesnice_horela_a_my__PctG</Cell><Cell>There was a large garrison at Maleshov that we managed to draw out of the fortress to extinguish the fire we'd set. Von Bergow's mercenaries assumed that a horrible fire had broken out in the village and didn't expect an enemy raid on the royal chamberlain's seat. The village was burning, and we gained the upper hand.</Cell><Cell>我们成功引出了马列索夫的大批守卫，让他们前去扑火。冯·波尔高的士兵们皆以为那不过是村庄意外失火，也未曾料到他们的敌人将突袭皇家总管的领地。烈火之下，我们占据了上风。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vem_si_z__kovat_se_neda_j_op6f</Cell><Cell>I can't forge from thin air. I could run from pillar to post looking for iron, but luckily Radovan has a chest in his forge where I should find all I need.</Cell><Cell>我不能空手锻造。我本来要到处去找铁块，但幸运的是，拉多万的铁匠铺里有一个箱子，里面什么都有，应该够用了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vezninatr_dojdi_na_konec__qO96</Cell><Cell>Accompany Zizka, Katherine and Godwin to the end of the passageway.</Cell><Cell>陪杰式卡、凯瑟琳、古德温一起走出密道。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vino_ze_s_trvalo_ti_to_mo_nNS9</Cell><Cell>I gained the custodian's trust and he lent me the keys to the basement to bring him a bottle of wine. Hopefully, he didn't die of thirst because I never brought him the bottle.</Cell><Cell>我获得了管理员的信任，他把酒窖的钥匙给了我，让我给他拿一瓶酒。希望他不会渴死，因为我至始至终都没有给他带酒。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vloz_osta_splnil_jsem_o_c_iwns</Cell><Cell>I did what the widow asked of me, exactly as the old hermit prophesied. The widow Margaret's sins were forgiven and Jan's soul finally found peace.</Cell><Cell>正如老隐士预言的那样，我做了寡妇要求我做的事。寡妇玛格丽特的罪孽得到了宽恕，而约翰的灵魂也最终得到安宁。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vloz_osta_zbyva_posledni__4Hkq</Cell><Cell>All that's left to do is lay Jan's bones in the graveyard's consecrated ground where they belong.</Cell><Cell>剩下要做的就是把约翰的遗骨安葬在墓地圣土上，那才是它们的归宿。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vrat_se_n_mel_bych_se_na__GNd4</Cell><Cell>I signed up for the Kuttenberg tournament, but then I chickened out. I should keep my word and go back. Henry of Skalitz doesn’t run away!</Cell><Cell>我报名参加了库滕堡比武大会，但我临阵退缩了。君子一言，驷马难追。我应该回到比武大会，斯卡里茨的亨利才不会逃跑！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vrat_se_n_odesel_jsem_v_p_lwjc</Cell><Cell>I left the tourney to itself and went to do something more useful. It'll be happening again in a week anyway.</Cell><Cell>我离开了大会，忙自己的事情了。反正一周后还会举办的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vrat_se_s_donesl_jsem_hro_w86p</Cell><Cell>I brought the magic arrowhead to Devil's Den, but Pasha isn't here. Only the other bandit, Hare, is still here. I hope he has the reward for me.</Cell><Cell>我把魔箭带到魔窟酒馆，但帕夏不在这里。只有另一个强盗黑尔还在。我希望他能给我赏金。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vrat_se_s_hura_uz_zase_ma_EgG8</Cell><Cell>Hurray! We have something to drink. Although… this moonshine looks a little odd.</Cell><Cell>好极了！我们又有酒喝了，不过这瓶私酒看起来有些奇怪。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vrat_se_s_ten_magicky_sip_0npC</Cell><Cell>Sakra! Pasha isn't at the Devil's Den, and things with his lackey didn't go according to plan.</Cell><Cell>妈的！帕夏不在魔窑，他的狗腿子没按计划行事。</Cell></Row>
如果我愿意，还可以穿戴绗缝衬裤，但不能穿戴任何金属类护腿。
<Row><Cell>vyhledej__jindra_si_v_dia_eUut</Cell><Cell>I imagined all kinds of people, but it never occurred to me that this grandmaster would be a solitary herbalist.</Cell><Cell>我设想过无数种情况，却未曾料到这位大师竟是一个与世隔绝的草药师。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyhledej__kutnohorsky_zap_Y7yi</Cell><Cell>Luckily, the Kuttenberg fighter is a mere mortal. His name is Frantishek and he works here as a gravedigger.</Cell><Cell>还好那位库滕堡搏击手是人非鬼，其名为弗朗特齐歇克，是这片墓园的掘墓人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyhraj_zl_nakonec_jsem_ho_Icyz</Cell><Cell>I got the gold badge in the end. At first, Betty didn't want to, but she eventually agreed to play for the badge, and I was able to win it.</Cell><Cell>我终于赢得了那枚金制徽章。 贝蒂起初并不乐意接受挑战，但最终还是同意以徽章为赌注进行比赛，而我最终在比赛中胜出。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vykopej_h_pokud_chci_vdov_FpIK</Cell><Cell>If I'm going to help the widow, I have to dig a grave in consecrated ground and lay Jan's remains to rest here.</Cell><Cell>如果我要帮助这个寡妇，我必须在圣土上挖一个坟墓，将约翰的遗体安葬在这里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vykovej_s_abych_mateje_po_lNAu</Cell><Cell>To beat Matthias, I have to forge a better hunting sword than him. </Cell><Cell>要打败马蒂亚斯，我必须锻造一把胜过他的猎刀。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vykovej_s_tesak_jsem_vyko_LqhE</Cell><Cell>I forged a hunting sword, now I have to hope it will be better than Matthias'.</Cell><Cell>我锻造了一把猎刀，只希望它能胜过马蒂亚斯锻造的猎刀。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__dle_otce_prokop_rXWA</Cell><Cell>According to Father Prokop, Jarka was a kind girl who served the local von Grolle family. Father Prokop feels responsible, but mainly blames a wandering minstrel named William.</Cell><Cell>通过与普罗科普神父了解得知，贾卡生前是个好姑娘，还曾服侍过冯·格罗尔一家。尽管心怀愧疚，但神父普罗科普还是将贾卡的死怪罪到了一位叫威廉的吟游诗人头上。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__hospodska_me_va_Bn23</Cell><Cell>The innkeeper told me that the old hermit had sold his soul to the devil. But later I found evidence that this had nothing to do with the devil. There was money and old documents in a hiding place beneath the roadside cross, as well as a new cloak of the Order. It must have been hidden there by the mysterious rider. Why he'd been digging there and what he took is anyone's guess, though. In any case, his horse is still in Apollonia, so the stranger hasn't left yet. Unless he's dead, of course. But maybe he was threatening to kill the hermit, or could he have already killed him?</Cell><Cell>旅店老板告诉我，这个老隐士已经把灵魂卖给了魔鬼。但后来我发现了证据，表明这与魔鬼无关。在路边十字架下面的藏身之处有钱和旧文书，还有一件新的骑士团斗篷。一定是那个神秘的骑手藏在那里的。不过，他为什么要在那里挖掘，他拿了什么东西，谁也说不准。无论如何，既然马还在阿波罗尼亚，那说明这个陌生人还没有离开。当然，除非他已经死了。但也许他威胁要杀了那个隐士，或者他可能已经杀了？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__jarka_nejstarsi_c3Oh</Cell><Cell>Jarka, the oldest victim of the mad murderer, was the ward of a local priest, Father Prokop. It shouldn't be too hard to track him down and talk to him about Jarka and her condition before the murder.</Cell><Cell>贾卡是头几位惨遭疯狂杀手谋害的姑娘，同时也是当地牧师普罗科普神父的养女。要想找到这位神父并与他谈论贾卡及其生前境况并非难事。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__nepodarilo_se_m_KLSW</Cell><Cell>I didn't manage to learn anything more from Father Prokop about the life and death of his ward Jarka, and so the investigation has hit a dead end. Just like Father Prokop.</Cell><Cell>我没能向普罗科普神父打探到任何与其养女贾卡生死相关的信息。正如一命呜呼的神父，案件调查的进展也因此被中断。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vypatrej__podarilo_se_mi__3ykB</Cell><Cell>I managed to glean from Father Prokop that Jarka was pregnant, so it was a double murder. Perhaps the father of the child wanted to silence the mother before she disgraced  him?</Cell><Cell>通过向普罗科普神父了解得知，当时的贾卡已经怀有身孕，因此那凶手实际上害死了两条人命。难道是孩子父亲担忧名誉扫地，才杀害了贾卡？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyres_ber_potom_co_jsem_v_syfW</Cell><Cell>After I won all the bouts, Tobias, who everyone calls Darling, asked me to have one more bout with him, which I would lose on purpose, in hopes of Stanley leaving him alone. I didn't want to cheat though and Darling will have to deal with it himself.</Cell><Cell>未尝一败的我完成了所有搏斗，而这位人称“达令”的托比亚斯却还想向我发起挑战，并希望我故意输掉对局，好让他不再受到斯塔尼克的烦扰。但我并不想作弊，就让这个“达令”好自为之吧。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyrob_pod_celedin_je_mrtv_9ev6</Cell><Cell>Stable hand Janek is dead; now the horseshoes will be of no use to him...</Cell><Cell>马棚工人雅内克死了。马蹄铁他是用不上了……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyrob_pod_ted_kdyz_vim_ja_3qUM</Cell><Cell>Now that I know how, I can forge Janek his own set of spiked horseshoes.</Cell><Cell>现在知道了制作方法，我就可以为雅内克打造带刺马蹄铁了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyrob_pod_vyrobil_jsem_ce_eEz6</Cell><Cell>I forged spiked horseshoes for Janek.</Cell><Cell>我为雅内克打造了带刺马蹄铁。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vysetri_v_k_ranenemu_cher_BbSI</Cell><Cell>Someone got to the wounded Chertan and poisoned him. Musa the physician is a suspect, but I find it hard to believe he did it. Unfortunately, that's exactly what camp commander Grozav believes, so he sent for the royal executioner to get rid of Musa. My "commander" Katz isn't going to stand for this, so he ordered me to find the real murderer. Until I do, neither he nor the cannon I need will leave the camp.</Cell><Cell>有人接近并毒害了负伤的赫尔坦，医生穆萨成了犯罪嫌疑人，尽管我很难相信此事由他所为。但可惜的是，营地指挥官格罗扎夫却对此深信不疑，所以他派出了皇家刽子手前去处置穆萨，而我的“长官”卡茨不想让此事发生，因此下令要我找出真正的凶手。在我完成任务之前，他和那台我要找的火炮都不会离开营地。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vystopuj__ovce_pasacka_ne_WQSB</Cell><Cell>The shepherd boy Natan's sheep are mysteriously disappearing. I promised to help him. I should try to track down this werewolf. At a nearby crossroads I found a bloody stain and a broken arrow. I think Mutt should be able to sniff this werewolf out.</Cell><Cell>牧羊人纳坦的羊羔神秘失踪，我答应会给他提供帮助。我得想办法追查到那只狼人。在附近的路口处，我发现了一记血渍和一支折断的箭矢。牧羊人认为呆呆应该可以帮我们揪出这只狼人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vystopuj__ovce_pasacka_ne_xtcF</Cell><Cell>The shepherd boy Natan's sheep are mysteriously disappearing. I promised to help him. I should try to track down this werewolf. Perhaps the best thing would be to start at the nearest crossroads, just north of Natan's hut, where he discovered a bloody stain.</Cell><Cell>牧羊人纳坦的羊羔神秘失踪，我答应会给他提供帮助。我得想办法追查到那只狼人，从附近最近的路口开始调查或许是最好的选择，而那些路口就在纳坦小屋的北边，纳坦也曾在那里发现了血渍。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vysvobod__hans_je_na_pran_BnSv</Cell><Cell>I have to free Janosh now. The local bailiff gave me the keys to let Janosh out of the pillory after I treated the wounded villager.</Cell><Cell>现在我必须释放亚诺什。在医治了受伤村民后，我从执行官那里拿到了解开颈手枷的钥匙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vytahni_r_ted_uz_ho_musim_R7Nn</Cell><Cell>Now I just have to pull him on the shore.</Cell><Cell>现在我只需要把他拉到岸边即可。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyzvi_a_p_konecne_jsem_mo_A7o8</Cell><Cell>I was finally able to challenge Thrush for his gold badge. But when I beat him, I found out he had already lost it to Betty, the Troskowitz innkeeper. So if I really want it, I have to defeat her too.</Cell><Cell>我终于能挑战瑟鲁什并获取他的金制徽章了，但当我打败他时，才发现他早已将那枚徽章输给了特罗斯科维茨的酒馆老板贝蒂。所以如果想得到徽章，我还得打败贝蒂。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyzvi_a_p_konecne_muzu_vy_He7o</Cell><Cell>I can finally challenge Thrush and get that beautiful gold badge. This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.</Cell><Cell>我终于可以向瑟鲁什发起挑战，好赢得那枚精美的金制徽章，这可是个千载难逢的机会。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyzvi_hro_frantisek_uz_ma_fAux</Cell><Cell>Frantishek already has his most exuberant years behind him, but he likes to reminisce. I hope I win, otherwise I may be just about ripe for his services.</Cell><Cell>弗朗特齐歇克的风采早已不复当年，但却喜欢将过往成就挂在嘴边。但愿我能打败他，否则我或许就要亲自体验他提供的掘墓服务。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyzvi_hro_zadny_velmistr__3Ky2</Cell><Cell>No grandmaster should take his title to the grave. If I challenge him to a fight, maybe I'll manage to defeat Frantishek. I just have to remember his one condition and come to see him at night.</Cell><Cell>任何一位大师都不应该将他的名号带进坟墓里。倘若要向弗朗特齐歇克发起挑战，我就得尽力击败他。他要求我晚上再去找他，我得谨记于心。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyzvi_na__ceka_me_zapas_s_Sbg5</Cell><Cell>The fight with Stanley awaits me.</Cell><Cell>与斯塔尼克的决斗正等着我。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyzvi_na__jako_prvniho_ma_5IG7</Cell><Cell>The hired hand Tobias, who they call Darling, is the first up for me to challenge. He's a stableboy from Grund, but I can meet him in Horschan, where he goes to Thomlin's to fight.</Cell><Cell>人们称之为“达令”的雇工托比亚斯将是第一个我要挑战的对手。此人是一位来自格兰德的马夫，他也常到托姆林那里参与搏击，因此我在霍斯昌就能找到他。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>vyzvi_na__jako_tretiho_ma_2S23</Cell><Cell>The third challenger for a fight is the Bruthans' hired hand Stanley. He works on Thomlin's farm, so he naturally fights in his club. </Cell><Cell>我的第三个对手将是布鲁桑斯手下的雇工斯塔尼克，此人平日就在托姆林的农场里干活，因此在他的俱乐部里打搏击倒也不足为奇。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>wine_nared_vino_XHNf</Cell><Cell>I heard that the councillor has his own personal cask of wine somewhere here, and that chamomile doesn't agree with him! So I reckon he won't be happy if I add some Chamomile Brew to his wine. Now I just have to find the cask. It's somewhere in the pantry and stands on tall legs, it seems.</Cell><Cell>据说那位议员在此地私藏了一桶红酒，有了甘菊药剂可不允许这样的事情发生！如果我往他的红酒里渗入甘菊药剂，估计他就得咬牙切齿咯。而现在我要做的就是找到那桶酒，看来它应该储藏室里，存放在高挑支架上。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>wine_videli_me_pri_redeni_Zjrg</Cell><Cell>Kurva! I was seen pouring the brew into the cask, so there's no chance they'll serve this wine to Naaz now. I have to find another way to spoil his visit, otherwise the Kingfisher baths will go down the drain.</Cell><Cell>Kurva（该死）！有人看到我将甘菊药剂倒进了那桶酒里，既然如此他们绝对不会再用来招待纳兹。我得想点别的办法来搞砸他的本次造访，不然翠鸟澡堂将会一落千丈。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>wine_vino_jsem_naredil_do_vY9c</Cell><Cell>I found Naaz's cask and poured Chamomile Brew into it. Let's hope the Councillor drinks a lot and feels sick as a dog.</Cell><Cell>我找到了纳兹的那桶红酒，并朝里灌注了甘菊药剂。希望他喝得痛快，也拉个痛快。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_jana_planovane_miro_UA1T</Cell><Cell>The idea of a peaceful handover was a naive one. First an argument broke out that soon grew into a fight. I had to make a quick decision. Jan might be honourable, but he's also naive, dangerously so. There is a war on, and in war, it's the strong that win. And Baron Farkas is strong. I'm not proud of it, but he offered a better deal. At least Jan is with Peter now.</Cell><Cell>和平交接的想法太过天真。双方先是发生了争执，很快就发展成争斗。我不得不迅速做出决定。扬可能品格高尚，但他也很天真，这很危险。现在一场战争正在进行，而在战争中，强者才能获胜。而法卡斯男爵是强者。这事虽并不光彩，但他给出的条件更好。至少扬现在和彼得在一起了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_jana_planovane_miro_uIWj</Cell><Cell>The idea of a peaceful handover was a naive one. First an argument broke out that soon grew into a fight. I had to make a quick decision. Jan might be honourable, but he's also naive, dangerously so. There is a war on, and in war, it's the strong that win. And Baron Farkas is strong. </Cell><Cell>和平交接的想法太过天真。双方先是发生了争执，很快就发展成争斗。我不得不迅速做出决定。扬可能品格高尚，但他也很天真，这很危险。现在一场战争正在进行，而在战争中，强者才能获胜。而法卡斯男爵是强者。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_pis_pista_je_ze_hry_xT5Q</Cell><Cell>Istvan's dead. I finally got my revenge for everything that treacherous bastard did to us.And the main thing is I got my father's sword back.</Cell><Cell>伊斯特万死了，我总算得以仇报让这个奸诈的狗杂种为他的所作所为付出了代价。最重要的是我拿回了父亲的剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_pro_dle_dlouhe_deba_Z3QR</Cell><Cell>After much debate and argument we decided that Father Prokop was the murderer. I then killed him and hopefully stopped his murderous rampage.</Cell><Cell>经过费尽心力的探究与讨论后，我们断定是普罗科普神父就是杀人凶手。随后我便将其杀死，只愿能以此终结他的屠杀行径。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_pro_dle_nasi_dlouhe_CvDv</Cell><Cell>After a long debate in which we concluded Father Prokop was the murderer, I just couldn't bring myself to kill the old man. I didn't want to have that on my conscience. </Cell><Cell>经过了漫长的探讨，我们得出了普罗科普神父就是凶手的结论，但是并不想让自己良心不安的我，无法下手杀死一位年迈的老者。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zabij_pro_dohodli_jsme_se_LGRP</Cell><Cell>We agreed that Father Prokop was the murderer and that we needed to kill him to stop his murderous rampage.</Cell><Cell>我们都认为普罗科普神父就是杀人凶手，为阻止他惨无人道的屠杀行为，我们必须把他杀死。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zacni_boj_bojuj_VHrk</Cell><Cell>A-Ha! Now I'm going to show everyone what Henry of Skalitz can do with a blade!</Cell><Cell>来呀！现在就让众人见识见识，斯卡里茨的亨利持剑在手时能使出怎样的本事！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zacni_kov_nakonec_jsem_me_Fcs6</Cell><Cell>In the end I had more important things to do than forge a sword.</Cell><Cell>比起锻造一把剑，我有更重要的事情要做。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zacni_s_k_pak_jsem_se_do__QW57</Cell><Cell>I got started, but it's a long time since I helped my father. Thankfully, Radovan is standing by if I need help with anything.</Cell><Cell>开始锻造了，但我已很久没有帮父亲做事了。还好拉多万就在我旁边，如果我有任何不懂的地方，他随时都能帮我。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zacni_s_k_uz_mam_vsechno__GfP1</Cell><Cell>I've got everything I need, now I just need to forge the hunting sword and show what I can do.</Cell><Cell>万事俱备，现在只需要打造出猎刀，展示我的手艺就行了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zajdi_za__cas_vyprsel_zji_XYue</Cell><Cell>Time is up and the race is over. I need to speak to Bibrek and see how I did.</Cell><Cell>Time is up and the race is over. I need to speak to Bibrek and see how I did.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zapal_lis_hotovo_skrze_ko_4rL5</Cell><Cell>I helped the knights of the military order. The smoke created a diversion, and made the murderer miss.</Cell><Cell>我帮助了红星十字骑士团的骑士们。烟雾转移了注意力，杀手没有得逞。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zautoc_na_nasledne_jsme_p_nyXk</Cell><Cell>We continued on to the main bandit encampment. Lord Semine started negotiating with the robber baron who stole the cart, and it turns out both of the hands were in on it. Lord Semine's negotiation tactics were rather harsh, so it's no wonder they didn't come to an agreement. We had no choice but to attack.</Cell><Cell>我们继续向强盗主营地前进。塞米大人开始与偷走马车的贵族强盗谈判，结果发现两名工人都参与其中。塞米大人的谈判策略相当严苛，也难怪他们没能达成协议。我们别无选择，只好进攻。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zavodnipo_dones_jankovi_p_QkHc</Cell><Cell>Bring the horseshoes to Janek.</Cell><Cell>把马蹄铁给雅内克送去。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zavodnipo_najdi_podkovu_v_foUr</Cell><Cell>Find horseshoes in the nomad's camp.</Cell><Cell>去游牧民的营地里找找马蹄铁。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zavodnipo_pockej_par_dni__6Qyi</Cell><Cell>Wait a few days and then collect your reward from Janek.</Cell><Cell>等上几天，然后从雅内克那里领报酬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zavodnipo_promluv_si_s_ci_HWgg</Cell><Cell>Talk to the nomads about the horseshoes.</Cell><Cell>向游牧民打听马蹄铁的事。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zavodnipo_vyrob_podkovu_DdnV</Cell><Cell>Forge spiked horseshoes for Janek.</Cell><Cell>为雅内克打造带刺马蹄铁。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zbyva_pos_zbyva_poslednic_o1iE</Cell><Cell>Half of the time has elapsed.</Cell><Cell>Half of the time has elapsed.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zeptej_se_bozena_mi_porad_zTA0</Cell><Cell>Bozhena told me where I could find the Cumans. They're camping near the pond where the nomads are.</Cell><Cell>博珍娜告诉我库曼人的位置。他们在池塘边扎营，和游牧民族待在一起。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zeptej_se_lovci_tibor_mi__IsR2</Cell><Cell>Natan told me where to find the Cumans. They're camping near the pond where the nomads are.</Cell><Cell>纳坦告诉我库曼人的位置。他们在池塘边扎营，和游牧民族待在一起。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zeptej_se_z_poulicni_rvac_7iDq</Cell><Cell>Fortunately, we got out of the brawl with the Saints with our honour intact. Everything would have been fine had Anton not thought about his dear Tess and her birthday over a tankard of ale.</Cell><Cell>我们所幸摆脱了与圣徒帮的冲突，光荣撤离，毫发无伤。要不是安东喝得迷迷糊糊，还一直惦记着他那亲爱的小特和她的生日，事态也不至于走到如此境地。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_in_pobav_se_s_pred_YD4e</Cell><Cell>I am to ask Frank, foreman of the first shift, how many corves his "sonnies" mined on the feast of St. Petronilla. </Cell><Cell>我要向第一班的领班弗兰克询问他手下的“小伙”们在圣佩特罗尼拉纪念日那天开采了几车矿石。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_od_abych_si_mohl_s_32NO</Cell><Cell>To be allowed to play dice against Bailiff Thrush for his gold badge, I needed to beat Emmerich the apothecary, and get his tin badge. But he lost it in the meantime, so I have no way to win it. I hope Thrush doesn't mind.</Cell><Cell>要想与执行官瑟鲁什玩骰子并赢取他的金制徽章，我就得先击败草药师艾默里奇，赢得他的锡制徽章。但是那枚徽章已经不在他手上了，因此我无法赢得徽章，希望瑟鲁什不会介意。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_od_abych_si_mohl_s_jATd</Cell><Cell>To be allowed to play dice against Bailiff Thrush for his gold badge, I needed to beat Emmerich the apothecary, and get his tin badge. But he lost it in the meantime. In the end, I got it from scribe Gaibl, so I can continue playing.</Cell><Cell>要想与执行官瑟鲁什玩骰子并赢取他的金制徽章，我就得先击败草药师艾默里奇，赢得他的锡制徽章。但是那枚徽章已经不在他手上了，好在最终我从抄写员盖布尔那里取了回来，这样我便可以继续玩骰子了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_od_abych_si_mohl_s_xEu5</Cell><Cell>To be allowed to play dice against Bailiff Thrush for his gold badge, I have to beat Emmerich the apothecary, and get his tin badge.</Cell><Cell>要想与执行官瑟鲁什玩骰子并赢取他的金制徽章，我就得先击败草药师艾默里奇，赢得他的锡制徽章。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_od_jestli_chci_od__hcnG</Cell><Cell>To win the gold badge from Bailiff Thrush, I had to beat the Chamberlain first, and so I did.</Cell><Cell>要想赢取执行官瑟鲁什的金制徽章，我必须先击败管家，最终我达成了目标。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_od_jestli_chci_od__vMme</Cell><Cell>If I want to win the gold badge from Bailiff Thrush, I must beat the Chamberlain and get his tin badge first.</Cell><Cell>要想赢取执行官瑟鲁什的金制徽章，我就必须先击败管家并赢取他的锡制徽章。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_od_pokud_si_chci_s_2jVL</Cell><Cell>If I want to play against Thrush for his gold badge, I must get a tin badge from Radovan the blacksmith first.</Cell><Cell>要想与执行官瑟鲁什比试并赢取他的金制徽章，我必须先赢得铁匠拉多万的锡制徽章。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_od_pokud_si_chci_s_7HUi</Cell><Cell>To be allowed to play against Thrush for his gold badge, I needed to get a tin badge from Radovan the blacksmith first. Lady luck smiled on me and I won.</Cell><Cell>要想与执行官瑟鲁什比试并赢取他的金制徽章，我必须先赢得铁匠拉多万的锡制徽章。最终我得到了幸运女神的青睐，在比试中胜出。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_os_nasel_jsem_jano_AuNY</Cell><Cell>I've found Jan's remains. Thirty years on, all that's left is yellowed bones and a skull with a clump of red hair. No coffin - they simply wrapped him in a shroud and the worms soon got to work on him.</Cell><Cell>我找到了约翰的遗体。三十年过去了，只剩下发黄的骨头和长着一丛红发的头骨。没有棺材——他们只给他用了裹尸布，虫子很快就啃噬了他的身体。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_os_za_hrbitovni_zd_z8VG</Cell><Cell>Apparently, there's a spot by the graveyard wall where Jan's body is buried. Finding and moving all the bones into the sacred ground of the graveyard will be dirty work.</Cell><Cell>显然，约翰的尸体埋在墓地墙边某处。找到所有遗骨，并将它们移到墓地圣土，将是个脏活。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_st_p_kat_mi_rekl_o_CxoG</Cell><Cell>Heinz told me that at midnight, a large black horse, or perhaps its spirit, appears in the burnt forest between Old Kutná and Grund. He suggested I go there and look for the horse because he wants to make the guard of his new executioner's sword from its horseshoe.</Cell><Cell>海因茨告诉我，午夜时分，在老库特纳和格伦塔之间那片被烧毁的森林里，会出现一匹巨大的黑马，或者说是它的灵魂。他让我去那里找找，因为他想用这匹马的马蹄铁来做新行刑剑的十字剑格。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_st_p_podkovu_se_mi_3eAu</Cell><Cell>So, I’ve got the horseshoe from this supposedly spectral horse. It turned out to be just an ordinary animal mourning its dead master, but the horseshoe will still make a very fine crossguard.</Cell><Cell>然后，我从这匹所谓的幽灵马那里得到了马蹄铁。其实它就是一匹普通的马，在为它逝去的主人哀伤，不过这马蹄铁做剑格确实挺合适。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_st_p_to_musi_byt_u_lUB7</Cell><Cell>I can hardly believe it, but at midnight, a beautiful black horse really did appear in the charred forest. I should follow it for a while.</Cell><Cell>说实话，我半信半疑，但午夜时分，一匹美丽的黑马真的出现在了被烧毁的森林里。我应该跟着它走一段。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_zb_podarilo_se_nam_8jnR</Cell><Cell>After a seemingly endless search, we finally discovered the buried hand cannons.</Cell><Cell>在经历了一场看似漫无天日的搜查后，我们终于找到了那些埋藏的手铳。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_zb_potrebuju_vykop_lN1A</Cell><Cell>The hand cannons are supposed to be buried underground, but Kubyenka doesn't remember exactly where. Now I have to dig according to his instructions. Fortunately, I don't have to go looking for a shovel as one is leaning near a tent.</Cell><Cell>那些手铳应该就埋在地下，但是库宾卡却无法记起它们的具体位置。现在我得按照他的描述进行挖掘，所幸帐篷旁就倚着一把铲子，那让我省去了寻找的时间。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_zp_strazni_mi_zaba_MB6x</Cell><Cell>The guards confiscated the stolen seal for Rat. I should get it back.</Cell><Cell>警卫们为了“老鼠”收走了那枚印章，我得把它拿回来。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ziskej_zp_ziskal_jsem_zab_JNu4</Cell><Cell>The guards confiscated the stolen seal for Rat but I got it back.</Cell><Cell>警卫们为了“老鼠”收走了那枚印章，但我已将其追回。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zjisti_ja_vzhledem_k_tomu_cSu5</Cell><Cell>Considering that I couldn't be bothered looking for the cart, it's no wonder they're none too happy with me at Semine. However, the cart was eventually found. Seems the hands conspired with a certain robber baron called Gules and they simply drove the cart to him. Lord Semine and Gnarly recovered the cart and punished the culprits.</Cell><Cell>鉴于我不大愿意去寻找马车，也难怪他们对我在塞米的表现不太满意。然而，马车最终还是被找到了。工人似乎与一位名叫古勒斯的贵族强盗合谋，而他们只负责把马车驾到他那里。塞米大人和格纳利找回了马车，惩罚了罪魁祸首。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zjisti_od_prinesl_jsem_he_8XVh</Cell><Cell>I talked to Hersh the stableboy and helped him with his task. In return, he told me Nikvard had given him an assignment - to find something the nobleman had lost beyond the castle wall. The only trouble is he never found out what he was meant to be looking for.</Cell><Cell>我和马夫赫什聊了聊，并帮助他完成了他的任务。作为回报，他告诉我尼克瓦德让他去做一件差事——寻找贵族在城堡围墙外丢失的东西。唯一的问题是，他一直没明白他要找的到底是什么。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zjisti_vo_krejzl_puvodne__gEGO</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl originally meant to get the book through the Trosky chamberlain at the Semine wedding, but he wasn't able to arrange it. The castle was still closed off at the time. But now he knows me, and I have near unlimited access to the castle, making the whole situation a lot simpler. I found Erazim the scribe at the castle and asked him where the book is. He gave me a few names, the most important of which is Nikvard Libak. </Cell><Cell>克雷泽原本想在塞米的婚礼上通过特罗斯基的管家拿到那本书，但他的安排出了差错。那时候的城堡还处于关闭中。但现在他认识了我，我几乎可以不受限制地进出城堡，这就让整件事简单多了。我在城堡这儿找到了特罗斯基的抄写员埃拉兹姆，并问了他书在哪里。他告诉了我几个名字，其中最重要的一位叫尼克瓦德·利巴克。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zjisti_vo_krejzl_puvodne__hroH</Cell><Cell>Kreyzl originally meant to get the book through the Trosky chamberlain at the Semine wedding, but he wasn't able to arrange it. The castle was still closed off at the time. But now he knows me, and I have near unlimited access to the castle, making the whole situation a lot simpler. Now I just have to go to the castle writing room and talk Erazim the scribe. He should know where the book is.</Cell><Cell>克雷泽原本想在塞米的婚礼上通过特罗斯基的管家拿到那本书，但他的安排出了差错。那时候的城堡还处于关闭中。但现在他认识了我，我几乎可以不受限制地进出城堡，这就让整件事简单多了。现在我只需要去城堡的抄写室，和抄写员埃拉兹姆聊聊。他应该知道书在哪里。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>zucastni__vsadil_jsem_se__09j1</Cell><Cell>I made a bet with the master blacksmith Zdimir that I could forge a better hunting sword than his apprentice Matthias. If I succeed, I'll not only get some money, but also Matthias's weapon.</Cell><Cell>我和铁匠大师兹迪米尔打了个赌，赌我能比他的徒弟马蒂亚斯锻造更好的猎刀。如果我赢了，我不仅可以得到一些钱，还可以得到马蒂亚斯的武器。</Cell></Row>
</Table>
