<Table>
<Row><Cell>alch_fevertonic_step_1</Cell><Cell>You will need wine, 3 handfuls of feverfew, 2 handfuls of ginger and a handful of elderberry leaves.</Cell><Cell>准备好葡萄酒，三把小白菊，两把生姜以及一把接骨木莓叶。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_fevertonic_step_3</Cell><Cell>Grind the elderberry leaves and add them to the cauldron.</Cell><Cell>研磨接骨木莓叶后将其加入锅中。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_painterMedicine_step_1</Cell><Cell>You will need wine, mandrake, a river pearl and 2 handfuls of sage.</Cell><Cell>准备好葡萄酒、曼德拉草、一颗河珍珠和两把鼠尾草。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_painterMedicine_step_2</Cell><Cell>Add in the mandrake and boil for 1 turn.</Cell><Cell>加入曼德拉草并熬煮一轮。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_painterMedicine_step_3</Cell><Cell>Grind the river pearl and add it to the cauldron.</Cell><Cell>捣碎河珍珠并加入到大锅中。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_painterMedicine_step_4</Cell><Cell>Boil for 1 turn.</Cell><Cell>熬煮一轮。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_painterMedicine_step_5</Cell><Cell>Grind the sage and add to the cauldron.</Cell><Cell>研磨鼠尾草并加入到大锅中。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_painterMedicine_step_6</Cell><Cell>Using the bellows, boil for 1 turn.</Cell><Cell>使用风箱将其熬煮一轮。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>alch_painterMedicine_step_7</Cell><Cell>Finally, distil.</Cell><Cell>最后蒸馏即可。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>andelstrazny_oresmus_book_tVjY</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;God be praised, here begins Aristotle's treatise On Heaven and Earth, which I, Nicole Oresmus, dean of the church of Rouen, propose to translate and explain in French by order of the almighty and most illustrious Prince Charles, the fifth named, by the grace of God, king of France, seeker and lover of all noble wisdom.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;This work bears this title because it treats of the heavens and the elements of which the world is composed, the word world including the four elements contained in and under the heavens; for in this treatise the world is commonly interpreted otherwise to mean the whole mass of the heavens together with the four elements. Elsewhere world is used in several other senses not relevant to this treatise.&lt;/paragraph&gt;This work contains four separate books. In the first of these, Aristotle considers the cosmos as a whole, as a unit in itself, and discusses its characteristic properties; in the second book he discusses the heavens; in the third book he examines the views of his predecessors on the elements; in the fourth book he expresses his own view of the elements. The first book contains thirty-six chapters.&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;天主在上，本人，尼古拉·奥雷姆，鲁昂教堂的院长，将于此先容亚里士多德的《论天》。全知全能、盛名无双的查理王子，即天选之第五世法国国王、众贵士之才智的探寻者与拥戴者，已向本人委以嘱托，为奉其圣命，本人建议将《论天》翻译为法语并加以解释。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;《论天》探究天空之真谛、创世元素之内核，因而得此题名，所谓“世界”即与天上地下的四大元素息息相关；在此著作中，“世界”被通俗地解读为天空与四大元素。在别处，“世界”所承载的内涵各不相同，但却均与此著作毫无关联。&lt;/paragraph&gt;此著作由四本独立书籍组成。其一，亚里士多德于其中把宇宙视作整体，将其看作独一事物，并探讨了它的特性；其二，亚里士多德着眼于对天空的解读；其三，亚里士多德探讨了前人关于元素的看法；其四，书中阐述了亚里士多德本人关于元素的见解。而此著作的第一本书籍则涵盖了整整36篇章节。&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>andelstrazny_riddles_2_pa_6LuP</Cell><Cell>&lt;poem&gt;
Here on the north wall top&lt;br/&gt;
Sir Knight Pail von Bucket&lt;br/&gt;
Guarded the growing hops. &lt;br/&gt;
Now a shaft is all he can look at.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/poem&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;poem&gt;
从北方城墙上俯瞰田野，&lt;br/&gt;
窥见屹立于内外墙之间的稻草骑士&lt;br/&gt;
头顶木桶手持木剑，&lt;br/&gt;
勇敢地守护着花田。&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/poem&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>andelstrazny_riddles_5_pa_cl2x</Cell><Cell>&lt;poem&gt;
St. George has struck with his deadly sword,&lt;br/&gt;
The dragon writhes and spills its blood.&lt;br/&gt;
But St. George is not done yet.&lt;br/&gt;
Beneath his helm he turns his head.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
He fixes his gaze towards the &lt;accent&gt;east&lt;/accent&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Where there spawns another beast.&lt;br/&gt;
This dragon though is set on stone.&lt;br/&gt;
In its throat to your aid a &lt;accent&gt;window&lt;/accent&gt; will come.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/poem&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;poem&gt;
圣乔治刺出长矛，&lt;br/&gt;
龙血流淌，恶兽倒地。&lt;br/&gt;
但战斗还未结束，&lt;br/&gt;
圣乔治转过头去。&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
他将目光投向&lt;accent&gt;东方&lt;/accent&gt;，&lt;br/&gt;
新的巨龙于彼处诞生。&lt;br/&gt;
纵使砖石身躯坚不可摧，&lt;br/&gt;
喉处的&lt;accent&gt;窗户&lt;accent&gt;将助你破局。&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/poem&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>fairystory_houseofruthard_ntwf</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;D&lt;/inc&gt;uring the reign of the good King Wenceslas II of the Premyslides, a fever for precious metals broke out in Kuttenberg. Many people came every day to Gang and Kukliek to seek their fortune on the surface and underground. There was so much pure silver flowing out of the furnaces that even the last miner could get rich if he had not drunk it all before or had not met with misfortune in the mine. And those who didn't return were not few. But nothing could discourage the profit-hungry mine owners from opening new shafts.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Along with the mine owners, rich merchants also came to Kuttenberg, who rented the mines from the king to extract white metal from them at their own expense and thus increase their wealth even more. Proving that they were successful in their work, the patricians began to build great houses and palaces, and soon a large town with several markets and a town hall was established. A little later, high walls were also erected to guard the peace and wealth of the upper town.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;One of the first to come to Kuttenberg to try their luck was the German Ruthard family, who established an estate on Kolmark above the river Vrchlitz, where silver in the fissures rose to the surface in abundance and had therefore been mined here for ages. Jan Kunzlin Ruthard was a well-known mine owner and erckaufier in Kuttenberg, so when King Wenceslas II himself visited Kuttenberg, he offered him hospitality in his house. The king, impressed by the selection of food and the wealth of Ruthard's house, realised that Jan must be well versed in silver mining, since he was doing so well. &lt;/paragraph&gt;Imagine the king's astonishment when, after a good meal, Jan took him into the cellar, where the silver bars lay on top of each other like ears of silver wheat in a sheaf. Then the king asked Jan for the first time: 'Whose silver is all this, Ruthard?' And he answered him wisely: 'Yours, King, if ever thou hast need of it from me.' The king, pleased with these words, shook his head and told Jan that he had no need of it yet, but would remember it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Later Jan accompanied King Wenceslas to vespers in the monastery of Sedletz. On the way, the king asked his guide who owned the meadows they were passing through, and Jan told him: 'You, gracious King! But I manage them, and I pay every year ten white groschen to the abbot of the monastery for their use. Please plead with him, so I pay less.' &lt;br/&gt;The king promised to plead, and in good humour turned his horse to a willow tree that grew by the roadside. He broke off a branch from it and handed it to Jan, saying: 'Let this sprig be a reminder to posterity of My Grace for the sincerity with which you have shared your treasures with me.'&lt;br/&gt;Ruthard understood the king's words, and while Wenceslas stayed in the monastery, he hastened to the city, where he had the royal arm and the sprig painted on his shield. When Wenceslas saw the new decoration on his shield, he confirmed the coat of arms and with it the dignity Ruthard had achieved for his family that day.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;瓦&lt;/inc&gt;茨拉夫二世·普热米斯尔国王执政期间，人们对珍贵矿石的狂热追求席卷整片库滕堡地区。每天，堪克和库克里克都会涌来源源不断的淘银者，地上和地下均留下了他们追寻财富的痕迹。当时，不计其数的纯银从熔炉中淬炼而出，即便是搭上热潮末班车的矿工，只要他未将钱财挥霍在酒水之上，或是在矿场中遭遇不测，他最终都能腰缠万贯。至于那些一去未归者也不在少数，但无论如何，任何事情都无法磨灭醉心利益的矿工们不断开采的欲望。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;除了矿工以外，富商们也来到了库滕堡。他们自掏腰包，跟国王租下矿场，从中开采的白银更是让他们赚得盆满钵满。为了展示自己在事业上的成就，这些富商巨贾开始兴建豪宅与宫殿，很快，一个坐拥几处市场、设有市政厅的大城镇赫然屹立于大地之上。未几间，高耸城墙拔地而起，守护着城中的财富与安宁。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;在第一批前往库滕堡寻求财富的淘银者中，就见得德国人鲁瑟德一家的身影。弗赫利茨河中的裂痕常会有大量白银浮上水面，鲁瑟德一家在河边上的科尔马克修建庄园，多年来一直在那里经营着采矿事业。扬·昆克林·鲁瑟德是库滕堡远近闻名的采矿者，当瓦茨拉夫二世国王亲临库滕堡之时，扬将其接至家中，施以盛情款待。待客佳肴让国王欣喜万分，堂皇别墅也让他过目不忘，他意识到，能拥有如此丰裕的生活条件，鲁瑟德在采矿事业中必定颇有建树。&lt;/paragraph&gt;饱餐之后，扬将国王领到了地窖中，谁知眼前的一幕竟让国王瞪目结舌：只见银条一根接一根地叠在一起，就像捆起的银色麦穗。随后国王向扬发问：“这些白银都是谁的，鲁瑟德？”扬则给出了明智的回答，说道：“都是您的，陛下，如果您愿意的话。”听闻此言，国王喜上眉梢，但只是摇摇头，说他并不需要那些白银，不过会将此铭记于心。&lt;br/&gt;而后，扬在陪同瓦茨拉夫国王前往塞德莱茨修道院的夕祷仪式的路上，他们经过了一处牧场，国王便向扬问起了牧场归属之事宜，扬回答道：“那是您的，尊敬的陛下！只不过它现由微臣打理，我每年都会给修道院的院长支付10枚格罗申，以此租用牧场。还请您向他说情，好让我少付些钱。”&lt;br/&gt;国王答应了扬的请求，心满意足的他把马牵到了路边的一棵柳树旁。他折下一根柳树枝，递给了扬，说道：“感谢你甘愿与我分享财富，遂予你此树枝以表恩宠，就让它提醒后人，勿忘王恩。”&lt;br/&gt;鲁瑟德明白了国王的话中深意，趁着国王在修道院落脚期间，他立马赶回城里，将国王的手与柳树枝印画在了他的盾牌上。看到盾牌上崭新的涂饰，瓦茨拉夫承认了这一纹章的权威性，扬也因此为自己的家族争得了尊严。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>heavyweapons_skillbook_lv_6RzW</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Heavy Weapon combat.</Cell><Cell>一本关于重武器的技能书。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>heavyweapons_skillbook_lv_FtYY</Cell><Cell>You won’t let go? Alright, maybe you could learn a thing or two. Here are the 101 best mace fighting techniques from Master Fiore Furlano de'i Liberi de Cividale d'Austria. </Cell><Cell>还不愿意放弃？好吧，也许你还能学几招。这是大师菲奥雷·弗兰诺·德·利贝里·德·奇维达莱·达奥斯特里亚的《101种最棒的钉头锤战法》！ </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>heavyweapons_skillbook_lv_OnSD</Cell><Cell>Mace or Hammer?</Cell><Cell>《锤子还是钉头锤？》</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>herb_hypericum_desc</Cell><Cell>St. John's wort, the king of all medicinal plants, purifies the blood and dispels dropsy and kidney stones. Whoever brews it in wine arms himself against all alcohol, whoever brews it in oil prevents decay of meat. It is good also for stamina and sharp eyes, it unties the tongue and dispels foul moods. When used too often it loses its effects on the body.   </Cell><Cell>圣约翰草，药用植物之王，可净化血液，消除浮肿和肾结石。将其放入葡萄酒中煮后饮用可以防止酒醉，将其放入油中可防止肉类腐烂。也可提高耐力，使目光锐利。它可以使你的舌头不再打结，让阴郁的心情消散。但如果使用得过多，效果就会减弱。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>herb_paris_effect</Cell><Cell>Reduces stamina, induces sleep and lowers health.</Cell><Cell>减少耐力、促进睡眠、降低生命值。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>herb_urticaria_effect</Cell><Cell>Improves health, but lowers speech and vitality.</Cell><Cell>提高生命值, 但降低口才和活力。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>houndmaster_skillbook_lvl_a0JO</Cell><Cell>A skill book on dog handling. Can be read from level 15 of the Houndmaster skill.</Cell><Cell>一本关于训犬的技能书。训犬技能15级以上才能阅读。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>houndmaster_skillbook_lvl_eIpv</Cell><Cell>A skill book on dog handling. Increases Houndmaster skill.</Cell><Cell>一本关于训犬的技能书。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>houndmaster_skillbook_lvl_phLJ</Cell><Cell>A skill book on dog handling. Can be read from level 5 of the Houndmaster skill.</Cell><Cell>一本关于训犬的技能书。训犬技能5级以上才能阅读。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ius_regale_montanorum_ii__MJUG</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;On the Office of the Guards&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;T&lt;/inc&gt; he guards or hutmen are proposed by the miners, but they are to take their oath to the urburers. Anyone who has proposed a guard shall give a bond of 1/32nd of the mine, which shall be forfeited if the guard sins and neglects his duties, fails to heed the warning, and fails to appear for the hearing of the offence.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;On mines let a distinction be made between guards on the surface, guards underground, and guards of the forges. The former are to protect all that is extracted from the ground and to count the workers and the miners as they come and go on shift. They are also to search everyone when they leave to see if they are secretly taking ore from the mine, and if anyone is caught doing so, to report it to the perksmasters so that such things do not happen again.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The guards inside the mine are to see that the miners are not late for their shifts and are conscientious about their work, so that if they are not, their pay will be deducted.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Finally, the said guards are to ensure that the blacksmiths in the mines do not have their equipment taken away from their workshops, that the blacksmiths work properly, and to check the consumption of charcoal as well as the importation of coal for each week.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;All those appointed are then to see that no one works more than two shifts in the mine or in the forges, which would go immediately after each other in one day.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;矿山守卫&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;守&lt;/inc&gt;卫或管理人由矿工提名，须向矿区管理者效忠。提名守卫的人需提供矿场1/32的保证金，若守卫玩忽职守、无视警告、或未出席听证会，则该保证金将被没收。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;守卫依职责应分为地表守卫，矿场守卫及锻造厂守卫。地表守卫负责保护所有开采出的矿产，记录工人及矿工的出入班次，还需在每人离开时进行检查，防止其偷运矿石。若发现此类行为，须向经营者报告，以防止类似事件再次发生。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;矿场守卫负责确保矿工按时上下班并认真工作，如有违反，将扣除其工资。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;最后，上述守卫须确保矿井中的铁匠不将设备带离工坊，监督铁匠工作，并每周检查煤炭库存。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;所有守卫须确保在矿场或锻造厂工作的人不会在同一天内连续工作超过两个班次。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
so that they may be best suited to the office and most just.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;If it should happen that any one of ill repute should be appointed, or who should afterwards do anything to injure his reputation, the sovereign shall order the co-sworn or the royal chamberlain to remove such person from his office immediately.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Among the powers of the Affiants are to issue findings and, if there is no appeal, to refer them to the judge for execution. In issuing findings they are to have regard only to God, and to condone nothing, for equality is to be preserved in the court. The Affiants are to issue their findings promptly and without unnecessary delay, so as to save the parties labour and expense.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;If serious doubts should arise, all the Affiants and the court scribe are to be called together and all opinions recorded, so that in future mistakes may not occur.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;宣誓者&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;宣&lt;/inc&gt;誓者由国王或王室总管任命，从各界人士
<Row><Cell>ius_regale_montanorum_ii__RAIQ</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;On the Mining Courts&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;I&lt;/inc&gt;n the name of God and by the will of the king, we make it known that we establish the power of the court, that injustice may not occur. We further provide that every judge has justice in him, for it is he who judges who holds the scales and puts the weights on the bowls according to the law, as the parties to the dispute have testified or what he himself has learned of the dispute and procured by judgment.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The judge is to judge according to reason and to hear the parties with caution, and to have all that he learns with the affiants written down by the scribe, before the trial is decided.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The judge is to appoint one of the affiants for himself if the dispute concerns himself or any of his relatives. A judge is to be excluded even if he is in direct relation to the cause or person in dispute&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;The duties of the ushers and oath-bearers include, in particular, the protection of the poor from the oppression of the proud, that just prices and measures may be observed and that the royal office may not be disgraced.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;A summons from the ushers, magistrates, or sworn officers belongs to the king alone, for there is no one more fit before God to whom such dignity can be bestowed.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;上级法院&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;以&lt;/inc&gt;上帝之名及国王之旨，特此确立法院的权力，以杜绝不公现象。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;法官乃执掌天秤之人，应确保公正，依当事人证词及自身的判断，置筹码于天秤两端。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;法官应依据理性判决，审慎听取各方陈词，并应在裁决前，将一切证言交由法庭书记员记录。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;若纠纷涉及法官自身或其亲属，法官应委派宣誓者代为行事。若法官与案件或争议当事人存在直接关联，应将其排除在外。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;司法官与宣誓者应保护穷人免受傲慢之人压迫，确保定价及计量公正，不得使王室职务蒙羞。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;仅国王有权对司法官，治安官，及宣誓者发出传令，上帝之下，唯有国王应得此尊荣。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ius_regale_montanorum_i_k_Q9vp</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;On the Ore Distributors&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;I&lt;/inc&gt;t is the duty of the ore distributors to divide the ore from one pile into specified portions, which they are then to deliver to the various parties. First they separate 1/8 as the share or royal portion, then 1/9 for the mine smiths, 1/16 for the leases, and divide the remainder into 4 parts, that is, according to the shifts that did the mining.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;In the case where they do not have to pay 1/16 for the leases, this remainder of the ore is divided equally between the shifts. The place and time of the division of the ore is to be such that no one can miss it. If any one should violate this law, he shall be immediately dismissed with disgrace, and another shall be put in his place who shall observe it.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;矿石配发员的职责&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;矿&lt;/inc&gt;石配发员的职责即是将开采的成堆矿石分为多份，并交付于各个组织。首先，他们会取出矿石的1/8交给皇室，然后分出1/9交给矿场铁匠，1/16用于支付矿场租金，最后将剩余部分根据采矿班次划分为4份。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;假如无需将那分出的1/16用于支付矿场租金，则多出的矿石将平均分给各个矿班。分配矿石的地点与时间理应让所有人知晓，若有人违反此律，应当立即将此人革职并使其蒙羞，另立遵行此律法之人接替其位。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ius_regale_montanorum_i_k_TDnq</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;On the People in the Silver Mines&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;A&lt;/inc&gt;ll the people in the silver mining industry are divided into four groups according to their duties. Among the primary persons are the chief clerks, the "Urburers" (who oversee the royal share) and the Mint Masters, as well as the sworn burghers, judges and the Bergmeisters, who all have judicial powers. We may include the scribes of the appointed "Urbura" officials.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Other people are the lower mining clerks, i.e. the stewards, surveyors, joiners and watchmen, who conduct supervision in the mines.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;And a third group, by which we mean the mine entrepreneurs, namely, the primary mine men, the secondary mine men, and the "Lehenhauers" or "querks", who are chiefly to bear the profit and loss in the extraction of silver.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt; And lastly, the fourth group, which are all the other persons under the direction of the querks, of whom details are given elsewhere.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;采银行业从业者&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;在&lt;/inc&gt;采银行业中，人们会根据职责的不同将此行业的从业人员分为四大类。首要从业人员包括：首席文员，“Urburers”（负责监管皇室份额的管事）、铸币厂厂长，以及具有司法权的宣誓市民、法官和矿务长。为“Urburers”配备的抄写员有时也包含在内。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;除以上人员外，便是些官衔较低的矿业职员，如管家、测量员、细木工和看守，他们通常负责矿场中的监督工作。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;至于第三类从业人员，也就是所谓的矿工，分为主级矿工和次级矿工，分别被称为“Lehenhauers”和“querks”，他们承担起了开采银矿所产生的利润和损失。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;最后，第四类是querks手下的所有其他人员，详情请见其他章节。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
鉴于我们之间良好的关系，我希望能请您帮一个小忙。这封信的带信人是斯卡里茨的亨利，他是一个富裕矿工家庭的长子和唯一的继承人，其家族决定将他们的财富投资于他们的银矿及对应的冶炼业务。&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;paragraph&gt;All thefts of property, serfs and domestic animals will be punished by fines, whipping and the pillory. Severe deeds will be punished by branding. Whoever continues to commit evil deeds with the brand shall be sentenced to death.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;
&lt;paragraph&gt;所有抢劫和偷猎行为，若伤及他人性命，则处以罚款、鞭笞和颈手枷示众，严重者将处以烙印，再犯者将判处死刑。&lt;/paragraph&gt;
&lt;paragraph&gt;针对盗窃个人财产、农奴及家畜的行为，处以罚款、鞭笞和颈手枷示众，严重者将处以烙印，再犯者将判处死刑。&lt;/paragraph&gt;
&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;accent&gt;+&lt;/accent&gt;与他人妻子或未婚女子通奸者将处以鞭笞，并驱逐出城，该女子则处以颈手枷示众。若双方均为自愿，则二者皆处以鞭笞、烙印，并驱逐出城。&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;accent&gt;+&lt;/accent&gt;恶意散布谣言或在法庭上做伪证者将处以罚款或鞭笞，并处以颈手枷示众。&lt;/paragraph&gt;
在卢森堡王朝的统治下，上城区修建了石墙，随后下城区也修建了石灰石墙。此外，在原有的四个主门的基础上，新增了数道城门，大小皆有。西边的是古雷恩门（Gurein Gate），北边有卡斯劳门（caslau Gate），波希米亚门（Bohemian Gate），和面向塞德莱茨的克罗斯特勒门（Klösterle Gate）。南边有一个单独的赫拉德克门（Hrádek Gate），最新的则是东边的大卡斯劳门（caslau Gate）。每座城门都有各自行会雇佣的守卫，他们负责维护秩序和征收关税。商人如果没有从对应的城门进入城市，将被处以没收货物的处罚。
&lt;paragraph&gt;希望您和夫人阿涅什卡安好。我刚从格兰返回，扬·卡尼日斯基大主教告诉我，教宗博尼法斯九世决定支持那不勒斯的拉迪斯劳斯继承匈牙利王位的合法主张。您也清楚，自从您堂兄行使帝国事务以来，国库已捉襟见肘，但依然未能为我们应对南方奥斯曼帝国的威胁提供足够的保障。&lt;/paragraph&gt;
&lt;paragraph&gt;Because of this, the virgin goddess of the hunt, Artemis, took a liking to her, and Atalanta took a vow of chastity after her example. She sailed with the Argonauts on their expeditions and was one of the hunters who set out to hunt the Calydonian boar. It was her arrow that first struck the creature. &lt;/paragraph&gt;
&lt;paragraph&gt;Meleagros, the son of the Calydonian king who eventually managed to kill the beast, gave Atalanta the boar's hide in exchange for a promise of her love. He was killed, however, and the marriage never took place.&lt;/paragraph&gt;
&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;The fox began to look around, &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;She carried it outside panting hard &lt;br/&gt;
<Row><Cell>lorebook_grimoirsecretzer_qXbd</Cell><Cell>&lt;title&gt;Algoritmi de numero Indorum&lt;/title&gt;&lt;subtitle&gt;Treatise on Nought&lt;/subtitle&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;title&gt;《Algorithmi de numero Indorum（印度数字演算法）》&lt;/title&gt;&lt;subtitle&gt;论空无&lt;/subtitle&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lorebook_legendofchristia_T85B</Cell><Cell>To make a short tale of it, taking him with them on the appointed night they made him a party to their unholy deed: disinterring the sacred body, they began their desecration. For the priest's son did disrespectfully handle the jaw of the saintly remains and pulled it out. This they wrapped in a cloth and covered the rest of the body again with earth. &lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;From the relic they took, they kept what share they wanted and distributed the rest among their friends. But soon the wrath of God descended on them all. However, since, as is known, this happened recently and is abundantly familiar, I regard it as superfluous to put it in this account. I only write down that sudden and unexpected deaths surprised them and they departed from this world.</Cell><Cell>事情大致是这样的：在一个晚上，那位朝圣者带着普利比斯拉娃等人掘出了圣人的遗骸，牧师的儿子大逆不道地将圣人的下颚拔了下来，之后他们将剩下的遗骸重新埋回了土里。事后，他们拿走了遗物中自己想要的部分，剩下的分给了亲朋好友。但不久之后，上帝的愤怒便降临到了他们身上。然而，鉴于这件事就发生在不久前，并且已耳熟能详，详述实属多余，故此处仅记录他们意外身亡，无人生还的悲惨结局。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lorebook_oncharlesiv_part_o5o5</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;H&lt;/inc&gt;e was the greatest and most venerated of Czech rulers, whose legacy shall forever be indelibly etched into the hearts of the Bohemians and into their country, for no other ruler can come close to exceeding his deeds or his leadership. He was born in the year of our Lord 1316 as the firstborn son of John of Luxembourg and Elizabeth of Bohemia of the Premyslid dynasty, and thus through his veins flowed the blood of both of those famous families, but it was the Premyslid blood that later brought him, as emperor of the whole Holy Roman Empire, back to his country, where he establish his seat. For when the old king died and left the kingdom to his son, it was desolate and impoverished, and young Charles, who hastened to be crowned, could not yet properly speak the language of the Bohemians. Soon thereafter he learned to speak as fluently as any native and could also converse in four other tongues, for he was learned, and began to write a book of his own.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;他&lt;/inc&gt;是最伟大的，也是最受人崇敬的捷克君主。他的遗产将永存波希米亚人民的心中，铭刻在王国的记忆中，因为没有其他统治者能超越他的功绩和领导能力。他于公元1316年降生，是普热米斯尔王朝卢森堡的约翰与波希米亚的伊丽莎白的长子。因此，他的身体里流淌着两个名望家族的血液，但正是普热米斯尔王朝的那份，让他后来作为全罗马帝国的皇帝回到了自己的家乡，并在那里建立了自己的治所。当先王将国家托付给他的时候，整个国家是一片萧索，遍地狼藉，而年轻的查理急于继位，尚未学会波希米亚的语言。此后不久，他学会了这里的语言，可以和波希米亚人流利地交流，同时也会说其他四种语言。他学识渊博，并且开始着手编撰一套属于自己的著作。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lorebook_oncumans_part_nkLb</Cell><Cell> The appearance of the Cuman is unmistakable: a shaved head, a thick plait hanging from the temple, pointy moustaches, and eyes and faces slanted, like the Mongols and Tatars, with whom they are often confused. They are small of stature, well-suited for riding horses, and often they are so skilled in the saddle that it seems as if that is where they were born. They are oft armed with a bow, which they can use to shoot with great skill from the back of a horse, or with a curved sword, the scimitar, and their armour is so light, made to accommodate rapid movement. Cuman warriors should not be underestimated, for from a young age they are trained in combat and they serve as mercenaries, as evidenced by the King of Hungary and the would-be usurper of the Bohemian Crown, Sigismund Luxembourg, who assembled an entire enormous army of Cumans and who did plunder towns and villages, because there were no other fighters in Hungary who would advance with him on Bohemia.</Cell><Cell>库曼人的外貌非常独特：剃光的头，鬓角挂着粗大的辫子，尖尖的胡须，他们的眼睛和面部轮廓与蒙古人和鞑靼人相似，常常被混淆。他们身材矮小，适合骑马，他们的骑术十分精湛，仿佛生来就在马背上。他们经常装配弓箭，用精准的骑射带来杀戮；或者带着一把弯曲的剑，即“弯刀”；他们身着轻甲以适配更快的行军速度。库曼战士的实力不可小觑，他们从小就在实战中训练成长，是雇佣兵的最佳选择。匈牙利国王，波希米亚王位簒夺者，卢森堡的西格斯蒙德，当年就是雇佣了一支庞大的库曼人军队，在城镇乡村烧杀抢掠无恶不作，因为在匈牙利没有其他战士愿意随他前往波希米亚。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>lorebook_onprague_part_E9i1</Cell><Cell>&lt;inc&gt;T&lt;/inc&gt;he seat of the kings of Bohemia, a city of grandness, whose glory reaches to the heavens. Amongst the great cities of the world, it is the greatest, rich in commerce and strong in arms, and endowed with beauty, the towers of which rise above other towns. Founded by Princes Libusse and Premysl, her husband and the father of the Premyslid Dynasty, with a castle of stone at a place called Hradčany, to which later quarters were adjoined and during the reign of Emporer Charles the whole of the New Town was built on the opposite bank of the Vltava River, with the largest stone bridge the world had ever seen connecting it to the Old Town, made of much stone and mortar, to which, according to legend, thousands of eggs were added for greater strength.&lt;br/&gt; &lt;br/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;inc&gt;布&lt;/inc&gt;拉格是波希米亚国王的王座，一座宏伟壮丽的城市，其辉煌程度人间少有。它是世界上最伟大的城市，商业繁荣，兵力雄厚，城楼高耸，美不胜收。它由丽波瑟王后及其丈夫，也就是普热米斯尔王朝之父，普热米斯尔建立。最初于名为城堡区（Hradcany）的地方建起了一座城堡，之后其他区划也相继发展起来，在查理皇帝统治时期，新城也于伏尔塔瓦河对岸拔地而起。新旧两个城区由世界上最大的石桥连通，桥梁由石头和灰浆建成。据传为加固桥身，建筑材料中曾加入了成千上万的蛋清。&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</Cell></Row>
裤子破洞，鞋子踩烂。&lt;br/&gt;
<Row><Cell>map_u49_mapakpokladu_uina_dOn3</Cell><Cell>Krizhan's treasure map</Cell><Cell>克日然的藏宝图</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>natroskach_zapiskyfelcara_m0cq</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt; Fortunately, the feverfew grows right in the forecourt, on the terrace on the path to the lower gate. I'm not a herbalist, so I had a bit of trouble finding it, as it looks almost identical to chamomile. As for the elderberry leaves, I visited the carpenter above the upper gate. I know well that they dye their cloth in secret right behind the workshop and then sell it around the village, so they have an abundance of elderberry leaves.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;幸运的是，前院通往下门的小路上就长有小白菊，露台上就有很多。因为它们看起来和甘菊几乎一模一样，我又不是专业的草药学家，分辨起来费了点力气。至于接骨木莓叶，附近的木匠那里就有。我知道他在作坊后面偷偷给布料染色，然后卖到村子里，所以他藏了很多接骨木莓叶。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>natroskach_zapiskyfelcara_NLe2</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;The scribe Erazim lay down with a fever, which probably came from an inflamed wound on his right hand. I have thus an occasion to try my new decoction against the fevers which accompany inflammations of various kinds. It's a simple decoction made from ingredients that are quite readily available. The decoction is prepared from boiled wine, three parts of feverfew, two parts of grated ginger and one part of elderberry leaves.&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;抄写员埃拉兹姆高烧不起，应该是他右手的伤口发炎的缘故，因此我有机会尝试我的新煎药了。这种药可以治疗各种炎症引发的发热，它的优点是材料易于获得，做起来也容易。用煮沸的葡萄酒、三份小白菊、两份磨碎的姜和一份接骨木莓叶就可以制成。&lt;/paragraph&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poustevnik_oldorderpapera_eNwQ</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;About the founding of the Knights of the Cross&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;There have always been many foreign religious orders in the Kingdom of Bohemia, but none of them have ever come from our roots. The blessed daughter of Premysl, Agnes of Bohemia, seeing the misery and suffering of her subjects, who, plagued by sickness and wounds, had nowhere to turn, founded in the year 1233, at her nunnery, the humble hospital brotherhood of St. Francis. By the grace of God, unity and devotion to helping their fellow men, the brothers soon achieved renown, so that after only two years the brotherhood moved to the church of St. Peter under the old town of Vyšehrad in Prague. Many clerics and priests now came with an interest in joining the Order, which was not even a real Order yet. &lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;In the year of the Lord 1237, through the intercession of the blessed Agnes of Bohemia, Pope Gregory IX himself took the Hospitallers under his protection, so that no foreign power could harm them and they would have to confess to him and to God alone. The Bull Omnipotens Deus established the brotherhood as the Knights of the Cross.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;heading&gt;《十字骑士团的创立》&lt;/heading&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;波希米亚王国一直有很多宗教团体，但皆来自外国，没有一个是起源于我们本土的。直到1233年，普热米斯尔受祝福的女儿，波希米亚的阿格尼丝，看到她的子民在疾病和创伤的折磨下无处可求，于是心生怜悯，在她的女子修道院建立了简陋的圣方济各医院兄弟会。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;承蒙上帝恩典，加之成员的团结与奉献，兄弟会很快便赢得了声誉，在仅仅两年后，就搬到了布拉格的威瑟赫拉德旧城区的圣彼得教堂。此刻，尽管该组织在当时还并非真正意义上的骑士团，但许多牧师和其他神职人员都纷纷对此产生了兴趣。1237年，在波希米亚的祝福之女阿格尼丝的斡旋下，教皇格里高利九世亲自将医院兄弟会纳入保护，以确保外国势力不能伤害他们，而兄弟会成员从此只得向教皇和上帝忏悔。后来，在教宗诏书《全能的上帝》中，将医院兄弟会确立为十字骑士团。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>poustevnik_oldorderpapera_kpIn</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;T&lt;/inc&gt;he history of the rise and fall of the noble and honourable order of the Knights of the Cross.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Thank God and Christ that He has been pleased to guide my hand and bless me in the unworthy thing which I have, perhaps, only presumed to do out of insolent pride. I give attention to work where others cannot, to record what is not to be forgotten. &lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;Concordia res parva crescunt. Discordia res maxima dilabuntur.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell><Cell>&lt;paragraph&gt;&lt;inc&gt;荣&lt;/inc&gt;耀而尊贵的十字军骑士团兴衰史。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;感谢上帝和基督，他乐于指引我的手，在这项因我个人之傲慢而染指的伟业之上亦赐予我祝福。我将专注于他人无法完成的工作，记录不应被遗忘之事。&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;paragraph&gt;Concordia res parva crescunt. Discordia res maxima dilabuntur.&lt;/paragraph&gt;&lt;newpage/&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_ammo_shot_scatter_name</Cell><Cell>Scattershot Powder</Cell><Cell>霰弹火药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_maliruvLek_potion_painterMedicine_name</Cell><Cell>Mandrake Decoction</Cell><Cell>绘师之疗愈</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_maliruvLek_potion_painterMedicine_usage</Cell><Cell></Cell><Cell>Léčí zdraví během delší doby. V lepších kvalitách zvyšuje vitalitu a neubráněné údery ubírají méně staminy.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_perfume_longWeak_name</Cell><Cell>Mintha perfume</Cell><Cell>薄荷香水</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_perfume_shortStrong_name</Cell><Cell>Lion perfume</Cell><Cell>雄狮香水</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_bane_name</Cell><Cell>Bane poison</Cell><Cell>“祸根”毒药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_chamomile_decoction</Cell><Cell>Chamomile decoction</Cell><Cell>甘菊药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_hooch_name</Cell><Cell>Moonshine</Cell><Cell>私酒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_hooch_usage</Cell><Cell>Henry's homemade moonshine. A strong drink that is sure to put you in a good mood.</Cell><Cell>亨利自酿的私酒，烈酒入喉定能让你身心愉悦。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_paralysis_name</Cell><Cell>Dollmaker potion</Cell><Cell>“玩偶”毒药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_sleep_name</Cell><Cell>Lullaby</Cell><Cell>“安眠”毒药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_sneak_usage</Cell><Cell>Increases thievery and craftsmanship skills.</Cell><Cell>可提升偷窃和手工艺技能。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>recipe_potion_stamina_usage</Cell><Cell>Increases stamina and increases stamina regeneration if good quality.</Cell><Cell>可提升耐力，高品质药剂还将提升耐力恢复速率。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_alchemy_iv_kcd2_EXRO</Cell><Cell>Sift the flour well, mix with lukewarm water and do not spare the salt. Knead the dough thus formed into patties, toast it on a hot stone and rub it well with lard and crushed garlic. Sprinkle the hot pancakes thickly with cracklings and raw onions and ingest three times a day.</Cell><Cell>将面粉筛好，混合温水，多放盐。将面团揉成饼状，在热石上烤熟，然后用猪油和捣碎的大蒜涂抹均匀。最后在热煎饼撒上大量的脆猪皮和生洋葱，每天食用三次。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_craftsmanship_i_0kUS</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Craftsmanship. Can be read from level 15 of this skill.</Cell><Cell>一本关于手工艺的技能书。手工艺技能15级以上才能阅读。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_craftsmanship_i_7Yei</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Craftsmanship. </Cell><Cell>一本关于手工艺的技能书。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_craftsmanship_i_bfmO</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Craftsmanship. Can be read from level 10 of this skill.</Cell><Cell>一本关于手工艺的技能书。手工艺技能10级以上才能阅读。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_craftsmanship_i_eBt7</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Craftsmanship. Can be read from level 5 of this skill.</Cell><Cell>一本关于手工艺的技能书。手工艺技能5级以上才能阅读。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_drinking_i_kcd2_5ly9</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Drinking and alcoholism. </Cell><Cell>一本关于饮酒和酒精中毒的技能书。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_horseriding_i_k_QrA0</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Horsemanship.</Cell><Cell>一本关于马术的技能书。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>skillbook_scholarship_2_u_A1FX</Cell><Cell>A skill book on Scholarship. Can be read from level 5 of this skill.</Cell><Cell>一本关于学术的技能书。学术技能5级以上才能阅读。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_antibust_gold</Cell><Cell>After an unlucky throw, you can &lt;strong&gt;throw again&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;three times per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>若对掷骰不满意，你可以使用该徽章进行&lt;strong&gt;重掷&lt;/strong&gt;。每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;三次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_antibust_plumb</Cell><Cell>After an unlucky throw, use this badge to &lt;strong&gt;throw again&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt; once per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>若对掷骰不满意，你可以使用该徽章进行&lt;strong&gt;重掷&lt;/strong&gt;。每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;一次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_antibust_silver</Cell><Cell>When a throw doesn't go your way, use this badge to &lt;strong&gt;throw again&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;twice per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>若对掷骰不满意，你可以使用该徽章进行&lt;strong&gt;重掷&lt;/strong&gt;，每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;两次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_bird_king_badge</Cell><Cell>The badge of the rightful king of the birds will allow you to roll an &lt;strong&gt;additional die&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;twice per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>正统鸟王的徽章。使用后，可在指定掷骰时&lt;strong&gt;额外增加一颗骰子&lt;/strong&gt;，每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;两次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_double_take_gold</Cell><Cell>Using this badge will double the point value of your last throw. Can be use &lt;strong&gt;three times per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>使用此徽章可以将你所选骰子的&lt;strong&gt;分数翻倍&lt;strong&gt;。每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;三次&lt;strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_double_take_silver</Cell><Cell>You &lt;strong&gt;double the score of your last throw&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;twice per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>使用此徽章可以将你所选骰子的&lt;strong&gt;分数翻倍&lt;strong&gt;。每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;两次&lt;strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_extra_dice_dice_badge</Cell><Cell>Using it will allow you to roll &lt;strong&gt;one extra die&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;twice per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>使用后，可在指定掷骰时&lt;strong&gt;额外增加一颗骰子&lt;/strong&gt;，每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;两次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_extra_dice_gold</Cell><Cell>Using it will allow you to roll &lt;strong&gt;one extra die&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;three times per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>使用后，可在指定掷骰时&lt;strong&gt;额外增加一颗骰子&lt;/strong&gt;。每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;三次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_extra_dice_plumb</Cell><Cell>Use it to add &lt;strong&gt;one extra die to your throw&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;once per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>使用后，可在指定掷骰时&lt;strong&gt;额外增加一颗骰子&lt;/strong&gt;。每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;一次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_formations_gold</Cell><Cell>You gain a new dice formation called &lt;strong&gt;The Eye&lt;/strong&gt;, consisting of the values &lt;strong&gt;1, 3 and 5&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>你骰出了点数&lt;strong&gt;1、3、5&lt;/strong&gt;。这个组合名为&lt;strong&gt;“全视之眼”&lt;/strong&gt;</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_alias_loot_aPinchOfHappiness</Cell><Cell>Happiness you can't find anywhere else. Side effects may include dancing in the moonlight.</Cell><Cell>你将获得从未体验过的幸福感。可能的副作用包括在月光下跳舞。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_alias_loot_brenekHuntingSword</Cell><Cell>Won't stop a belly ache, but it's great for slicing them open.</Cell><Cell>没法止住腹痛，但切开肚皮还是挺有用的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_alias_loot_lorecChalice</Cell><Cell>A golden chalice gifted to the vineyard by one Pippo Spano of Ozora.</Cell><Cell>奥佐拉的皮波·斯帕诺赠予葡萄园的金圣餐杯</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_alias_loot_pesekPotion</Cell><Cell>The poison works best when the inattentive eye focuses on the wrong person.</Cell><Cell>当目标漫不经心的双眼聚焦在错误的人身上时，就是下毒的最好时机。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_alias_loot_zizkaChalice</Cell><Cell>A chalice from some sort of bandit expedition. It seems to have a sentimental value for Zizka.</Cell><Cell>一次剿匪行动时获得的圣餐杯，对杰式卡来说似乎有特殊意义。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_animal_sheepCasings</Cell><Cell>Freshly extracted sheep guts. Carrying something like that around is a bit... disgusting.</Cell><Cell>刚取出的羊肠。随身携带这种东西有点……恶心。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_arrowTournament</Cell><Cell>An arrow designed for tournament shooting, not suitable for combat.</Cell><Cell>专门用于射箭比武的箭矢，不适用于战斗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_axebattle03</Cell><Cell>The horseman's pick is a light riding axe with a spike. Used correctly, it's a good friend in a pinch. Its sharp point can cut through armour, its blade through any shield.</Cell><Cell>骑兵镐斧是一种带有尖刺的轻型骑兵斧。使用得当的话，在紧要关头能发挥很大用处。它锋利的稿尖可以轻易击穿盔甲，而斧刃则可以劈开任何盾牌。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_axecuman</Cell><Cell>Cuman long-handled fokos. A fast and agile weapon of the Hungarian raiders. It can pierce light armour or the skull of a good Christian.</Cell><Cell>库曼长柄斧。匈牙利人常用的一种敏捷的武器。它可以轻易穿透轻甲，或击碎一个基督徒的头骨。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_axefancy</Cell><Cell>A lightweight, well-forged war axe. The blade forged into the point replaces the spike, which can be used to cut through the ring armour and the belly underneath.</Cell><Cell>轻便，锻造精良的战斧。斧刃被锻造成尖头形状，代替了传统的尖刺，可以用来切穿链甲，开肠破肚。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_axeWork02_kunesh</Cell><Cell>An axe made by the skilful hands of a blacksmith in Skalitz, it always seems to find its way to the one who drinks the most.</Cell><Cell>斯卡里茨的一位技艺高超的铁匠锻造而出的斧头，它似乎总是能找到那个喝得最多的人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bascinet_open</Cell><Cell>A helmet called a bascinet with a wide chainmail aventail that protects the neck and shoulders of the warrior.</Cell><Cell>名为“中头盔“（bascinet）的头盔，配有宽阔的链甲颈甲，可保护战士的脖颈和肩膀。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bascinet_open01</Cell><Cell>A helmet called a bascinet forged from a single piece of sheet metal. In this basic form, it has no bretache or klappvisor and therefore does not protect the warrior's face.</Cell><Cell>名为“中头盔“（bascinet）的头盔，有单片金属片锻造而成。这种基础款式的头盔并未配备保护片或翻盖面甲，因此无法保护战士的脸部。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bascinet_open02</Cell><Cell>A helmet called a bascinet protecting the whole head except the face, so it looks a bit like a bell. Very often used by marksmen because the face is not covered by any visor and it is easy to see the target.</Cell><Cell>名为“中头盔“（bascinet）的头盔，为除脸颊外的整个头部提供保护，因此形状与钟相似。这种头盔常由弓箭手穿戴，因为脸部未设面甲，便于佩戴者清晰地观察目标。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bascinet_open03</Cell><Cell>An older form of the bascinet with a removable wide bretache, complete with a chainmail aventail protecting the warrior's neck and shoulders.</Cell><Cell>老式中头盔，配有可拆卸的宽型保护片，还附带可保护战士脖颈和肩膀的链甲颈甲。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bascinet_open_Brunswig</Cell><Cell>A large bascinet decorated with a gilded lion statuette, excellent for jousting tournaments. According to legend, it belonged to the Bohemian prince Brunswick.</Cell><Cell>大型头盔，饰有镀金狮子雕像，适用于马术对决。据说此头盔曾属于波希米亚王子布伦瑞克。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bascinet_visor01</Cell><Cell>A helmet called a bascinet with a fitted klappvisor of an older drop-shaped pattern. The helmet is fitted with a wide chainmail aventail, so it protects the whole head and shoulders of the warrior.</Cell><Cell>名为“中头盔“（bascinet）的头盔，配有旧式水滴形状的翻盖面甲。这种头盔还配有宽阔的链甲颈甲，所以可为战士的整个头部和肩膀提供防护。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bascinet_visor02</Cell><Cell>A helmet called a bascinet with a fitted klappvisor. It has been pejoratively nicknamed the dog's snout because of its strange shape, but it is easier to breathe in it and is more durable than its older models.</Cell><Cell>名为“中头盔“（bascinet）的头盔，配有翻盖面甲。因其形状奇特，人们戏谑地称其为“狗鼻盔”，但它比旧式头盔更便于呼吸，也更加耐用。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_battle_shot</Cell><Cell>Ammunition for firearms, suitable for immediate use. The powder stale and the ball is a bit lopsided.</Cell><Cell>火器的弹药，可随时使用。火药略显褪色，而弹丸呈现微微的锥形。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_boots_ankle_courtier</Cell><Cell>Blending in with high society can be difficult. One must keep up appearances, but it's also good to move silently while sticking your nose where you shouldn't. That's what these boots are for.</Cell><Cell>融入上流社会并不容易。不止要保持体面，有时也需要悄无声息地行动，甚至多管一些闲事。而这双靴子正是为此准备的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_boots_ankle_pick</Cell><Cell>Quickly sneak up to your mark, then slink away. The motto of every good pickpocket!</Cell><Cell>迅速接近，无声远离——这就是每个优秀扒手的座右铭！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_boots_ankle_silent</Cell><Cell>Boots made of fine leather that don't squeek, clink, or make any other unnecessary noise.</Cell><Cell>精致皮革制成的靴子，不会发出摩擦声，金属响声或是任何其他不必要的噪音。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_boots_knee_high</Cell><Cell>A pair of mid-calf-high boots, practical for most every day activities, and can even be worn to social events.</Cell><Cell>鞋帮较高的中筒系带靴，十分实用，适合大多数日常活动，即使在社交场合中穿着也不显尴尬。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_boots_knee_soft</Cell><Cell>Soft, tallow-greased boots that don't squeak.</Cell><Cell>这种涂过牛脂的柔软靴子不会发出吱吱的噪音。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_boots_knee_thief</Cell><Cell>Boots of the finest goatskin make barely any noise, which is valuable to a certain sort of people.</Cell><Cell>十分优质的山羊皮靴，走起路来几乎不会发出任何声音。对某些特殊人群来说很有价值。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bow_c_b</Cell><Cell>Hunting bows are supposed to be strong enough to bring down larger game. This bow is made of ashen wood and is therefore one of the stronger hunting weapons that are still easy to handle. Most experienced gamekeepers and poachers will rely on it.</Cell><Cell>要想猎杀大型猎物，猎弓就应当足够强大。这把弓由白蜡木制成，因此是把威力相对强劲的弓，且易于操持。大多经验老道的猎手和偷猎者都对其有所依仗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_bow_d_a</Cell><Cell>A long strong bow made of ashen wood. It has a decent range and thanks to its draw speed it is suited very well for fighting.</Cell><Cell>白蜡木制成的强劲长弓。射程可观，且得益于拉动其弓弦的速度，这把弓非常适合用于战斗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_brigandine03_raub</Cell><Cell>Valued mainly for its colour. Doesn't lose any defensive capability, but allows its user to easily disappear.</Cell><Cell>价值在于它独特的颜色。在不损失防御能力的情况下，可以让穿戴者消失在阴影之中。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_brooch_golden_letter</Cell><Cell>Try putting a beautiful brooch like this on a beggar's skirt and you'll be thrown straight into the jail. You could be king and no one would believe it belongs to you. Clothes make the man, as Lord Capon and I already know.</Cell><Cell>试试看把这样一枚漂亮的别针别在乞丐的裙子上，你会立刻被扔进监狱。即使你是国王，也没人会相信它属于你。正如卡蓬领主和我早已知晓的那样，人确实得靠衣装。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_cap_courtier</Cell><Cell>A stylish hat that elevates its wearer's status. At the same time, it isn't too distinctive, and doesn't get int the way when checking a doors acoustics.</Cell><Cell>一顶体面的帽子，可以提升佩戴者的地位。同时，它又不会太显眼，在检查门的隔音效果时不会给你添麻烦。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_cap_mrHunter</Cell><Cell>The pointed hunting hat decorated with a brooch is the badge of an experienced hunter. Poachers should be on the lookout if they see him.</Cell><Cell>这顶饰有别针的尖顶猎帽是老练猎人的标志。如果偷猎者看到穿戴此帽之人，就应该提高警惕。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_cap_pickpocket</Cell><Cell>When you need to blend in with a crowd, you musn't stand out, and walking around with your head uncovered isn't common nowadays.</Cell><Cell>需要融入人群时，可不能做什么引人注目的事。这年头，不戴帽子到处走就很不常见。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_cap_thief</Cell><Cell>Whether a thief is hiding a lustrous mane or shiny bald spot, it's best to cover it up with something dark and inconspicuous.</Cell><Cell>作为盗贼，无论是有一头光泽的长发还是闪亮的秃顶，最好都用深色不起眼的东西遮一遮。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_cap_vagrant</Cell><Cell>What kind of vagrant would you be without a proper head? Protects its wearer from sun and rain alike, as well as suspicious looks from the locals.</Cell><Cell>没有合适的帽子，你又怎能以流浪者自称？这种帽子可以遮阳挡雨，也能避开当地人怀疑的目光。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_cheesecake</Cell><Cell>For those who aren't fans of poppy seeds or nuts, a quark kolach is the best of all.</Cell><Cell>如果不喜欢罂粟籽和坚果，奶酪圆面包就是最好的选择。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_coat_courtier</Cell><Cell>A handsome coat, intentionally made from wool instead of satin or at last, so it doesn't shine or make noise.</Cell><Cell>一件精美的外套，特地使用羊毛而非绸缎或麻布制成，因此既不会反射出光泽，也不会发出噪音。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_coat_over_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Bad weather is a vagrant's worst enemy. Therefore it's important to stay warm, and it doesn't hurt to keep a low profile as well.</Cell><Cell>恶劣天气是流浪者最大的敌人，因此保暖很重要。而且样子低调总是好的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_coat_thief</Cell><Cell>A true thief needs something that doesn't stand out, is hard to see, and doesn't make any unnecessary noise.</Cell><Cell>真正的盗贼需要款式普通，难以察觉，也不会发出不必要噪音的衣物。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_coif_small_vagrant</Cell><Cell>If Saint Dismas doesn't protect the vagrant, maybe this quilted coif will.</Cell><Cell>如果圣迪斯马斯庇护不了流浪者，或许这件头巾可以。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_common_oldHorseshoe</Cell><Cell>I reckon this horseshoe has done its fair share of travelling.</Cell><Cell>这个马蹄铁肯定走过不少地方。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_cracklings</Cell><Cell>What could be better than freshly roasted pork cracklings? Especially with a tankard of ale.</Cell><Cell>还有什么比新鲜出炉的烤脆猪皮配上一大杯啤酒更美妙吗？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_crossbowHeavyCheap</Cell><Cell>The heavy siege crossbow is used for shooting soldiers defending castle walls. The strong iron limbs have a considerable draw weight, therefore a hand crank must be used to load it. A bolt fired from this weapon can easily tear through plate armour.</Cell><Cell>用于射杀守城士兵的重型攻城弩。结实的铁弩臂拉伸力巨大，因此需要使用手摇曲柄进行装填。使用该武器发射的弩箭可以轻松击穿板甲。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_dlc2cernokneznik_bookSecretText</Cell><Cell>A strange book. Its pages aren't made of parchment, and are covered in various alchemical notes and symbols.</Cell><Cell>一本奇特的书。书页是用羊皮纸之外的某种材料制成的，上面布满了各种炼金术笔记和符号。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_dlc2cernokneznik_letterCipher</Cell><Cell>A strange list of symbols, clearly drawn by the hand of the lost alchemist. It looks like some sort of blind map with places marked by alchemical symbols.</Cell><Cell>一张奇特的符号清单，显然是由失踪的炼金术士手绘的。看起来像是某种地图，上面用炼金术符号标记了地点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_dlc2MalirZlodejske_colors</Cell><Cell>A variety of chisels made of quality steel, used by stonemasons for detailed work.</Cell><Cell>各种由优质钢材制成的凿子，供石匠进行精细工作时使用。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_gambeson_short02_vagrant</Cell><Cell>The roads can be dangerous, so it makes sense to wear something that will protect you while not making you stand out like a sore thumb.</Cell><Cell>路途险恶，穿一些能保护自己，还不会让自己很显眼的衣服很重要。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_gambeson_short04_raub</Cell><Cell>Its owner might have been a noble, but also could have been someone who ambushes travellers in the woods. Or perhaps both?</Cell><Cell>它的主人可能是个贵族，也可能是个在树林中伏击旅行者的盗贼。又或者两者皆是？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_gloves_pick</Cell><Cell>While not ideal for actually picking pockets, a fine, soft pair of gloves can come in handy in many other situations.</Cell><Cell>虽然不适合扒窃本身，但这双柔软精致的手套在很多其它场合都派得上用场。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_gloves_thief</Cell><Cell>While a 15th century thief didn't have to worry about leaving fingerprints, a good pair of gloves still came in handy when performing acrobatic maneuvers or prying open doors and chests.</Cell><Cell>虽然15世纪的小偷不用在乎指纹，但在表演杂技或撬门开箱时，一副好手套还是会派上用场。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hood01_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Most wear hoods to protect themselves from the elements. Some wear them to hide from the gaze of others</Cell><Cell>大多数人戴兜帽是保护自己免受风雨侵袭，而小部分只是为了避免他人的注视。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hood02_court</Cell><Cell>A handsome hood, good for conceiling its wearer's identity at secret meetings.</Cell><Cell>一顶帅气的兜帽，适合在秘密聚会中掩盖佩戴者的身份。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hood07_pick</Cell><Cell>Remain unseen and unheard with this hood.</Cell><Cell>可以用这个兜帽躲避他人的视野和听觉。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hood09_thief</Cell><Cell>It can get cold or windy on the prowl, and it's not a bad idea to keep your face hidden. Besides, what kind of thief doesn't have a hood?</Cell><Cell>踩点的时候天气可能会很冷，也可能遇到大风，这时候遮住脸是个好主意。而且，有哪个小偷不带兜帽呢？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hoodSemin</Cell><Cell>A hood of the good knight Jan Semine of Semine.</Cell><Cell>杰出骑士扬·塞米的兜帽。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hookgunFancy</Cell><Cell>The hook gun is a much more massive weapon than the handgonne. The barrel is fitted with a hook on the underside, which serves to wedge the weapon behind an obstacle and limit recoil when fired. This particular piece is cast from bronze by a master gunsmith, therefore can be fired repeatedly without breaking.</Cell><Cell>一把钩枪，它比手铳更猛。枪管底部装有钩子，可将武器楔在障碍物后，降低射击时产生的后坐力。这件武器由一位枪匠大师用青铜铸造而成，因此在射击时，能够承受较大火力所产生的冲击而不会立刻破裂。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hookgunNormal</Cell><Cell>A hand cannon, unlike a pistole, is a much more massive weapon. The barrel is fitted with a hook on the underside, which serves to wedge the weapon behind an obstacle and limit recoil when fired. This piece has a barrel made of wrought iron and therefore does not last as long as guns cast in bronze. It is therefore recommended to shoot with a smaller powder charge. Up close, this gun cracks knights in metal like thrushes smash snails on a rock.</Cell><Cell>一把带钩手铳，比一般的手铳猛多了。铳身底部装有钩子，可将武器楔住在障碍物后，降低射击时产生的后坐力。此火器铳身由铸铁制成，因此其耐用性与青铜制火器难以比拟，遂建议装填较小火药进行射击。近距离内，这种手铳能像画眉鸟啄击岩石上的蜗牛一样，粉碎披甲的骑士。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hose_joined</Cell><Cell>Long hose are a staple of men's clothing. They are worn by noble lords as well as simple folks. However, they differ in quality of fabric, cut or richness of colour. These hose are fashionably joined at the crotch by a separate flap.</Cell><Cell>长裤在男士服装中属于基本款式，无论是平民还是贵族都会穿，不过面料质量，裁剪手艺和颜色丰富度上会有所不同。在长裤的裆部会有一块襟布用作拼接，显得十分时尚。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hose_joined_courtier</Cell><Cell>A fine pair of hose that don't offend the eye, but don't draw much attention either - perfect for sneaking around and eavesdropping.</Cell><Cell>一条不会引人注目的优质裤子——非常适合潜行和窃听。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hose_joined_thief</Cell><Cell>While on the job, even the smallest detail can give you away - like the rustle of your hose. Thankfully, these don't rustle.</Cell><Cell>“工作”期间，即便是最小的细节，比如裤子发出的沙沙声，也可能会让你暴露。但幸运的是，这种裤子不会。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hose_pick</Cell><Cell>Not soiling them while hiding from guards is half the battle.</Cell><Cell>躲避警卫时，不把裤子弄脏就已经成功了一半。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_hose_separate_vagrant</Cell><Cell>A vagrant's pants tell a story of all the places they've been, and let's be honest - they've been to many a place they shouldn't have.</Cell><Cell>流浪者的裤子上沾满了他们旅途的痕迹，而且，说实话，他们去过太多不该去的地方了。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_huntingswordGuard</Cell><Cell>A hunting sword is the faithful companion of every huntsman and poacher. Commonly used for finishing off hunted game, but can come in handy when chopping woodchips for a campfire.</Cell><Cell>猎刀是每位猎人和偷猎者最忠诚的战友，它们通常用来终结猎物的生命，但当需要砍伐柴火时，猎刀亦有大用。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_huntingswordMussle</Cell><Cell>A beautiful hunting sword with a hilt made of deer antler will not disgrace even a nobleman. It is usually used to finish off hunted game, but it will also help against uninvited forest visitors.</Cell><Cell>以鹿角为柄的猎刀，十分漂亮，就算是贵族使用也不辱其身份。它通常用来结束猎物的生命，但也可以刺穿不速之客的喉咙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_huntingswordSword</Cell><Cell>The hunting sword – originally made for hunting wildlife, nowadays often carried by wealthy burghers, as they aren't allowed to carry a noble's sword at their side.</Cell><Cell>猎刀——最初是用于狩猎野生动物的武器，现在大多由富裕的市民携带，因为他们不被允许携带贵族剑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kettlehat_blk</Cell><Cell>Someone must have boiled sausages in this for a bloody long time.</Cell><Cell>一定是有人用它煮了很久的香肠。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_klasterniTajemstvi_casperWine_bad</Cell><Cell>This batch of Casper's wine didn't turn out so well.</Cell><Cell>卡斯帕的这批酒质量不怎么样。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kovaniKatuvSleh_magicHorseshoe</Cell><Cell>Won't wake the dead, but acts as a memento of one.</Cell><Cell>它没办法唤醒亡者，但可以用作纪念。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kovaniKovarskaSoutez_huntingKnifeApprentice</Cell><Cell>Light, perfectly balanced and sharp so that the feather is cut in half by its own weight when it hits the blade. That's what this hunting sword should be, but...</Cell><Cell>很轻，平衡完美，锋利无比，羽毛落在其上都会被切成两半。这把猎刀理应如此优秀，然而……</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kovaniNaKovarne_pajslSword</Cell><Cell>This weapon has been through a lot. Maybe too much. The owner seems to be using it more as a baton than a sword, since its too blunt.</Cell><Cell>这把武器早已历经沧桑，其经历或许难以估量。因其钝刃，似乎武器的主人已经把它当作棍棒来使用。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kovaniPoklad_adornedAxe</Cell><Cell>The beautiful axe from the legend of the two woodcutters was lost for many years, but Henry of Skalitz found it and restored it to its former glory.</Cell><Cell>《两个樵夫的传说》中那把美丽的斧头丢失了很多年，但斯卡里茨的亨利找到了它，并使其恢复了昔日的光彩。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kovarskeZakazky_magdalenaAxe</Cell><Cell>A homemade axe, improved years ago by blacksmith Schkoda to better suit his wife Magdalena's needs. It's more durable than an ordinary axe.</Cell><Cell>一把自制的斧头。铁匠施科达在许多年前对它做出了改进，以更好地适应他妻子马格达琳的需求。它比普通斧头结实耐用得多。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kovarskeZakazky_magdalenaAxe_broken</Cell><Cell>A homemade axe, modified years ago by Schkoda the blacksmith to better suit his wife's needs. It lasted significantly longer than an ordinary axe, but now its time is over.</Cell><Cell>一把自制的斧头。铁匠施科达在许多年前对它做出了改进，以更好地适应他妻子的需求。它比普通斧头结实耐用得多，但现在也已经到了寿命。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kovarskeZakazky_magdalenaBrokenAxe</Cell><Cell>A homemade axe, improved years ago by blacksmith Schkoda to better suit his wife Magdalena's needs. It lasted significantly longer than an ordinary axe, but its time has come to an end.</Cell><Cell>一把自制的斧头。铁匠施科达在许多年前对它做出了改进，以更好地适应他妻子马格达琳的需求。它比普通斧头结实耐用得多，但现在也已经到了寿命。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_kumaniNaTrosecku_peculiarSpirits</Cell><Cell>Schnapps from the hidden stash. Judging by the smell, it's bound to have the right kick.</Cell><Cell>被藏起来的烈酒，光闻一闻就知道它够劲。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_legs_padded02</Cell><Cell>A quilted hose that have been through a lot. They are rugged and have patches, but can still be used on their own or as a bottom layer for the upper part of armour.</Cell><Cell>一条历经沧桑的绗缝衬裤。裤子结实耐用，布满补丁，可单独穿着，或是用作上半护腿的打底裤。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_legs_padded02_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Comfortable even while running and sneaking around, both of which are a daily occurrence for a vagrant.</Cell><Cell>用于奔跑和潜行也很舒适，而流浪者每天都要面对这两种情况。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_legs_plate01</Cell><Cell>A leg protection consisting of forged plates of sheet metal suitably fit together. Such armour protects the warrior's entire leg, but its weight depends on the craftsmanship of the maker.</Cell><Cell>由合理拼接的锻造金属板组装而成的腿部护甲，能够保护战士全腿，但其重量则取决于锻造者的手工艺水平。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_longswordDemo</Cell><Cell>The long sword is a fearsome weapon commonly used by knights and warriors in 15th century Europe. With a blade measuring over 3 feet in length, it is designed for powerful strikes and precise thrusts, making it versatile in both one-on-one combat and battlefield skirmishes. Its sturdy construction and balanced weight allow for swift movements and devastating blows, making it a popular choice for those seeking to dominate their opponents in close combat.</Cell><Cell>长剑是15世纪欧洲骑士和战士常用的可怕武器。它的刃长度超过3英尺，专为强有力的打击和精确的刺击而设计，无论是在一对一的战斗中还是战场厮杀中都很通用。长剑结构坚固、重量平衡，能够使持剑者动作迅速的同时有强大的打击力，因此成为那些寻求在近战中压倒对手的人的热门选择。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_longswordOld</Cell><Cell>Original long swords have a slightly wider blade and a pronounced groove for durability. They are not weapons for decoration, but noble blades to uphold knightly honour and family tradition.</Cell><Cell>最初的长剑有一个略宽的刃和一个明显的耐用凹槽。它们不是装饰用的武器，而是维护骑士荣誉和家族传统的高贵利刃。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_loot_salt</Cell><Cell>A mineral suitable for flavouring dishes. To some it's more precious than gold.</Cell><Cell>一种能当调味料使用的矿物质，对某些人来说比黄金还要珍贵。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_loot_silverChalice</Cell><Cell>One day in the future, people with battle with sticks for such a trophy… maybe on ice!</Cell><Cell>在未来，人们会在草地上用棍子互相争夺这样的战利品……也可能是在冰上！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_loot_stone</Cell><Cell>Stone from the old smithy</Cell><Cell>老铁匠铺的石头</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_mace01</Cell><Cell>A mace with steel flanges is a formidable weapon, yet it is still nimbler than a simple axe. It can crush and break bones even through quality plate armour.</Cell><Cell>带有钢突缘的钉头锤是一种可怕的武器，且比简易斧头更为灵活。它可以穿透坚固的护甲，进而粉碎敌人的骨骼。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maceBailiff</Cell><Cell>Bronze mace cast in one piece with ground tips. It expresses both position and determination to make one's case, even if one has to beat one's ideas into opponent's head with force.</Cell><Cell>由青铜一体打造的钉头锤，尖端经过打磨。它既象征着地位，也表明了一种决心——即要用武力将思想灌输到对手脑海之中。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maceClubSpiked</Cell><Cell>A wooden bludgeon reinforced with blunt spikes that can quickly turn anyone's face to a bloody mash. A weapon like this can put a swift end to any tavern brawl or absent-minded traveller's life.</Cell><Cell>一根带有钝刺的木制棍棒，转瞬间即可将人的脸打成血糊。如此武器可迅速终结任何酒馆斗殴，或是杀死心不在焉的旅人。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maceHetman</Cell><Cell>A captain's mace is a great weapon expressing the status of the owner and the punishment that will befall anyone who opposes him. A single movement with the weapon in hand is enough to set in motion whole ranks of warriors!</Cell><Cell>首领手中的钉头锤是一种强大的武器，象征着持有者的身份，也预示着反对者即将遭受的惩罚。仅凭挥动此武器的简单动作就足以让整个队伍的战士动起身来！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_magic_arrow</Cell><Cell>The magic arrowhead from Karel the Arrow's head.</Cell><Cell>“锋矢”卡雷尔的魔法箭头</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_magickySip_magickaSipka</Cell><Cell>A shaft with an arrowhead, which I pulled out of the head of the dead Karel, whom folk called Arrowhead. It's supposed to be magical, but I have my doubts.</Cell><Cell>我从死去的卡雷尔头上拔下的一柄带箭头的箭矢，而人们都叫卡雷尔“锋矢”。这支箭似乎有魔力，但我对此秉持疑虑。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_magicShop_nepomukNeedle</Cell><Cell>The needle used to sew vicar Jan of Pomuk into a bag, after which he was thrown into the Vltava river, all on the orders of Wenceslas IV.</Cell><Cell>在瓦茨拉夫四世的命令下，扬·波穆克副主教被缝进袋子，丢进了伏尔塔瓦河，这就是当时用到的针。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_mail_long01</Cell><Cell>A long, chainmail shirt with sleeves covering the arms and forearms.</Cell><Cell>一件长链甲衫，长长的袖子能保护胳膊。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_mail_short01</Cell><Cell>Shortened chainmail shirt with long sleeves.</Cell><Cell>短款链甲长袖衫。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_malir_die_b</Cell><Cell></Cell><Cell>Modrá kostka malíře Vojtěcha. Nese jméno B, protože… No… Kdo ví.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_malir_die_g</Cell><Cell></Cell><Cell>Zeleně pomalovaná kostka malíře Vojtěcha. Nese jméno G ale proč?</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_malir_die_r</Cell><Cell></Cell><Cell>Painter Voyta's red-painted die. It carries the name R. </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maliruvLek_freshwaterPearl</Cell><Cell>Found in freshwater pearl mussels. They're used in jewellery making, therefore are quite valuable.</Cell><Cell>在淡水蚌中发现的珍珠。能用来制作珠宝，因此价格不菲。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maliruvLek_mandrakeRoot</Cell><Cell>Grows near dead men's graves. It's used as an ingredient in special potions</Cell><Cell>生长于死者坟墓周围，是制作特殊药剂的材料。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maliruvLek_potion</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;Quiets down the frightening thoughts and menacing voices.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;body&gt; Heals 50 health over 8 hours.</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;平息恐惧，屏蔽邪念。&lt;/body&gt;&lt;body&gt;在8小时内恢复50点生命值。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maliruvLek_potion_best</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;Quiets down the frightening thoughts and menacing voices.&lt;/body&gt; Heals 75 health over 8 hours, raises Vitality by 3, and unblocked hits deplete 10% less Stamina.</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;平息恐惧，屏蔽邪念。&lt;/body&gt;&lt;body&gt;在8小时内恢复75点生命值，提升3点活力，且未被格挡的攻击降低10%的耐力消耗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maliruvLek_potion_high</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;Quiets down the frightening thoughts and menacing voices.&lt;/body&gt; Heals 75 Health over 8 hours, raises Vitality by 2.</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;平息恐惧，屏蔽邪念。&lt;/body&gt;&lt;body&gt;在8小时内恢复75点生命值，并提升2点活力。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_maliruvLek_potion_medium</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;Quiets down the frightening thoughts and menacing voices.&lt;/body&gt; Heals 75 Health over 8 hours, raises Vitality by 1.</Cell><Cell>&lt;body&gt;平息恐惧，屏蔽邪念。&lt;/body&gt;&lt;body&gt;在8小时内恢复75点生命值，并提升1点活力。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_malirZlodejske_sketch</Cell><Cell>A sketch by the painter Damian.</Cell><Cell>画家达米安的素描</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_marikasScarf</Cell><Cell>Nice scarf, probably belongs to Marika, a young girl from the nomadic camp.</Cell><Cell>漂亮的围巾，似乎属于游牧民营地的年轻女孩玛丽卡。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_money</Cell><Cell>Groschen, Groschen, Groschen&lt;br&gt;My silver cushion&lt;br&gt;It's a merchant's world&lt;br&gt;Groschen, Groschen, Groschen&lt;br&gt;It's my passion,&lt;br/&gt; Now my goods are sold.</Cell><Cell>格罗申，格罗申&lt;br&gt;大家都爱&lt;br&gt;格罗申&lt;br&gt;格罗申，格罗申&lt;br&gt;旋转起来真迷人…...</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_necklace01_Vajda</Cell><Cell>The necklace of the nomadic foreman protects against bewitchment and evil spells.</Cell><Cell>游牧民首领的项链，可抵抗妖术和邪恶法术。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_PaintedStatueSaintMagdaleine</Cell><Cell>A small worn-down statuette of St Mary Magdalene. Beikovetz must have stolen it straight from some church or monastery.</Cell><Cell>一个破旧的马格达莱妮圣玛利亚的小雕像，肯定是贝科维茨从教堂或者修道院偷来的。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_pearCooked</Cell><Cell>Cooked pear softens up and smells wonderful.</Cell><Cell>煮熟的梨子又软又香。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_poi_matkaADite_childsSkull</Cell><Cell>A child's skull I dug up in the Sedletz cemetery.</Cell><Cell>在塞德莱茨墓地挖到的孩童的颅骨。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_poi_pokladPodTroskami_oldSpirit</Cell><Cell>A bottle of moonshine that's been hidden in the caves beneath Trosky since the castle was built. It's a once-in-a-lifetime experience.</Cell><Cell>一瓶自特罗斯基城堡建成以来就藏在地窖之中的私酒，如此美酒此生能得几回逢？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_pomatenec_brokenSword</Cell><Cell>The broken sword I got from the aggressive madman near the place where painter Voyta sent me. It might be worth getting it repaired for him.</Cell><Cell>在画家沃伊塔让我前往的地点附近，我遇到了一个张牙舞爪的疯子，还从他身上取得了这把断剑。但它似乎需要好好修理一番。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_pomatenec_longsword</Cell><Cell></Cell><Cell>Meč starého blázna ze zemnice, ke které mě poslal malíř Vojtěch. Na čepeli je vyryto: Confiteor Deo omnipotenti.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_poppyseedcake</Cell><Cell>A good poppy seed cake is beneficial to all the senses. It calms and soothes. Quick, one more piece before it's banned for being too delicious!</Cell><Cell>一块上好的罂粟籽圆面包有百利而无一害，它能镇静和舒缓情绪。快，再吃一块，免得它因为太好吃而被禁止了！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_poPytlackeStezce_machKey</Cell><Cell>A key to a chest found in the possession of the poacher, Mach of Marschowitz.</Cell><Cell>在偷猎者马绍维茨的马赫身上发现的钥匙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_poPytlackeStezce_whiteDeerHide</Cell><Cell>A beautiful white hide taken from a buck. Found in the poachers' camp in the forest near Suchdol.</Cell><Cell>一张美丽的白色兽皮。发现于苏赫多尔附近森林中的偷猎者营地。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_poPytlackeStezce_youngWhiteDeerHide</Cell><Cell>A white hide taken from a young roebuck. It's sad, I reckon there aren't many white roebucks in the region.</Cell><Cell>从一只年幼狍子身上取下的白色兽皮。太可惜了，这附近的白色狍子本来就非常稀少。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_potion_aquaVitalis_medium</Cell><Cell>You lose 15% less Health and slows bleeding by 10%. Lasts 10 minutes.</Cell><Cell>你所损失的生命值减少15%，且流血速度降低10%，效果持续10分钟。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_potion_artemisia_high</Cell><Cell>Increases Strength by 4 and both attack and defence cost 15% less Stamina, lasts 10 minutes.</Cell><Cell>提升4点力量，攻击和防御消耗的耐力均降低15%，持续10分钟。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_potion_bowmanBrew</Cell><Cell>Increases Marksmanship by 3 for 10 minutes.</Cell><Cell>提升3点射术，持续10分钟。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_aesopPotion</Cell><Cell>Increases riding and dog-handling skills. If good quality, animals will take less notice of you and dogs won't bark at you.</Cell><Cell>可提升骑术以及训犬能力，高品质药剂的话，能让动物降低对你的警惕，且狗不会对你吠叫。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_axebattle02</Cell><Cell>The battle axe, called a broadaxe, is related to the ordinary carpenter's axe, but is much lighter and forged specifically for combat. It's a good weapon against shields and chainmail.</Cell><Cell>这种战斧又称宽刃斧，与普通木匠斧相似，但要轻得多，专门为战斗而锻造。能轻松劈开盾牌和链甲。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_axebattle03</Cell><Cell>The horseman's pick is a light riding axe with a spike. Used correctly, it's a good friend in a pinch. Its sharp point can cut through armour, its blade through any shield.</Cell><Cell>骑兵镐斧是一种带有尖刺的轻型骑兵斧。使用得当的话，在紧要关头能发挥很大用处。它锋利的稿尖可以轻易击穿盔甲，而斧刃则可以劈开任何盾牌。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_axebattle04</Cell><Cell>A knight's battle axe. A dexterous weapon that can pierce good armour or crush the bones underneath with its spike. It also has a pointed tip to finish off tougher opponents.</Cell><Cell>骑士战斧是一种灵活的武器，上面的尖刺能击穿坚固的盔甲，甚至能粉碎盔甲之下的骨头。它还有一个尖头，可以用来了结更难缠的对手。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_axecuman</Cell><Cell>Cuman long-handled fokosz. A fast and agile weapon of the Hungarian raiders. It can pierce light armour or the skull of a good Christian.</Cell><Cell>库曼长柄斧。匈牙利人常用的一种敏捷的武器。它可以轻易穿透轻甲，或击碎一个基督徒的头骨。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_axefancy</Cell><Cell>A lightweight, well-forged battleaxe. The blade forged to a point replaces the spike, which can be used to cut through chainmail and the belly underneath.</Cell><Cell>轻便，锻造精良的战斧。斧刃被锻造成尖头形状，代替了传统的尖刺，可以用来切穿链甲，开肠破肚。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_axework01</Cell><Cell>Lightweight axe designed for work in the woods or on the farm. An invaluable tool for all woodcutters, but also for angry people who don't have a better weapon at hand.</Cell><Cell>轻便的工作斧，专为森林或农场的工作而设计。对伐木工来说是必备的工具，但对于怒气上头却没有更好武器在手的人，也是如此。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_axework02</Cell><Cell>Heavy work axe used by carpenters for working beams. If there's no better weapon at hand, it can become a tool of revenge.</Cell><Cell>木匠用来加工横梁的重型工作斧。如果手头没有其他更好的武器，也可以把它当复仇的工具使。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_banePotion</Cell><Cell>Depletes 110 health and therefore leads to certain death. In better quality, it depletes health faster. It's better for poisoning cauldrons than applying to weapons.</Cell><Cell>消耗110点生命值，可能导致死亡。更高品质的药剂会更快生效，对锅中食材下毒的效果比在武器上涂毒要更好。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_bardPotion</Cell><Cell>Improves speech and speeds up reading if good quality. Also increases the amount of experience gained if best quality.</Cell><Cell>高品质药剂可提升口才和提高阅读速度，且当药剂品质最优时还能提高经验获取量。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_chamomileDecoction</Cell><Cell>Sleep heals you faster and if good quality, Energy replenishes faster while sleeping.</Cell><Cell>睡眠可以助你更快地恢复伤势，如果睡眠质量好，能量也会更快恢复。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_hoochPotion</Cell><Cell>Henry's home-brewed moonshine. A strong drink that is sure to put you in a good mood.</Cell><Cell>亨利自酿的私酒，烈酒入喉定能让你身心愉悦。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_huntingSwordBasic</Cell><Cell>The hunting sword is the faithful companion of every hunter or poacher. It is usually used to finish off hunted game, but it's also handy for cutting kindling for a fire.</Cell><Cell>猎刀是每个猎人（或者偷猎者）的忠实伙伴，通常用来终结猎物的生命，但也可以用于砍柴生火。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_huntingswordmussle</Cell><Cell>A beautiful hunting sword with a hilt made of deer antler will not disgrace even a nobleman. It is usually used to put out hunted game, but it will also help against uninvited forest visitors.</Cell><Cell>以鹿角为柄的猎刀，十分漂亮，就算是贵族使用也不辱其身份。它通常用来结束猎物的生命，但也可以刺穿不速之客的喉咙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_longswordcommon</Cell><Cell>The longsword is a perfectly balanced lethal weapon. Its price is not small, because only a master of his craft can forge a thin yet flexible blade! The longsword is not meant for the heat of battle, but for swift swordplay.</Cell><Cell>这把长剑是拥有完美平衡的致命武器。它价格不菲，因为只有锻造大师才能造出如此轻薄而灵活的剑刃。这把剑不适合用于激烈的战斗，而适用于敏捷的剑术格斗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_longswordsturdy</Cell><Cell>A heavier long blade will last longer and won't break easily, but it must be balanced by a much larger pommel. This sword is designed for actual battle rather than a quick sword fight.</Cell><Cell>越重的剑就越耐用，越不容易断裂，但剑柄也就需要相应得做得更大才能平衡剑身重量。这把剑是为实战设计的，在点到为止的剑术决斗中并不适用。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_perfumeShortStrong</Cell><Cell>A strong but short-lasting perfume. Substantially increases charisma for short periods, but reduces charisma if combined with another perfume.</Cell><Cell>一款香气浓郁但只能短暂留香的香水，可在短时间内大幅度提升魅力值，但与其他香水混合使用则会降低魅力值。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_shortswordcleaver</Cell><Cell>A terrible skull opener or a mere figment of the tortured mind of a clumsy apprentice who abused the blacksmith's craft to create such wickedness and called it a hunting sword?</Cell><Cell>是一把可怕的开颅凶器，还是一个笨拙的学徒滥用铁匠工艺创造出的，号称猎刀的邪恶产物？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_shotBall</Cell><Cell>Gunpowder used to fire lead shot that even the best plate armour can't stop at close range.</Cell><Cell>用于发射铅弹的火药，即便是最坚硬的板甲也无法承受挡下其近距离射击。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_sleepPotion</Cell><Cell>Reduces restedness to 0. Reduces stamina regeneration if good quality. Suitable for applying to weapons and for poisoning cooking pots.</Cell><Cell>将休息度降至0，高品质药剂还会降低耐力的恢复速度。适合用作武器涂毒和给食物下毒。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_sneakPotion</Cell><Cell>Increases Thievery and Craftsmanship. </Cell><Cell>可提升偷窃技能和手工艺技能。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_staminaPotion</Cell><Cell>Increases stamina and increases stamina regeneration if good quality.</Cell><Cell>可提升耐力值，高品质药剂还能提升耐力恢复速度。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_recipe_vitalityPotion</Cell><Cell>Reduces loss of health and slows bleeding.</Cell><Cell>减少生命值流失，并减缓出血。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_salamiDried</Cell><Cell>Spicy dried salami. The longer you dry it, the better it tastes. </Cell><Cell>辛辣的萨拉米香肠干。晾晒的时间越长，它就越美味。 </Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_sedmStatecnych2_pillory</Cell><Cell>The key to the pillory.</Cell><Cell>颈手枷的钥匙。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_sermiryHuntingSwordJimram</Cell><Cell>An excellent hunting sword of the master butcher Emmeram from Kuttenberg.</Cell><Cell>属于库滕堡老练屠夫艾默拉姆的绝佳猎刀。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_shieldPavise_bergov</Cell><Cell>A riding pavese with the symbol of Lord von Bergow, owner of Trosky Castle.</Cell><Cell>一面骑兵帕维斯巨盾，其上装饰着特罗斯基堡垒的拥有者冯·波尔高领主的图纹。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_shieldPavise_dragon</Cell><Cell>A skillfully painted riding pavese.</Cell><Cell>一面精心涂绘的骑兵帕维斯巨盾。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_shieldPavise_hungary</Cell><Cell>A cavalry pavese with Hungarian symbols.</Cell><Cell>绘有匈牙利人图纹的骑兵帕维斯巨盾。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_shieldPavise_prague</Cell><Cell>A riding pavese with the symbol of the Old Town of Prague.</Cell><Cell>一面骑兵帕维斯巨盾，盾上涂饰着布拉格老城的纹章。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_shieldPavise_stripes</Cell><Cell>A skillfully painted riding pavese.</Cell><Cell>一面精心涂绘的骑兵帕维斯巨盾。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_shoes_thief</Cell><Cell>Shoes of the finest deerskin allow their wearer to move about near silently, as well as keeping their feet safe. Cellars and attics often have a surprising amount of old nails and other dangers.</Cell><Cell>优质鹿皮制成的鞋子，不仅让穿戴者可以悄无声息地行动，还能保护他们双脚的安全。毕竟地窖和阁楼里往往有不少旧钉子和其它危险品。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_shoes_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Life on the road is hard, so it's best to have a good pair of shoes. Ideally ones that don't make much noise when you need to tuck yourself away.</Cell><Cell>流浪生活很艰难，所以最好选一双好鞋陪伴。最好是那种需要藏身时不会发出太多噪音的款式。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_skin_roe</Cell><Cell>A roe-deer hide does not reach the strength and quality of deerskin and is not suitable for tanning. It is therefore mainly used as fur.</Cell><Cell>狍子皮的韧性和质量都不及鹿皮，不适合鞣制，只能当做皮草使用。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_special_lard</Cell><Cell>Rendered lard for various alchemical recipes.</Cell><Cell>精炼猪油，可用于各种炼金配方。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_spurs01_m01</Cell><Cell>Riding spurs for better control of a horse. Its arms, points and binding are all made of cheap materials, so they only provide a minor boost to horse riding skill.</Cell><Cell>为了更好驾驭马匹而设计的马刺。它的支架、尖端和绑带都是用廉价材料制成的，只能提供少量的骑术加成。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_spurs01_m02</Cell><Cell>Riding spurs for better control of a horse. The binding is made of quality leather, but its arms aren't curved enough. Provides an average boost to horse riding skill.</Cell><Cell>为了更好驾驭马匹而设计的马刺。有着优质皮革制成的绑带，但支架部分弯曲度不足。能提供一些骑术加成。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_spurs01_m03</Cell><Cell>Riding spurs for better control of a horse. Strong binding, expanded arms and an eight-pointed rowel provide a generous boost to horse riding skill.</Cell><Cell>为了更好驾驭马匹而设计的马刺。绑带坚固，支架做了延长，还有八齿滚轮。能提供很大的骑术加成。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_spurs01_m04</Cell><Cell>Riding spurs for better control of a horse. Double binding, massive arms, long shank and rowel held in place by a strong pin. It provides an exceptional boost to horse riding skill.</Cell><Cell>为了更好驾驭马匹而设计的马刺。有双重固定结构，加粗的连接部，加长柄再加上强力销钉固定的滚轮。能提供极大的骑术加成。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_stealthMiseZaJindru_samHuntingKnife</Cell><Cell>Samuel's hunting sword that never leaves his hand.</Cell><Cell>塞缪尔的猎刀，从未离开过他的双手。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_strasidlo_scaryThings</Cell><Cell>Equipment for spooking rival Bellissimo. Contains a demon costume, as well as some torches.</Cell><Cell>用来吓唬你的对手贝利西莫的装备。包含一套恶魔服装和一些火把。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_svatba_drinkForMoravians</Cell><Cell>Some moonshine the Moravians brought to the Semine wedding.</Cell><Cell>一些摩拉维亚人带到塞米婚宴上的私酒。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_svatba_ringFromChamberlein</Cell><Cell>A simple but truly beautiful gold ring with which Chamberlain Ulrich wanted to bribe Enneleyn at young lord Semine's wedding.</Cell><Cell>一枚简单但非常漂亮的金戒指，这本来是管家乌尔里希想在塞米少爷的婚礼上给恩内琳的贿赂。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_swordBrabant</Cell><Cell>The sword worn by Vauquelin Brabant. He sought opportunities all his life, but the window for him has closed for good.</Cell><Cell>瓦奎林·布拉班特的佩剑。尽管他毕生都在寻求机遇，但是机会之窗早已永久紧闭。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_swordCleaver</Cell><Cell>A dreadful skull opener or a mere result of the tortured mind of a clumsy journeyman who abused the blacksmith's craft to create such wickedness and called it a hunting sword?</Cell><Cell>是一把可怕的开颅凶器，还是一个笨拙的学徒滥用铁匠工艺创造出的，号称猎刀的邪恶产物？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_taboryLapkuTrosecko_plesnivecMace</Cell><Cell>A mace of the leader of the bandits from the Troskowitz gorge. A crude weapon that cracked many a skull and was never properly wiped clean afterwards.</Cell><Cell>特罗斯科维茨峡谷土匪首领的钉头锤。这是一种粗制武器，曾击碎过许多头骨，但从未被彻底擦拭干净。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_taboryUcesty_ostatkylebkaSvaty</Cell><Cell>A small fragment of flat bone said to come from the skull of Saint Margaret. In ancient times, the Roman Emperor persecuted all Christians and had many of them cruelly martyred. Margaret was reported by her spurned suitor to the prefect, accusing her of secretly professing faith in Christ. In prison, the devil himself appeared to the virtuous maiden in the form of a dragon and devoured her, but she overcame him with the help of the cross. She survived drowning and burning by fire, so they finally had to behead her. A few relics of this martyr were supposedly given to the Czech King Premysl Otakar by the Pope himself after his victory over the Hungarians.</Cell><Cell>一小块扁骨，据说是圣玛格丽特头骨的一部分。在古代，罗马皇帝对所有的基督教徒进行迫害，惨无人道地处决了不计其数的教徒。玛格丽特的追求者因遭到拒绝，便向掌权者举报了玛格丽特，指控她私下宣称对基督教的信奉。身处监狱的玛格丽特，遇到了化身恶龙的恶魔本体，后者欲要将她吞噬，好在这位高洁的少女在十字架的帮助下战胜了恶魔。即便遭受冷水淹没、历经烈火焚烧，她依然幸存了下来，所以人们最终只得将她斩首。有传闻称，在战胜匈牙利人后，教皇亲自把这位殉道之人的遗物交给了捷克国王普热米斯尔·奥托卡。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_tournament_maceHerald</Cell><Cell>An excellent mace, which serves more as a symbol of a strict ruler over the tournament than for fighting.</Cell><Cell>一把精良的钉头锤，更像是作为比武大会严苛规则的象征，而非简单用于战斗。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_treasureHunter_map3</Cell><Cell>A map to a site where there's treasure.</Cell><Cell>标记着宝藏所在地的地图。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_truhlari_handplane</Cell><Cell>A chisel, similar to those used by carpenters. Surely Chrudosh wouldn't just leave it here. Maybe it can help me figure out where he disappeared to.</Cell><Cell>A chisel, similar to those used by carpenters. Surely Chrudosh wouldn't just leave it here. Maybe it can help me figure out where he disappeared to.</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_truhlari_motherMaryStatue</Cell><Cell>A statuette of Mother Mary, meant as part of an altar.</Cell><Cell>一个圣母玛利亚的小雕像，应该是某个祭坛的一部分。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_tunic_long_pick</Cell><Cell>Keeps you hidden when stalking your prey.</Cell><Cell>在追踪猎物时能帮你隐藏行踪。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_tunic_long_vagrant</Cell><Cell>A vagrant needs to blend in, and if that doesn't work, disappear. This tunic will help with that.</Cell><Cell>流浪汉需要和环境融为一体，如果那还不够，就彻底消失不见。这件长袍可以帮你实现这点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_tunic_short_pourpoint_courtier</Cell><Cell>A respectable pourpoint, looks handsome while allowing its wearer to move silently and unseen in places he shouldn't be.</Cell><Cell>一件体面的棉衣，既能彰显穿戴者的英俊，也能使其在不该出现的地方悄无声息地行走，避开所有人的视线。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_tunic_short_thief</Cell><Cell>To blend in on the street without being seen is the goal of anyone who doesn't heed the law, and this tunic will help with that.</Cell><Cell>不法之徒都希望能融入街头，不被任何人发现。这件束腰外衣可以帮你实现这点。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_unique_clothing</Cell><Cell>This is a unique clothing asset for an important character. If you got it in game, report it!</Cell><Cell>这是一个重要角色的特殊服装。如果你在游戏拿到了它，请告知我们！</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_vajduv_amulet</Cell><Cell>Supposedly a magical amulet of a nomadic foreman, which guarantees invulnerability and resistance to all diseases.</Cell><Cell>据说是一位游牧民首领的魔法护符，能使人刀枪不入且可抵御所有疾病。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_viktorka_strangeHerbs</Cell><Cell>A bundle of dried herbs from Victoria's house.</Cell><Cell>维多利亚家里的一捆干草药。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_zikmunduvTabor_catherineShoe</Cell><Cell>I wonder where the other one is?</Cell><Cell>不知道另一只在哪里？</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_zlatyMedailon_vojtasScarf</Cell><Cell>This yellowed rag which smells of sweat and fish, is probably used by Voyta as a scarf.</Cell><Cell>这条黄色破布散发着汗臭与鱼臭，沃伊塔似乎将它用作围巾。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_in_ztratyANalezy_booze</Cell><Cell>This moonshine can get cause you a lot of trouble, and not just an upset stomach.</Cell><Cell>这种私酒会给你带来很多麻烦，不仅限于肠胃不适。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_matrimonium_badge</Cell><Cell>A memento of Agnes and Olda's big day. Using it allows you to &lt;strong&gt;reroll up to three dice&lt;/strong&gt;. Can be used &lt;strong&gt;once per game&lt;/strong&gt;.</Cell><Cell>用于纪念阿格尼丝和奥达盛大婚礼的徽章。使用后可在某次掷骰时&lt;strong&gt;重掷最多三颗骰子&lt;/strong&gt;。每局游戏可使用&lt;strong&gt;一次&lt;/strong&gt;。</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_antibust_dice_badge_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver badge of resurrection</Cell><Cell>银制重掷徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_double_take_dice_badge_gold</Cell><Cell>Gold doppelganger badge</Cell><Cell>金制镜像徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_double_take_dice_badge_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver doppelganger badge</Cell><Cell>金制镜像徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_extra_dice_dice_badge</Cell><Cell>Silver badge of might</Cell><Cell>银制力量徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_headstart_dice_badge_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver badge of headstart</Cell><Cell>金制先行徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_multiplier_dice_badge_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver warlord's badge</Cell><Cell>银制军阀徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_null_dice_badge_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver badge of defence</Cell><Cell>银制防守徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_reroll_dice_dice_badge_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver badge of fortune</Cell><Cell>银制幸运女神徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_mn_set_dice_dice_badge_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver badge of transmutation</Cell><Cell>银制换点徽章</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_alias_loot_aPinchOfHappiness</Cell><Cell>A pinch of happiness</Cell><Cell>一小搓幸福感</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_alias_loot_brenekHuntingSword</Cell><Cell>Bohumir's hunting sword</Cell><Cell>博胡米尔的猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_alias_loot_daggerOfAstarte</Cell><Cell>Dagger of Astarte</Cell><Cell>阿斯塔特匕首</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_alias_loot_hoochOfPach</Cell><Cell>Bach moonshine</Cell><Cell>巴赫私酒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_alias_loot_lorecChalice</Cell><Cell>Italian chalice</Cell><Cell>意大利圣餐杯</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_alias_loot_pesekPotion</Cell><Cell>Peshek's potion</Cell><Cell>皮社科的药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_alias_loot_zizkaChalice</Cell><Cell>Zizka's chalice</Cell><Cell>杰式卡的圣餐杯</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_animal_sheepCasings</Cell><Cell>Sheep guts</Cell><Cell>羊肠</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_appleDried</Cell><Cell>Dried apple</Cell><Cell>苹果干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_armplate02_m01</Cell><Cell>Plate knight sleeves</Cell><Cell>骑士板甲护手</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_armplate04_m01</Cell><Cell>Nuremberg plate sleeves</Cell><Cell>纽伦堡板甲护手</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_arrow_broken</Cell><Cell>Broken arrow</Cell><Cell>损坏的箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_arrow_enh_hunter</Cell><Cell>Improved hunting arrow</Cell><Cell>改良狩猎箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_arrow_enh_pierce</Cell><Cell>Improved piercing arrow</Cell><Cell>改良穿甲箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_arrow_EXAMPLE</Cell><Cell>New test arrow</Cell><Cell>新测试箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_arrow_hunter</Cell><Cell>Hunting arrow</Cell><Cell>狩猎箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_arrow_pierce</Cell><Cell>Piercing arrow</Cell><Cell>穿甲箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_arrow_tournament</Cell><Cell>Tournament arrow</Cell><Cell>比武用箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_axeBattle01</Cell><Cell>Bearded axe</Cell><Cell>胡须斧</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_axeBattle03</Cell><Cell>Horseman's pick</Cell><Cell>骑兵镐斧</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_axeCuman</Cell><Cell>Cuman fokos</Cell><Cell>库曼斧</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_axeWork02_broken_kunesh</Cell><Cell>Axe from Skalitz stub</Cell><Cell>来自斯卡里茨的斧头残骸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_axeWork02_kunesh</Cell><Cell>Skalitz axe</Cell><Cell>斯卡里茨之斧</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_azZaHrob_silveredStudSarcofag</Cell><Cell>Silver-plated button</Cell><Cell>镀银纽扣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetopen01_m01</Cell><Cell>Open bascinet</Cell><Cell>开放式中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetopen02_m01</Cell><Cell>Bell-shaped bascinet</Cell><Cell>钟型中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetopen03_m01</Cell><Cell>Bascinet with bretèche</Cell><Cell>配有护片的中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetopen08_m01</Cell><Cell>Bascinet with aventail</Cell><Cell>配有颈甲的中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetopen_twitch</Cell><Cell>Warhorse bascinet</Cell><Cell>战马中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetvisor01_m01</Cell><Cell>Saxon bascinet</Cell><Cell>萨克森中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetvisor02_m01</Cell><Cell>Hounskull bascinet</Cell><Cell>猎犬中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetvisor03_m01</Cell><Cell>Nuremberg bascinet</Cell><Cell>纽伦堡中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetvisor04_m01</Cell><Cell>Noble's bascinet</Cell><Cell>贵族的中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetvisor05_m01</Cell><Cell>Italian bascinet</Cell><Cell>意大利中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetvisorcapon_m01</Cell><Cell>Capon's bascinet</Cell><Cell>卡蓬的中头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bascinetvisorcapon_m01_Brunswig</Cell><Cell>Brunswick's bascinet</Cell><Cell>布伦瑞克的头盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_battle_arrow</Cell><Cell>Battle arrow</Cell><Cell>军用箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_battle_bolt</Cell><Cell>Battle bolt</Cell><Cell>军用弩箭</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_beefDried</Cell><Cell>Dried beef</Cell><Cell>牛肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_beefTenderloinDried</Cell><Cell>Dried beef tenderloin</Cell><Cell>牛里脊肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_boarMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried boar meat</Cell><Cell>野猪肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_boarRumpDried</Cell><Cell>Dried boar rump</Cell><Cell>野猪臀肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_boarTenderloinDried</Cell><Cell>Dried boar tenderloin</Cell><Cell>野猪里脊肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_boletusDried</Cell><Cell>Dried boletus</Cell><Cell>牛肝菌干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bolt_enh_precise</Cell><Cell>Sharpshooter's bolt</Cell><Cell>神射手弩箭</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootsankle01_m00</Cell><Cell>Work boots</Cell><Cell>工作靴</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootsankle01_m02</Cell><Cell>Work boots</Cell><Cell>工作靴</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootsankle01_m03</Cell><Cell>Working boots</Cell><Cell>工作靴</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootsanklecourtier</Cell><Cell>Courtier's boots</Cell><Cell>宫廷靴子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootsanklepick</Cell><Cell>Pickpocket's shoes</Cell><Cell>扒手的鞋子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootsanklesilent</Cell><Cell>Quiet boots</Cell><Cell>静音靴</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootskneesoft</Cell><Cell>Soft boots</Cell><Cell>柔软靴</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bootskneethief</Cell><Cell>Thief's shoes</Cell><Cell>盗贼靴</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bow_c_b</Cell><Cell>Ash hunting bow</Cell><Cell>白蜡木猎弓</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_bow_d_a</Cell><Cell>Ash longbow</Cell><Cell>白蜡木长弓</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brigandine02_blk</Cell><Cell>Bandit's brigandine - dark</Cell><Cell>强盗的板甲衣 - 暗色</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brigandine03_raub</Cell><Cell>Robber baron's brigandine</Cell><Cell>强盗贵族的板甲衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brigandine05_blk</Cell><Cell>Milanese brigandine - dark</Cell><Cell>米兰板甲衣 - 暗色</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brigandinearm01_m01</Cell><Cell>Plain laminar sleeves</Cell><Cell>普通层叠式护手</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brigandinearm02_m01</Cell><Cell>Laminar sleeves with rondels</Cell><Cell>圆板层叠式护手</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brigandinearm03_m01</Cell><Cell>Reinforced tempered sleeves</Cell><Cell>强化淬火护手</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brigandinearm06_m01</Cell><Cell>Noble laminar sleeves</Cell><Cell>贵族层叠式护手</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brooch_brass_inscription</Cell><Cell>Brass brooch with lettering</Cell><Cell>带有字母铭文的黄铜别针</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brooch_golden_erb</Cell><Cell>Golden heraldic brooch</Cell><Cell>金色纹章别针</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brooch_golden_letter</Cell><Cell>Golden initial brooch</Cell><Cell>金色字母别针</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brooch_silver</Cell><Cell>Silver brooch</Cell><Cell>银别针</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_brooch_silver_enamel</Cell><Cell>Silver brooch enamelled</Cell><Cell>搪瓷银别针</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_budovaniLazni_miparti</Cell><Cell>Ripped hose</Cell><Cell>破烂衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_caftan05_blk</Cell><Cell>Quilted caftan - black</Cell><Cell>黑色绗缝长袍</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cap12_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Vagrant's hat</Cell><Cell>流浪者的帽子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cap19_pick</Cell><Cell>Pickpocket's hat</Cell><Cell>扒手的帽子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cap21_thief</Cell><Cell>Thief's cap</Cell><Cell>盗贼帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cap22_m01</Cell><Cell>Chaperon with brooch</Cell><Cell>带别针的风帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cap33_courtier</Cell><Cell>Courtier's hat</Cell><Cell>宫廷帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_caparison02_m01</Cell><Cell>Executioner's caparison simple</Cell><Cell>刽子手简易马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_caparison_pros</Cell><Cell>Skalitz caparison</Cell><Cell>斯卡里茨的马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cheesecake</Cell><Cell>Quark kolach</Cell><Cell>奶酪圆面包</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cheeseQuarterDried</Cell><Cell>Dried cheese</Cell><Cell>奶酪干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_chickenDried</Cell><Cell>Dried chicken</Cell><Cell>鸡肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cisnicky_katata</Cell><Cell>The hose of a royal waiter</Cell><Cell>皇家侍者衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coat02_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Vagrant's coat</Cell><Cell>流浪者的外套</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coat05_thieg</Cell><Cell>Thief's coat</Cell><Cell>盗贼外衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coat08_courtier</Cell><Cell>Courtier's coat</Cell><Cell>宫廷外衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coat_huntsman</Cell><Cell>Nimrod's coat</Cell><Cell>尼姆罗德的外套</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coiflarge01_blk</Cell><Cell>Broad battle coif - black</Cell><Cell>黑色宽战斗头巾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coiflarge02_blk</Cell><Cell>Padded hood - black</Cell><Cell>黑色衬垫兜帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coifmail01_m01</Cell><Cell>Mail coif</Cell><Cell>链甲头巾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coifmail02_m01</Cell><Cell>Mail hood with a coat of arms</Cell><Cell>印有纹章的链甲头巾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coifsmall01_blk</Cell><Cell>Coif - black</Cell><Cell>黑色头巾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coifsmall02_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Quilted vagrant's cap</Cell><Cell>流浪者的绗缝帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_coifsmall03_blk</Cell><Cell>Padded coif - black</Cell><Cell>黑色衬垫头巾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cracklings</Cell><Cell>Cracklings</Cell><Cell>烤脆猪皮</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cuirass01_blk</Cell><Cell>Smooth cuirass - blackened</Cell><Cell>黑色光滑胸甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cuirass04_blk</Cell><Cell>Mended cuirass - dark</Cell><Cell>暗色补丁胸甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cuirass05_blk</Cell><Cell>Riding cuirass - blackened</Cell><Cell>涂黑骑兵胸甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cuirass06_blk</Cell><Cell>Rusted plate - dark</Cell><Cell>暗色的生锈板甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_cuman_bow_a_b</Cell><Cell>Cuman folded bow</Cell><Cell>库曼人的层压弓</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_deerFlank</Cell><Cell>Deer ribs</Cell><Cell>鹿排</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_deerFlankDried</Cell><Cell>Dried deer ribs</Cell><Cell>鹿排干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_deerMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried venison</Cell><Cell>鹿肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_deerRumpDried</Cell><Cell>Dried deer rump</Cell><Cell>鹿臀肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_dieFavourable</Cell><Cell>Favourable die</Cell><Cell>好运骰子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_dlc2cernokneznik_bookSecretText</Cell><Cell>Alchemical book</Cell><Cell>炼金术书</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_dlc2cernokneznik_letterCipher</Cell><Cell>Strange riddle</Cell><Cell>奇怪的谜语</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_dlc2MalirZlodejske_colors</Cell><Cell>Sculptor's chisels</Cell><Cell>雕刻师的凿子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_dogMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried dog meat</Cell><Cell>狗肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_egg</Cell><Cell>Egg</Cell><Cell>蛋</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gambesonlong01_blk</Cell><Cell>Long gambeson - black</Cell><Cell>黑色长软甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gambesonlong03_blk</Cell><Cell>Long pourpoint - black</Cell><Cell>黑色长棉衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gambesonshort02_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Vagrant's gambeson</Cell><Cell>流浪者的软甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gambesonshort03_blk</Cell><Cell>Short pourpoint - black</Cell><Cell>黑色短棉衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gambesonshort04_m01</Cell><Cell>Short aketon</Cell><Cell>短衬甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gambesonshort04_m02</Cell><Cell>Short aketon</Cell><Cell>短衬甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gambesonshort04_raub</Cell><Cell>Robber baron's aketon</Cell><Cell>盗贼男爵的衬甲</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gloves01_pick</Cell><Cell>Pickpocket's gloves</Cell><Cell>扒手的手套</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gloves05_thief</Cell><Cell>Thief's gloves</Cell><Cell>盗贼手套</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_gloves06_mlegate</Cell><Cell>Legate's gloves</Cell><Cell>特使的手套</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_handgonneFancy01</Cell><Cell>Master's handgonne</Cell><Cell>大师的手铳</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_handgonneNormal01</Cell><Cell>Pistole</Cell><Cell>手铳</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_herb_dried_comfrey</Cell><Cell>Dried comfrey</Cell><Cell>干燥的紫草</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_herb_dried_hypericum</Cell><Cell>Dried St. John's wort</Cell><Cell>干燥的圣约翰草</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_herb_dried_mint</Cell><Cell>Dried mint</Cell><Cell>干燥的薄荷</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_herb_dried_nightshade</Cell><Cell>Dried henbane</Cell><Cell>干燥的天仙子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_herb_dried_poppy</Cell><Cell>Dried poppy</Cell><Cell>干燥的罂粟</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_herb_dried_urticaria</Cell><Cell>Dried nettle</Cell><Cell>干燥的荨麻</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_herb_elderberry</Cell><Cell>Elderberry leaves</Cell><Cell>接骨木莓叶</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hood01_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Wanderer's hood</Cell><Cell>流浪者的兜帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hood02_court</Cell><Cell>Courtier's hood</Cell><Cell>宫廷兜帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hood07_pick</Cell><Cell>Pickpocket's hood</Cell><Cell>扒手的兜帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hood09_thief</Cell><Cell>Thief's hood</Cell><Cell>盗贼兜帽</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hookgunFancy01</Cell><Cell>Marksman's hook gun</Cell><Cell>射手的钩枪</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hookgunNormal01</Cell><Cell>Hook gun</Cell><Cell>钩枪</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_horseMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried horse meat</Cell><Cell>马肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoined01_m01</Cell><Cell>Hose joined</Cell><Cell>拼接衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoined01_mdrowner</Cell><Cell>Drowner's hose</Cell><Cell>溺水者的衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoined01_thief</Cell><Cell>Thief's hose</Cell><Cell>盗贼衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoined02_courtier</Cell><Cell>Courtier's hose</Cell><Cell>宫廷衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoined02_m02</Cell><Cell>Tied jester's hose</Cell><Cell>小丑衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoined02_mlegate</Cell><Cell>Legate's hose</Cell><Cell>特使的衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoined_twitch</Cell><Cell>Cutpurse's hose</Cell><Cell>盗贼衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hosejoine_hunter</Cell><Cell>Master huntsman's hose</Cell><Cell>狩猎大师衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hoseloose01_m01</Cell><Cell>Loose hose</Cell><Cell>宽松衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hoseseparate01_m01</Cell><Cell>Simple hose</Cell><Cell>简易衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hoseseparate01_m02</Cell><Cell>Plain troubadours' hose</Cell><Cell>简朴诗人衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hoseseparate01_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Vagrant's hose</Cell><Cell>流浪者衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hoseseparate04_m01</Cell><Cell>Beggar's hose</Cell><Cell>乞丐衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hoseseparate04_pick</Cell><Cell>Pickpocket's hose</Cell><Cell>扒手衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_hoseseparate05_m01</Cell><Cell>Miner hose</Cell><Cell>矿工衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_huntingSwordFalchion</Cell><Cell>Falchion</Cell><Cell>弯刃砍刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_huntingSwordGuard</Cell><Cell>Burgher's hunting sword</Cell><Cell>市民猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_huntingSwordMussle</Cell><Cell>Shell hunting sword</Cell><Cell>鹿角猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_huntingSwordSword</Cell><Cell>Noble's hunting sword</Cell><Cell>贵族猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kettlehat01_blk</Cell><Cell>Kettle hat - dark</Cell><Cell>暗色水壶盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kettlehat04_blk</Cell><Cell>Beaked kettle hat - dark</Cell><Cell>暗色具喙水壶盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kettlehat05_blk</Cell><Cell>Kettle hat - dark</Cell><Cell>暗色水壶盔</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_keyring</Cell><Cell>Bunch of keys</Cell><Cell>钥匙串</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_klasterniTajemstvi_casperWine_bad</Cell><Cell>Wine from Casper's vineyard</Cell><Cell>卡斯帕葡萄园的葡萄酒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kovaniKatuvSleh_fakeGamblerNoose</Cell><Cell>Hanged man's noose</Cell><Cell>吊死者的绞索</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kovaniKatuvSleh_magicHorseshoe</Cell><Cell>Ghostly horseshoe</Cell><Cell>幽灵马蹄铁</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kovaniKovarskaSoutez_huntingKnifeApprentice</Cell><Cell>Competition hunting sword</Cell><Cell>竞赛用猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kovarskeZakazky_magdalenaAxe</Cell><Cell>Magdalena's axe</Cell><Cell>马格达琳的斧头</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kovarskeZakazky_magdalenaAxe_broken</Cell><Cell>Magdalena's broken axe</Cell><Cell>马格达琳的损坏的斧头</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_kovarskeZakazky_magdalenaBrokenAxe</Cell><Cell>Magdalena's broken axe</Cell><Cell>马格达琳的损坏的斧头</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legsbrigandine01_m01</Cell><Cell>Old brigandine legs</Cell><Cell>老式板甲护腿</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded01_blk</Cell><Cell>Quilted hose - dark</Cell><Cell>暗色绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded01_m01</Cell><Cell>Quilted hose</Cell><Cell>绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded02_m01</Cell><Cell>Old quilted hose</Cell><Cell>老旧绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded02_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Vagrant's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>流浪者绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m02</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m03</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m04</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m05</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m06</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m07</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m08</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m09</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m10</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded03_m11</Cell><Cell>Noble's quilted hose</Cell><Cell>贵族绗缝衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legspadded_godwin</Cell><Cell>Mended padded leggings</Cell><Cell>修补过的长衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_legsplate03_blk</Cell><Cell>Noble's plate legs - dark</Cell><Cell>黑色贵族板甲护腿</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_lepiotaDried</Cell><Cell>Dried lepiota</Cell><Cell>环柄菇干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_longswordCommon</Cell><Cell>Common longsword</Cell><Cell>制式长剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_loot_copperPlate</Cell><Cell>Copper plate</Cell><Cell>铜盘</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_loot_goldenChalice</Cell><Cell>Golden chalice</Cell><Cell>金圣餐杯</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_loot_silverChalice</Cell><Cell>Silver chalice</Cell><Cell>银圣餐杯</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_loot_stone</Cell><Cell>Rock</Cell><Cell>石头</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_lovVlku_brokenArrow</Cell><Cell>Bloodied broken arrow</Cell><Cell>血迹斑斑的断箭矢</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_mace01</Cell><Cell>Light mace</Cell><Cell>轻型钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_mace02</Cell><Cell>Common mace</Cell><Cell>普通钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_mace03</Cell><Cell>Flanged mace</Cell><Cell>法兰钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_mace04</Cell><Cell>Ornate mace</Cell><Cell>华丽的钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maceBailiff</Cell><Cell>Bailiff's mace</Cell><Cell>执行官的钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maceClubSpiked</Cell><Cell>Reinforced bludgeon</Cell><Cell>强化棍棒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maceDagger</Cell><Cell>Dagger mace</Cell><Cell>匕首钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maceHetman</Cell><Cell>Captain's mace</Cell><Cell>首领的钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maceZizka</Cell><Cell>Zizka's mace</Cell><Cell>杰式卡的钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maillong01_m01</Cell><Cell>Hauberk long</Cell><Cell>长链甲衫</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maillong02_m01</Cell><Cell>Saxon hauberk</Cell><Cell>萨克森链甲衫</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_mailshort01_m01</Cell><Cell>Short chainmail</Cell><Cell>短链甲衫</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_mailshort02_m01</Cell><Cell>Italian hauberk</Cell><Cell>意大利链甲衫</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_malir_die_b</Cell><Cell>Painter's die B</Cell><Cell>画家的骰子B</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_malir_die_g</Cell><Cell>Painter's die G</Cell><Cell>画家的骰子G</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_malir_die_r</Cell><Cell>Painter's die R</Cell><Cell>画家的骰子R</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maliruvLek_freshwaterPearl</Cell><Cell>Freshwater pearl</Cell><Cell>淡水珍珠</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maliruvLek_mandrakeRoot</Cell><Cell>Mandrake root</Cell><Cell>曼德拉草根</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maliruvLek_potion</Cell><Cell>Weak Mandrake decoction</Cell><Cell>弱效曼德拉草药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maliruvLek_potion_best</Cell><Cell>Henry's mandrake decoction</Cell><Cell>亨利的曼德拉草药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maliruvLek_potion_high</Cell><Cell>Strong Mandrake Decoction</Cell><Cell>强效曼德拉草药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_maliruvLek_potion_medium</Cell><Cell>Mandrake decoction</Cell><Cell>曼德拉草药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_malirZlodejske_sketch</Cell><Cell>Damian's drawing</Cell><Cell>达米安的画</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_necklace_scapular_letter</Cell><Cell>Scapular with insignia</Cell><Cell>饰有徽章的肩带</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_necklace_scapular_saint</Cell><Cell>Scapular with saint</Cell><Cell>圣人肩带</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_necklace_scapular_window</Cell><Cell>Scapular with aperture</Cell><Cell>带孔肩带</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_noblecaparison03_m01</Cell><Cell>Executioner's caparison decorated</Cell><Cell>刽子手装饰马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_noblecaparison03_mLeipa</Cell><Cell>Executioner’s caparison in colours of Leipa</Cell><Cell>莱佩家族配色的刽子手马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_noblecaparison04_m01</Cell><Cell>Executioner's caparison with harness</Cell><Cell>带马具的刽子手马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_noblecaparison07_m01</Cell><Cell>Executioner’s caparison with harness</Cell><Cell>带马具的刽子手马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_noblecaparison_twitch</Cell><Cell>Warhorse tournament caparison</Cell><Cell>战马比武用马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_paddedcaparison02_m01</Cell><Cell>Executioner's caparison quilted</Cell><Cell>刽子手绗缝马衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_pearCooked</Cell><Cell>Cooked pear</Cell><Cell>煮熟的梨子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_pearDried</Cell><Cell>Dried pear</Cell><Cell>梨子干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_perchDried</Cell><Cell>Dried perch</Cell><Cell>鲈鱼干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_perfume_longWeak_best</Cell><Cell>Henry's Mintha perfume</Cell><Cell>亨利的薄荷香水</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_perfume_longWeak_high</Cell><Cell>Strong Mintha Perfume Effect</Cell><Cell>强效薄荷香水效果</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_perfume_shortStrong</Cell><Cell>Weak Lion perfume   </Cell><Cell>弱效雄狮香水</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_perfume_shortStrong_best</Cell><Cell>Henry's Lion perfume</Cell><Cell>亨利的雄狮香水</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_perfume_shortStrong_high</Cell><Cell>Strong Lion Perfume</Cell><Cell>强效雄狮香水</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_perfume_shortStrong_medium</Cell><Cell>Lion perfume</Cell><Cell>雄狮香水</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_pigMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried pork</Cell><Cell>猪肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_pigTenderloinDried</Cell><Cell>Dried pork tenderloin</Cell><Cell>猪里脊肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_placeholder_maceHeavy</Cell><Cell>Heavy mace</Cell><Cell>重型钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_poi_pokladPodTroskami_oldSpirit</Cell><Cell>Ancient moonshine</Cell><Cell>陈年私酒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_poi_vodnik_vodnikovyKalhoty</Cell><Cell>Water goblin's hose</Cell><Cell>水妖衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_poi_vyplataDrevorubcu_key</Cell><Cell>Nest key</Cell><Cell>鸟窝钥匙</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_pomatenec_brokenSword</Cell><Cell>Madman's broken sword</Cell><Cell>疯子的断剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_pomatenec_longsword</Cell><Cell>Madman's longsword</Cell><Cell>疯子的长剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_poppyseedcake</Cell><Cell>Poppy seed kolach</Cell><Cell>罂粟籽圆面包</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_poPytlackeStezce_youngWhiteDeerHide</Cell><Cell>White roebuck's hide</Cell><Cell>白狍子皮</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_potion_chamomile_decoction</Cell><Cell>Weak Chamomile Brew</Cell><Cell>弱效甘菊药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_potion_chamomile_decoction_best</Cell><Cell>Henry's Chamomile Brew</Cell><Cell>亨利的甘菊药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_potion_chamomile_decoction_high</Cell><Cell>Strong Chamomile Brew</Cell><Cell>强效甘菊药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_potion_chamomile_decoction_medium</Cell><Cell>Chamomile Brew</Cell><Cell>甘菊药剂</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_poustevnik_oldShoddyCloakOfAmbroz</Cell><Cell>Crusader cloak</Cell><Cell>红星十字骑士团斗篷</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_pracharna_concubineDress</Cell><Cell>Tyrol brocade cotehardie</Cell><Cell>蒂罗尔锦缎贴身长裙</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_rabbitMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried hare meat</Cell><Cell>兔肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_axebattle01</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Bearded axe</Cell><Cell>胡须斧图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_axebattle03</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Horseman's pick</Cell><Cell>骑兵镐斧图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_bardPotion</Cell><Cell>Recipe for Fox potion</Cell><Cell>狐狸药剂配方</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_chamomileDecoction</Cell><Cell>Recipe for Chamomile decoction</Cell><Cell>甘菊药剂配方</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_hoochPotion</Cell><Cell>Moonshine recipe</Cell><Cell>私酒配方</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_huntingSwordBasic</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Hunting sword</Cell><Cell>猎刀图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_huntingswordfalchion</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Falchion</Cell><Cell>弯刃砍刀图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_huntingswordmussle</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Shell hunting sword</Cell><Cell>鹿角猎刀图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_huntingSwordSword</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Noble's hunting sword</Cell><Cell>贵族猎刀图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_longswordcommon</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Common longsword</Cell><Cell>制式长剑图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_sabrecommon</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Common sabre</Cell><Cell>制式军刀图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_shortswordcleaver</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Homemade hunting sword</Cell><Cell>土制猎刀图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_shortswordcommon</Cell><Cell>Sketch – Military sword</Cell><Cell>武装剑图纸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_shotScatter</Cell><Cell>Recipe for Scattershot gunpowder</Cell><Cell>霰弹火药配方</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_recipe_sleepPotion</Cell><Cell>Recipe for Lullaby potion </Cell><Cell>“安眠”毒药的配方</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_roeDeerLoinDried</Cell><Cell>Dried roe deer loin</Cell><Cell>狍子里脊肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_roeDeerMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried roe deer meat</Cell><Cell>狍子肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_sabrecommon</Cell><Cell>Common sabre</Cell><Cell>制式军刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_salamiDried</Cell><Cell>Dried salami</Cell><Cell>萨拉米香肠干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_scatterShot</Cell><Cell>Scattershot</Cell><Cell>霰弹</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_sedmStatecnych2_pillory</Cell><Cell>Pillory key</Cell><Cell>颈手枷钥匙</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_sermiryHuntingSwordJimram</Cell><Cell>Emmeram's hunting sword</Cell><Cell>艾默拉姆的猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shieldPavise_bergov</Cell><Cell>Trosky pavese</Cell><Cell>特罗斯基骑兵帕维斯巨盾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shieldPavise_half</Cell><Cell>Halved pavese</Cell><Cell>双色骑兵帕维斯巨盾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shieldPavise_hungary</Cell><Cell>Hungarian pavese</Cell><Cell>匈牙利骑兵帕维斯巨盾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shieldPavise_painted</Cell><Cell>Painted pavese</Cell><Cell>涂绘骑兵帕维斯巨盾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shieldPavise_prague</Cell><Cell>City of Prague pavese</Cell><Cell>布拉格城骑兵帕维斯巨盾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shieldPavise_suchdol</Cell><Cell>Suchdol pavese</Cell><Cell>苏赫多尔骑兵帕维斯巨盾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shoes03_mlegate</Cell><Cell>Legate's shoes</Cell><Cell>特使的鞋子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shoes03_thief</Cell><Cell>Thief's shoes</Cell><Cell>盗贼靴</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shoes04_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Vagrant's shoes</Cell><Cell>流浪者的鞋子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shortSwordBasilard</Cell><Cell>Basilard</Cell><Cell>巴塞拉德短剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shortswordBroad</Cell><Cell>Broadsword</Cell><Cell>阔剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shortswordcleaver</Cell><Cell>Homemade hunting sword</Cell><Cell>土制猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_shortswordCommon</Cell><Cell>Military sword</Cell><Cell>武装剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_skin_roe</Cell><Cell>Roe-deer hide</Cell><Cell>狍子皮</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_sleepingPoison</Cell><Cell>Weak Lullaby potion</Cell><Cell>弱效“安眠”毒药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_sleepingPoison_best</Cell><Cell>Henry's Lullaby potion</Cell><Cell>亨利的“安眠”毒药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_sleepingPoison_high</Cell><Cell>Strong Lullaby potion</Cell><Cell>强效“安眠”毒药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_sleepingPoison_medium</Cell><Cell>Lullaby potion</Cell><Cell>“安眠”毒药</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_spirits</Cell><Cell>Schnapps</Cell><Cell>烈酒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_stealthMiseZaJindru_samHuntingKnife</Cell><Cell>Samuel's hunting sword</Cell><Cell>塞缪尔的猎刀</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_strasidlo_scaryThings</Cell><Cell>Spooking equipment</Cell><Cell>吓人用装备</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_svatba_longswordTourname</Cell><Cell>Tournament practice sword</Cell><Cell>比武用练习剑</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_taboryLapkuTrosecko_plesnivecMace</Cell><Cell>Canker's mace</Cell><Cell>“溃疡”的钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_TorsoPainter_m01</Cell><Cell>Painter Vojtiech's pourpoint</Cell><Cell>画家沃伊捷赫的束腰短上衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_tournament_maceHerald</Cell><Cell>Tournament mace</Cell><Cell>比武用钉头锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_troutDried</Cell><Cell>Dried trout</Cell><Cell>鳟鱼干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_truhlari_handplane</Cell><Cell>Chrudosh's chisel</Cell><Cell>克鲁多什的凿子</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_truhlari_motherMaryStatue</Cell><Cell>Mother Mary statuette</Cell><Cell>圣母玛利亚雕像</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_tuniclong01_pick</Cell><Cell>Pickpocket's tunic</Cell><Cell>扒手的外衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_tuniclong04_vagrant</Cell><Cell>Wanderer's tunic</Cell><Cell>流浪者长袍</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_tunicshort04_courtier</Cell><Cell>Courtier's pourpoint.</Cell><Cell>宫廷棉衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_tunicshort08_thief</Cell><Cell>Thief's tunic</Cell><Cell>盗贼束腰外衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_tunicshortlegate_m01</Cell><Cell>Legate's tunic</Cell><Cell>特使的束腰外衣</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_walnutcake</Cell><Cell>Walnut kolach</Cell><Cell>核桃圆面包</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_warhammer02</Cell><Cell>Rider's war hammer</Cell><Cell>骑兵战锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_warhammer03_trollslayer</Cell><Cell>Trollbane hammer</Cell><Cell>巨魔克星战锤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_warhammer03_trollslayer_broken</Cell><Cell>Trollbane hammer stub</Cell><Cell>巨魔克星战锤的残骸</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_warhammerRaven</Cell><Cell>Raven's beak</Cell><Cell>渡鸦之喙</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_wolfMeatDried</Cell><Cell>Dried wolf meat</Cell><Cell>狼肉干</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_zlatyMedailon_vojtasScarf</Cell><Cell>Voyta's scarf</Cell><Cell>沃伊塔的围巾</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_ztracenaCest_jezeksSpurs</Cell><Cell>Jezhek's spurs</Cell><Cell>杰泽克的马刺</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_ztratyANalezy_booze</Cell><Cell>Meaningless moonshine</Cell><Cell>无意义的私酒</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_nm_ztratyANalezy_hose</Cell><Cell>Lost hose</Cell><Cell>丢失的衬裤</Cell></Row>
<Row><Cell>ui_null_silver</Cell><Cell>Use to cancel the effect of your opponent's Silver badge in the game.</Cell><Cell>使用后可取消对手的银制徽章效果。</Cell></Row>
</Table>
